Here they are for one and all. The movements are about to come. Come on and sit down here with me, therefore you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements,
so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land, you can fly just like a bird, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la The It's spring again in Mumen Valley, and after their long winter hibernation, everyone
is awake and enjoying the sunshine of the flowers. Everyone that is except for Mumin was in bed with a terrible cold.
Ha, ha, ha.
Oh, dear, Mumin, that's a nasty cough.
My throat is very sore.
This will help soothe it.
It's one of grandma's best potions.
Yeah, it's hard.
Never mind.
Nice tasting medicines don't always work as well.
I wanted to go out, it's spring.
I know dear, but you'd catch pneumonia or something.
Oh, Mama.
Mm-hmm.
Does anyone know why Snuffkin hasn't come back yet?
No.
Perhaps Spring came earlier this year and he wasn't ready.
Snuffkin had always come back to Moonomin Valley on the very first day of spring.
But not this year.
Snuffkin.
I'm Moomin Papa. Is Moomin any better? No, I I'm afraid not he's still got a nasty
car I go up and see him no you'd better not you might catch it
Papa's right sniffing you know how poorly you get when you're ill it's best not
to take the risk I should think he'll be up and about before very long. Yes, it's better to be safe than sorry.
Moments shouldn't have gone out in the winter, should he, Mama?
No, but he couldn't go back to sleep.
Snow would have that effect on anyone.
I knew little Mai was out in the cold with him, and look at her.
She seems healthy enough.
I'll take these flowers to moon later.. Little mice too small to catch a cold.
This is boring! I can't believe that movement sick.
And Snuffkin's not back either.
I sure wonder what's happened to him.
I bet you moment gets better as soon as Snuffkin arrives in moment valley.
I'm not going to be able to do that.
I'm not going to be able to do that. I sure wonder what's happened to him.
I bet you, Momen gets better as soon as Snuffkin arrives in Momen Valley.
He's never been this late coming back before.
Perhaps he's got fed up with you guys.
Impossible. He's very fond of me.
He's told me so lots of times.
He likes Momen too, of course.
He might have been captured by a highwayman.
Let's go and look for him.
The highwayman?
First napkin, silly.
He's got to come back so a moment will get better.
We must find him.
But where do we look, Snork Maiden?
In the south.
It's a big place. He could be anywhere.
Well, I don't care how big it is. I'm going anyway.
You're being silly.
No, I'm not. I don't think your brother will like it'm going anyway. You're being silly. No, I'm not.
I don't think your brother will like it.
In fact, I know he won't.
Have you gone completely bananas?
No, I haven't.
And you'll just have to make your own muffins.
There's more to food than muffins.
I was speaking figuratively.
Anyway, I'm going to your brother
and nothing you can do or say will stop me.
It's for Mumin.
That's a sort of hair-brain scheme that could only have been dreamed up by you.
What good will it do? You don't even know where he is.
It is not. Mumin is pining for Snuffkin.
Rubbish. Men don't pine for their friends.
If he isn't back yet, then he isn't coming.
And if he isn't going to come, what's the point of looking for him?
You won't find him anyway.
He will come when he knows that Moon is sick.
Black males just like a sister.
Something done for love could never be black male.
Oh no, you're not going and that's fine.
Look, why don't you and little Mai go by yourselves?
Oh, well I didn't really make a definite decision.
I just sort of said that I might come along.
But if Snort Maiden isn't going, then there
doesn't seem any point, does there?
And I'm not going because I think it's stupid and hair
brain, too.
Snuff can come back soon.
Not Snort Maiden.
What do you say to that?
Oh.
How is Momen feeling any better? He's asleep now, but the cough doesn't seem so bad. And his temperature? Still quite high. Hmm. I'm not going to be able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it.
I'm not going to be able to do it.
I'm not going to be able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it. Snark in! Snark in! Snark in!
Snark in!
Am I pleased to see you, Moonman?
You look like you needed a lift.
This magic cloud must be one of those we got from the Hobgoblins top hat.
That's right. I had one of them away.
What a good idea, Moomin. You are clever.
Well, it was so much fun the last time, wasn't it?
Hi, Moomin! Hi!
Oh, look, Snuffkin. I'm not going to do it. I'm not going to do it.
I'm not going to do it.
I'm not going to do it. I'm not going to do it. Oh. Not just a dream.
Snuff can.
Oh.
You look blousy, moment.
Oh, thanks, stinky. You'd better keep away.
There's no need bugs and things like that. Stay away from me.
They're probably frightened of someone so healthy.
Mama isn't letting anyone in here.
It's very dull.
You followed a bed or something?
Yes, I did.
I know.
You were dreaming, weren't you?
Unfortunately, yes.
I know how you feel.
I have that dream a lot.
Oh.
You stand on a windowsill getting ready to break the glass
and inside there's diamonds.
And then moment you fall.
It's not the same dream at all, stinky.
Snuffkin hasn't come back yet.
Have you heard anything from him? It's very late.
Ah, Snuffkin, um.
Huh, you know something, don't you?
All I know is that he went away as usual last autumn and hasn't come back yet.
And then...
Yes, what?
Snark Maiden wanted to go looking for him
because she thinks that if Snork Kid comes back
he won't be sick anymore, but Snork with a letter.
Snork Maiden?
He snorked Maiden way!
Snork me!
You're not serious, are you? I feel perfectly alright. You look like that's warmed up if you ask me. Thanks a lot.
Now Stinky, tell me which way does Snuff can normally travel south?
Hey, are you going looking for him?
Yes, it's not really spring in Moomin Valley if he's not around.
It's just not right somehow.
Okay, you're all as mad as each other.
But you'll help me?
I'll help you. Yes, it's not really spring in Moomin Valley if he's not around. It's just not right somehow.
Okay, you're all as mad as each other.
But you'll help me. I've got to try and find him, Stinky.
Yes, all right, but don't tell your parents I helped you.
Don't worry, I'm fine. Here's your lunch, movement. How are you feeling?
Movement?
Papa, come here quickly.
Hmm.
Oh, sorry, stinky. Are you okay?
Oh, I'm fine.
Here's your lunch, movement. How are you feeling?
Movement? Papa, Mummenn. How are you feeling? Mummenn?
Papa, come here quickly!
Mmm.
Oh, Papa, Mummenn's gone. He's not in his bed.
Not in his bed? Are you sure, Mama?
Of course I am. His room is empty and there's no sign of him.
Perhaps he's in one of the other rooms. Don't worry mama, I'll find him.
You're home, Mumin! Mumin!
Hi, you're Mumin, Papa!
Oh, little Mai!
What's wrong? You look worried!
A moment's gone off somewhere.
I expect you must have gone to look for Snaftkin.
Snaftkin?
Well, you know how crazy Moomin is about him.
Bits stupid if you ask me.
But he's not well. He's got a fever. I'm sure this is the right way?
Of course I'm sure I live in this forest, don't I?
Why don't we miss each other somewhere?
Well if you think you might, don't go there and it's up to you.
But I've got to...
Moments!
Oh, snort me, little.
Huh?
Where are you taking him, Stinky?
You can see he's not well.
I'm not taking him. He insisted on going. I came to look after him.
Is that really right, Boomin?
Yes, I wanted to find Snuffkin, so he'd come back.
Well, I was going to find him for you. Little mine's sniff were coming too, but they chickened out so I came on my own.
What did Snork say about that? I bet he wasn't happy.
Oh, he made a big fuss and I just let him.
So you just walked out and came on your own?
Brothers, always think they can tell you what to do.
I just ignore him.
Did you tell your parents where you were?
Ah, no.
Did you put him up to this stinky? It's just a sort of thing you do.
No, I did not.
That's true, Snork Maiden.
I don't know how you did it stinky, but I know you and I know you're to blame and I don't think I won't find out.
That's not fair, Snark Maiden. It was nothing to do with me at all.
Oh, he's right, Snark Maiden. He didn't want to show me the way, but I made him.
I'm taking you home.
Oh, but Snark Maiden. Look.
No, buts. You're sick and you should be in bed and your parents must be very worried.
Look!
Moving!
It's Papa, it isn't that snorke behind him.
Yes it is.
Oh, it's time I wasn't here.
I'm glad you hadn't gone too far, Moomer. I might never have found you.
I'm very sorry, Papa.
I have a feeling you're behind this stinky come on quickly out with it.
Why doesn't anyone believe me it was moments I'd be I swear it was.
It was Papa I wanted to find snuffkin.
Are you alright moment?
Snork me.
Here we go again.
Snork me what are you doing here I thought I told you not to go on this silly jump.
Well, I didn't say I wouldn't.
Did I?
Listen to me, Snark.
Oh, you're looking guilty, stinky.
How did you persuade her to disobey me?
See, I told you.
You stay nice and warm in bed,
and I'll mix them of grandma's potion with honey for you.
You'll have to be better soon because I have a feeling Snuffkin's on his way.
My wish Snuffkin would hurry up then we could all get back to normal at last.
My sentiment's exactly.
So where is snuffkin well he's on his way back to woman valley but he's had a
very long walk and is getting very tired now Poor Snuffkin. He's had a terrible cold as well. This feeling rather weak. Hello, I know you don't I?
Oh yes, your snuffkin!
Isn't that water still a little cold for that? You'd better come by the fire and keep warm or you'll catch cold. This is nice!
Just think I'll be the one that's set by Snuffkin's fire.
And he told me to keep warm and that catch cold. Just Nick, I'll be the one that's that by Snuffkin's fire.
And he told me to keep warm and not catch cold.
Hmm, that's no big thing, little fella.
It's a pretty chilly night out here.
Oh, it is.
I've heard so many stories about you from everybody.
And each year I try to watch you go past, but I've never been brave enough to talk to you before.
Stories from everybody.
I don't know if I like that.
In fact, I'm sure I don't.
What's your name, little fella?
Oh, well, I haven't got one.
I'm so small that nobody's ever asked me before.
I've always wanted to have a name, you know?
And it was you who asked me.
And I've actually met you and sat next to it.
You're countifying.
Oh, it's so wonderful.
You don't know how happy it makes me meeting you like this.
Aw, come on. You do go on a bit old fella. You just get warm now.
Do you think Snuffkin? Oh, I don't know whether I should ask you. I don't want to offend you.
Oh, well, why not? Yes, I will.
Perhaps you'd be kind enough to it. I mean, would it be too much trouble for you to think of a name for me?
There. I've said it be too much trouble for you to think of a name for me? There. I've said it now.
Well choosing a name is important. I'd have to think carefully about that.
But it will be easy for you. You know everything!
Now listen to me. You can't look up to people too much if you want to be yourself. It's not right.
But Snuffkin, you're so clever. You can do anything, anything at all. I know you can.
I've always wanted to be free like you to do whatever I feel.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm talking too much. I want to listen to you too. All about your travels for a start.
I know you're on your way to the Moon Valley to see all your friends. The hedgehog told me the Moon
stayed out for most of the winter. Just waiting for you to come back.
Now, isn't that wonderful?
What?
I'd love to have someone that missed me so much
they were miserable until I came back.
You don't know how lucky you are that you're so special.
Well, perhaps I'm not going there.
I might have somewhere else to visit instead.
Oh, moment will be very sad if you don't go back.
Yes, but you've got to have time to be on your own as well.
Of course you have, and I've taken up too much of yours now.
Wait, I think I'll be off.
Okay, thanks.
Goodbye, Snuffkin. Good night, little fella. Hey, wait a minute. What about your name?
You remember it!
Well, what do you think of TD Wu, my friend?
Yes, TD Wu.
I'm not sure if you remember it.
I'm not sure if you remember it. I'm not sure if you remember it. What about your name? You remembered! Well, what do you think of TDW, my friend?
Yes, TDW.
It's nice and happy to start with, and then a little sadness.
TDW.
That's right. TDW.
TDW! TD-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-Woo! T-T-Woo! T-T-W anyone a name. Yeah! I think I'll build a house and then I can put up a real name plate that says
TDWOO!
Ah, good idea TDWOO. About what I said before.
Huh?
You know, not going back to Moomin Valley? Well I am. I've missed Moomin and all my friends.
Oh, I didn't take that seriously. You just got upset at something I said. I'm afraid
that happens a lot. I guess I talked too much.
Maybe you do.
I'll be going back to Moomin Valley a bit behind schedule, and this year's spring came along early too.
But I suppose it's better late than never, as they say.
Moomin will be happy. Say hello to everyone from TDW.
I will, and I'll tell them how it came about.
That's where you keep your harmonica, isn't it, Snuffkin?
It's really famous, you know?
I didn't realize that.
Do you know?
I've never ever heard any music.
Really?
What would you like me to play?
Anything.
Oh, I know.
What about women's favorite? Oh
That's Smokin! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! I'm not getting it. I'm not getting it. I'm not getting it.
I'm not getting it.
I'm not getting it. I'm not getting it. Now at last spring really has come to Woman Valley. Always happy and always at play The movements are having fun day after day
The movements
They love the laughter and they love the living
Believing and sharing and caring
And giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The moments I've been fun day after day, the movements The New Lands