Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
Therefore you are your TV.
They are the movements.
So, what's the problem?
The movement is not a problem. Here with me, here for you on your TV, they are the movements.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
There were the movements. There was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la- Bapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapapap Snort maiden is running as if the groke is chasing her. I don't think I've ever seen her run so fast.
I wonder what's the matter? Perhaps something terrible has happened. Mom! Mom!
Mom!
Mom! Mom! Mom! Mom! Mom! Now come down and tell us what's wrong. My brother's on the cliff and he's about to jump off.
What snorke?
Are you sure?
He says nothing will prevent him doing it.
Oh, please.
You must stop him, moment.
Did you say that you wanted me to help you with something snorke-made?
Yes, I want you to stop snorke jumping off the south side of the cliff.
Oh dear, I never thought he was the type.
He says it's a test flight.
Oh.
Now what?
A test flight, did you say?
Snorke made him.
Do you mean that he's finally finished building
his flying ship?
No, only the blueprint.
At least I think that's all.
He doesn't tell me.
Well, that's a start.
He built a small model of the flying ship's wings,
and they don't look strong enough to carry anyone.
And now he's going to try them out himself
to see if they'll work.
And I know they won't.
They'll break, you know.
Now, wait a minute, Snorkmaden.
Slow down and let me think.
He's made the wings from the blueprint of the flying ship.
Well, his plans are always very accurate.
Oh, Papa, you've got to stop him.
The south side, Papa.
Yes, I know. The highest and steepest one of all.
Oh, Mum and Papa, there must be something we can do.
Yes, I'm sure there is. Right.
Hurry, everybody. There's no time to lose. Come on.
Oh, thank you, Mum and Papa. I'm in power!
No! Go!
Go!
A snork? Wait! Wait! Please! Stop! Snork! Don't do it!
Why have you brought everybody here, Snork Maiden?
They've come to beg you not to do it!
You're too young and brilliant for such a tragic end!
Thank the booble we were in time!
As a matter of fact, you weren't.
Oh, really?
It looks very dangerous to me, Snork.
Well, it's not a tall moon in Papa.
I made these wings myself.
They're perfectly balanced.
Well, yes, I'm sure they are.
The blueprints are detailed and precise.
They're quite safe.
Tell me, Snork.
Why did you stop on the edge like that
after running down the slope?
I was measuring the right length from my approach run.
Don't do it, Snork. I don't want to lose my only brother.
Don't make such a fuss, Snork maiden.
Do you really think it's safe?
Of course it is. You don't see birds falling out of the sky, do you?
Well, at least do your test flight just above the ground so that if something happens to go wrong, you won't hurt yourself.
I've already done that from the roof of our house and it worked beautifully.
Did you see him?
No, I didn't see anything.
Of course you didn't. Do you think I let a wimpy little sister watch me?
What's that supposed to mean, snork?
Just that I don't want you sticking your big nose into my affairs all the time. I don't like it, and there's nothing to do with you.
Yours is just as big, and I don't want to lose you.
Don't go on about losing me.
Why not?
Come on now, you two.
Stop it.
Hey!
Oops!
That was close.
Snort, Maiden. I don't think your brother is going to be stopped.
Oh, dear, oh dear.
You're very brave, Snort.
Hmm, right. Here we go.
This time it'll be a perfect takeoff.
It's a long way. Oh look, isn't that Snorke in there?
Where? Where is he? Where is Snorke in?
You can't see him from there, Snorke. You'll have to come here.
Is it really Snuffkin?
Yes, I'm sure it is. Snuffkin!
Yeah!
Baby, here you.
No, I don't think so.
All right, here goes!
Good luck, Snork! Oh.
He's flying! I... Whoa!
We're here!
It's the snork! Mark!
Look at him flying! It's alright, Snorke, Ma maiden. Your brother's doing fine. Come and see.
He's done it! He's done it!
Whoa, I knew he could do it!
Will so did I, to be honest.
You, Snark!
Hello! You, Snark!
Hello!
Hey, hey, hey!
My baby's test flight is a great success! Yeah! Ha-ha!
Just as I thought he can't fly in wave at the same time!
Interesting!
That was mean stinky. If I could get him to wave with both arms,
he'd probably fall. Look, we don't want you here stinky. Why don't you just go away?
I can find lots to do with that machine. If you won't go away, I will.
Well, go on then, Snuffkin. What do I care what you do? Hmm, that would be perfect for robberies.
The wind seems to be taking him out to sea.
Why doesn't he turn around and come back?
Turning in that thing might not be so easy.
What? Do you mean he can't?
Well, don't worry Snuffkin, I mean, of course he can.
Oh, what's this I can't turn on?
Oh!
Oh, he's hit a tree.
Come on, hurry!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Hurry!
Is he dead? No, he's been knocked out. He looks dead to me anyway.
Where are they?
What's happened to the wings?
In the tree.
Ah, he won't want them anymore, so now I can have them.
Now, let me see. So did the test flight go all right? Will someone tell me what happened? Well, it was fine until the very end.
I'm sure that you only need a bit more practice.
Flying isn't the easiest thing to master, you know.
I expect so. Let's hope you don't run out of bandages, though.
Excuse me, snork.
Hmm?
Are you going to use the wings anymore?
I might not. Why?
Oh, well, I'll have them if you don't want them.
I want to fly in the sky too. It looks the most exciting thing I've ever seen.
Oh, please let me have them.
Well, it's not as simple as that moment. They need testing before the design is complete.
But I could do that snorkeh. I know I could do it. Please let me have them. Well I suppose I could do with some help. There's a lot to do fetching and
carrying mostly. You haven't said if I can have the wings or not yet snork. Yes you
can but on one condition. Anything. Well now the blueprints are finished and the
wings are more or less right. I'll need somewhere to build the ship and
somewhere to store all the materials
so they'll be dry and at hand.
Yes, you will snorke, I can see that.
It doesn't have to be much, just a roof will do,
or and walls, so that people can't spy on me
and steal my ideas.
I can do the building myself,
but I'll need some help, and when it's finished,
you can have the wings.
Great, I'd love to help you. I'd have done that anyway,
but now that I can have the wings, I'll work twice as hard.
You won't regret it, Snorke. I promise you, you won't.
Splendid, woman. That settled them.
Perhaps we can get more help. I'm sure that'd be easy.
How about it, Snorke?
Yes, of course.
Will you help us do Sniff? Yes, but I want something too.
I'll let you borrow the wings.
No, I'm far too heavy. I only break them.
Don't worry, sniff. I'm sure I'll think of something you can have.
Oh, as long as it's something nice.
Oh, I do love helping people.
You're all heart-sniff. We know always build for posterity.
Besides, I like pouring cement.
Okay, Papa. I've given your present a lot of fortune, oh?
And I think I'll give you one of my invaluable books on machinery.
Don't you want it?
Well, if there was something else, I'm not much of a reader.
What about my invaluable fountain pen? Don't you want it? Well, if there was something else, I'm not much of a reader.
What about my invaluable fountain pen?
Invaluable fountain pen?
What about my invaluable...
Do you have anything that's not invaluable, Snort?
Well, what about a gold coin?
Well, that sounds great! A real gold coin?
Oh boy, yes, that's a deal.
Oh ho ho!
Uh-oh!
Uh-oh! Uh-oh! You are digging a very deep hole. Uh...
You are digging a very deep hole. Why don't you stop and have some sandwiches?
Should we do that, Papa? Go on.
Yes, I think we can stop now.
Sniff and your brother in the woods.
Yes, I know. I heard them.
Hi, Snork Maiden.
Oh, no.
Wait a minute, I want to ask you something. What is it?
Tell me, Snork Maiden, is it true that your brother gave those wings to a woman?
Yes, it is.
He's helping Snork to build the shadows payment. I thought they'd been broken up. They hit that tree very hard. Well, my brothers are repairing them.
Will you let me pass? I've got to take his lunch to him.
And will he be able to repair them?
He can repair anything!
Mmm.
Gosh! What a lot of wood you've got!
Well, the shed has to be a lot bigger than my life.
I'm not going to let you go. I'm not going to let you go. Anything! Mmm!
Gosh! What a lot of wood you've got!
Well, the shed has to be a lot bigger than my flying ship!
Moving and moving proper digging holes, they sure are deep!
Everybody's being very kind, very kind indeed!
Mama's cooking and Snuffkin's gone to get nails.
There are some other things I need him to get as well.
Will you write them down?
Of course I will, Snork.
Oh, you're such a planner.
Well, I'm afraid all famous inventors have to be.
Yep.
Ah. Ugh.
Whether it was Snork's planning, or the fact that everyone in Mumen Valley helped in some way or other,
the hangar or boat house was finished in record time. I'm going to go able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it.
I'm not going to be able to do it.
I'm not going to be able to do it. I'm not going to be able to do it. You? Moments here? Come in, Moments.
Thank you for all your help.
You did so much that these wings are hardly paymented enough.
But if you're happy with them...
Oh no, it was great fun building this shed.
I changed the design a bit, so it's easier to take off and land.
And turning shouldn't be a problem anymore.
You must remember to give yourself plenty of time though, woman.
Thank you, Snork. I can't wait to try them out.
I'm so excited I don't think I'll sleep tonight.
Are you trying them out tomorrow?
As soon as I can.
You will be careful.
You must practice a lot just above the ground to get used to wearing them before you try
to go too high.
I don't want anything
to happen to you. Oh, practice, I promise. Where are you going to practice tomorrow? I haven't decided.
I'll find somewhere when I come out tomorrow. Perhaps on that small hill near the cliff.
Well that can't be too dangerous.
I'll see you there!
Hey!
Hey! Rui! Hi, Momen. Where do you put the wings?
On the table outside. You must have gone past them if you came in through the veranda door.
No, I didn't. They're not there.
What?
Oh no, you're right. They're gone.
Oh dear, I thought it was my friend.
What's happened to them?
Somebody stole them!
What's the matter with you, too?
Is something wrong?
Yes, somebody stole and Momen's wings!
Well, perhaps they haven't been stolen.
Of course they have, and I bet I know who did it, too!
Come on!
Where are we going? Do you know where they are?
It's stinky! Oh, yeah!
Well, it certainly didn't take you long!
Just a minute, stinky! Those are my wings!
See? I knew it was him!
Stop your horrible creature! I certainly will, Pat! See? I knew it was him. Oh, stop! Oh, stop! Oh, stop! Oh, stop!
Here, prosthetic!
And the wings are mine!
I'll become a master criminal now!
Oh, all rotten saving!
You shouldn't have left them outside, moment!
Yeah, but who'd think let each steal them?
Where his friends, well, almost,
I didn't think even stinky would do something like that! Well, I. Yeah, but who'd think, let each steal them.
I didn't think even stinky would do something like that.
Well, he did, didn't he?
Now, don't worry, moment.
We'll find him and get them back.
I know it.
Yeah.
Look, moment.
Now he's going towards the sea.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh. Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, turn around.
But stinky didn't know how to maneuver the wings.
It was taken further and further out.
Turn around when you turn back.
Until. I'm too. Ah!
You're at least he's having a bath full once. The wings will be badly damaged.
Never mind.
Snark will build another pair.
I sure hope so. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements. the movements believing and sharing and caring and giving the movements
they're always happy and goes at play
the movements are having fun day after day
the movements
the movements The moment, the moment