Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come on.
Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come you are your TV. They are the movements. They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand. I'll take you up to a moment land. You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever. There were the movements. There were the movements. There were the movements, there was the movements
There was the movements, there was the movements Ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba The Hey, where's Danny? I asked her if she wanted to play with us, and she said yes!
Danny, come on!
We're going to have some fun! She wanted to play with us, and she said yes!
Minnie, come on! We're going to have some fun!
Right, let's go.
Ninny, who became invisible because of her sarcastic ant, was now visible up to the neck.
But no matter how much of Granny's remedy she took
or how nice the movements were to her,
her head still remained invisible. So...
That's the invisible child. I wonder what she really looks like.
Ugh, well good morning everybody.
Morning, lazy bones. We've been up for hours and hours.
We're going to play hide and seek in the woods.
Great.
Nini, are you all right?
Yes, thanks.
Hmm.
This is dumb.
If I could see your face, I wouldn't have to ask.
Doesn't help with you, Sniff.
You always ask silly questions. It's a bit big for hide and seek isn't it?
But that's so good about it!
Okay, this is a good place to start, but we've got a new rule for the game.
Once you find somewhere to hide, you've got to stay in the same place, no moving about anyone.
Do you understand, Ninny?
Right, you're to go first, Sniff.
Huh? Why isn't always me first?
We'll have a practice for nanny's sake.
Show her what to do.
Uh, I didn't see it because an easy game.
Not for nanny, it isn't. She's never played it before.
What? Never ever?
No, and not just hide and seek.
She hasn't played any games at all.
Not even when she was visible?
No, nothing.
Oh, that's terrible. So, will you was visible? No nothing. Oh that's terrible. So will you go first?
No I won't. Oh okay I'll go first then. I'll count to 10 slowly so you'll have plenty of time to find somewhere.
One, two, Mini. Hurry up. For!
Five!
I can still see you.
Six!
Seven!
Good, good, good! Hello, Minnie.
Don't be frightened.
Why don't you hide in that bush over there?
He'll never find you.
I'm coming.
Thank you. Oh, my God! God, you sniff! Eh.
Huh?
Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh? Huh? Oh, I'm so excited. I'm so excited. I'm so excited.
I'm so excited.
I'm so excited. I'm so excited. Oops!
Got you, little Mike.
I'd like to know where Ninny's hiding.
Oh, look. Oh!
Ah, come out, Ninny.
I've got you.
That was a good place, but I saw your ribbeth.
Oh! Now for snork maiden. She's always easy to find.
Ha! That's only because she wants to be found.
Found you snork maiden. One.
Two.
Don't wait, nanny, this is my bush.
Four.
Hey, nanny, I'll show you a good place. Just come with your uncle stinky.
Now don't worry, no one will find you there.
It opens up once you're inside.
Come on, it's a bit steep, I'll help you.
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Right, that should keep you quiet. You're a bit too visible at the moment.
Oh, let me out.
But I'm sure if you stay here until tomorrow,
no one will see it all.
Please don't leave me here.
Please.
Oh, it's...
Oh, please.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
That's it.
Now tomorrow we'll hit the bank!
Let me out! Please let me out!
I'm very glad I thought of bringing Ninny here.
It's nice to have her here too, Tiki.
She's no trouble at all.
You're all pretty eccentric,
and it might be just what she needs to make her want to be seen again.
Oh, and you're very kind, of course.
Well, thank you. I think, I suppose we should be flattens, shouldn't we?
Oh, yes, definitely.
She started to talk, but her voice is very weak.
You have to listen very carefully.
Has it always been like that?
Or just since she was invisible?
I'm not sure.
I don't think it was like that before.
Lots of people manage very well without using their heads,
so I'm certain any will be all right.
Yes, and I'm glad she's got movement in the others to play with.
She's never had anybody before, you know.
I think she'd find it a bit difficult to tickle.
Well, Moomin, Mama, I think that all she needs is something to shock her out of it.
Huh. Got you little, my.
Oh, that bush was too prickly anyway.
I expect I'm the last one, hey.
No, I haven't found any yet.
Mini?
I didn't think Mini would hide so well.
Any luck, Sniff?
There's nowhere else to look, Momen.
Perhaps she's lost or fallen or hurt herself.
I've looked absolutely everywhere.
I bet she's invisible again.
That's why I can't find her.
I bet Sniff hasn't looked everywhere.
She can't be far.
Do you know where she is, Moomin?
No, I haven't seen her at all. Not since we started.
Nanny! Come on, we're going home. We've finished playing.
Nanny!
Oh my goodness, where could she be?
It's your turn, Sniff, so you've got to find her.
Nanny!
Not once the game's over, I haven't.
Never mind. We'll all look. We must find her.
We are supposed to be looking after her, you know?
Ugh.
Aw, come on. Nanny, the game's over. We've finished.
Nanny, Nanny, hurry up. We're going home for cookies and lemonade.
Nanny, Nanny! Nanny!
Nanny!
Can you hear us?
We weren't supposed to come this far, Snork Maiden. Nanny! Nanny! Can you hear us?
We weren't supposed to come this far, Snork Maiden.
She might be really lost or frightened or anything!
Nanny! Where are you, Nanny?
Can you hear me? Nanny!
Help! I'm over here!
Did you hear something?
I'm not sure. Help!
Help!
I'm here!
That's her!
She's not far away!
Lenny!
Where are you?
Here!
Behind this rock!
Of course her voice coming from!
That way I think!
Lenny!
I can't hear what you're saying.
Try and shout a bit louder.
I'm over here!
Over here!
Behind the rock!
I still can't hear properly.
Louder than any louder!
Behind the rock!
Which rock?
Over here!
The big rock!
Over there!
I've never shouted so much in my life!
Nanny!
Nanny, are you behind this rock, Nanny?
Yes! Stinky block the cave with it!
Don't worry, we'll get you out.
Hang on!
Are you alright, Lily? Thank you, Mum.
Oh, thank you!
Your voice seems to be...
Oh, what? Oh, nothing.
Try and hold on to me, and I'll pull you out.
Oh, thank you!
Hey, what's happened?
Where'd you find her?
In the cave.
Wow, what a brilliant hiding place had you find it!
What's wrong? Did I say something funny?
Now that was very mean of stinking. The clever idea though, I meant to use it for a ban robbery.
Oh, Papa!
Oh I know stinky shouldn't have done it,
and it must have been a nasty shopping trapped in the dark in that cave,
but no real harm came to her and she didn't disappear,
and her voice got much stronger.
Because she yelled so loud.
Oh, goodness, did you, dear?
Yes, Mum and Mama.
Mum and told me to yell loudly so he'd know where I was.
And it was loud too.
Good for you, Nanny.
It's surprising the things you can do if you have to, and you ought to remember that
people who speak loudly are usually very noticeable.
Go on, yeah, I want to see it.
That's a good idea, Ninny.
If shouting brought back your voice, you never know it might be just what's needed to make the rest of you visible.
Try and get angry as well.
Yeah, that's easy. Just think about stinky.
Yeah, and how horrible he is.
That should make you angry. Very angry.
Just your white stinky!
I can't help faster than me!
Stinky, wait! We want to talk to you!
I don't want to talk to you!
No!
Come on!
Oh, you are right, sniff!
You can't get away, stinky.
The forest is my home ground. You won't catch me in here.
Ah!
I did it.
Hold it. This hole to change your mind and scare her so much that she'd become totally invisible again
She had to be invisible for my plan now get me out of here. It's all right. Stinking. See you tomorrow
You crux you things I had such a wonderful plan! Ah! Ah! They're spiteful!
Oh, let's hear them my next job!
But despite all that had happened,
Ninny's face was still not to be seen.
Then, about ten days later... This weather seems to push the nails out.
I haven't seen anyone stare at the sea like Minnie does.
Well maybe she's crying now.
What's the matter?
It's the sea. It's far too big! You don't have to go on it, you know.
Mama! Mama! What's up?
Hmm?
What's the matter with her?
Nothing to worry about. She's never seen the sea before
and she's just surprised at how big it is.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. What's the matter with her? Nothing to worry about. She's never seen the sea before, and she's just surprised at how big it is.
Well, there's an awful lot of water, that's for sure.
Oh.
Nanny's lucky.
I wish there was something to surprise or excite me.
Nothing's happened for weeks. Anything would be nice.
Mama must be bored.
I think you're right.
But she never gets bored.
Well, she is now. She needs something to happen.
I think we should do something to surprise her.
Like what?
Well, I know what we can do.
Well, tell me.
We'll creep up behind her and just give her a little push.
What, Papa?
Push her into the sea?
Oh, Papa, you can't.
Mama wouldn't like it.
Just watch me.
But the water's freezing.
A mama will get all wet.
We never found the water too cold when we were your age.
You young people today have no sense of fun.
Did you really used to do things like that?
All the time. Papa?
Yes, Mumann?
Oh, nothing.
Don't worry, Mumann.
Mumann, Joy's a prank.
You'll find it very funny, I promise. I know you don't!
No! Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Don't you dare push your end to that big horrible scene.
Let me explain to me.
There's nothing to explain.
You're a big bully.
She'd have gone all wet.
What a nasty trick.
You could never, never. I'm sorry. Yeah. What? What? What?
What?
What? What? What? What? What? I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry!
What on earth happened? Were you up to something?
Oh, nothing much.
You know, that child has got the sharpest teeth
with the without our head.
A woman?
A woman at last? I'm visible again.
We're always you won't disappear again. Never, I'll never. Brave girl, and with a good strong set of healthy teeth too.
Oh, I'm so happy, nanny.
Mimi dear.
I'm very glad too.
Oh.
Oh. Uh. Uh. Uh. Oh. Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, Stop laughing you horrible child you use Sartuth monster.
What's so funny? Really? Ninny laughed? Well, she certainly changed, Moomin, Mama.
All she needed was to get angry, and she did.
I hope Moomin poppies forgiven Ninny.
Thank you all for taking such good care of her.
I hate to say it, but she sounds almost as bad as it'll mine out.
I'm sorry, but I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, but I'm sorry. all for taking such good care of her.
I hate to say it, but she sounds almost as bad as it'll mine out.
Tiki! Nini!
And so Nini left movement house with Tiki.
Now that she was completely visible and far from Timid,
she was ready for anything.
Anything that is except seeing her aunt, she said.
Hey.
Hmm.
Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah.
Boom!
Yeah. Yeah. They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements, believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and go as it played.
The movements are having fun day after day. The moment, the moment.