Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
Therefore you are your TV.
They are the movements.
They are the movements, they are the movements,
so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land, you can fly
just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there was the movement, there was the movement, there was the movement, there was the movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la The weather was far too beautiful for a woman Papa to concentrate on writing his memoirs,
so he went for a walk instead.
Good morning, Mr. Hamilton.
Ah, a woman Papa.
Have you found a new plan or something?
I'm afraid not, and I think I must have examined every single plant in Moomin Valley.
I know what you mean. There isn't a single person living here that I don't know.
Oh, yes, yes, quite.
Look, why don't you come over and have a cup of tea, Mr. Evelyn? Hmm? Isn't that moment a little, my?
Yes, I think it is.
Really, a moment, Papa, peeping into people's homes.
Oh, it's an empty house, Mr. Hemmellon.
Moment, what are you looking at?
Oh, hello, Papa. Nobody's lived in there for years. Somebody's just moved in.
Oh, really?
Let me have a look.
Oh, goodness.
How tidy they are.
Perhaps the children will play with us.
Well, they might, but they seem a bit too well behaved for that.
I must have a closer look at them.
Me too, Mum and Papa, but I'm not going to be able to they might, but they seem a bit too well behaved for that.
Me too, Moomin Papa, but the trouble is they never come outside the fence.
Well, in that case, we'll have to go in.
How do we do that, Papa?
We can't just walk in there.
See, you want to borrow some sugar? That should do it.
Oh, Mr. Hamilton, where's your imagination?
Will you please lend me your magnifying glass?
But surely. Here it is.
Oh, that should do it.
What are you going to do, Papa?
Now then, you all stay out here.
My plan will only work if it looks as though I'm on my own.
Oh, but what is your plan, Papa?
I hope Papa knows what he's doing.
They don't look that friendly to me. Me neither.
Mama, there's someone coming.
Oh! What do you want, my good man? Come on, tell me quickly. Do you hear me?
Hmm. Hmm? Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't think anyone lived here.
Well, we do know. You know we just moved in.
Really? Oh, do forgive me, madame. I certainly didn't mean to trespass.
Ah, so what are you doing here in the garden, man?
Researching the travel system of ants.
I didn't know they had one.
Oh, yeah, yeah, it's fascinating.
How they find their way and build their roads,
and they're not here now, of course.
But this is their main road.
It's very quiet at the moment, but at busy times, it's packed.
I'm afraid I can't see any main road.
Oh, you would if you were an expert.
Anyway, I'll point it out to you next time they're on the move.
If I'm in the vicinity, of course, but it's worth looking out for.
Welcome to Moomin Valley.
I'm your next door neighbor, though.
We live quite a long way away.
I'm Moomin.
Ah! So you must be Moomin Papa, are you?
Ah, yes.
That's me.
Ha, ha, how did you know?
Ha, ha, ha.
Did someone mention my name to you?
We were told the moments were a bit unusual. Very nice, they said though.
How very flattering, thank you.
And you're Mrs.
Billy John, mother and housewife.
Well, it's an honor to meet you. Mrs. Philly John.
Well done, Papa. It looks like you found us some new friends to play with.
Oh, welcome, party.
Don't you think it's a good idea? We haven't had a party for ages, Mama.
But you hardly know them, and I've never even met them.
But, Mama, how can we show them that they're really welcome
and they could meet everyone at a party, couldn't they?
And I could take care of all the children.
I know just what to do.
Splendid moment.
Ah, Mr. Hebblin, I know, moment papa.
You'd like me to do the fireworks.
It looks like we're throwing a party.
We'll have lots of pretty flowers. Just tell me what you want, mama, and we'll do it.
It's great! Those kids will just love it!
If they survive, mumen! It's great! Those kids will just love it!
If they survive, movement!
Now then, children! The movements are all a little bit odd, so behead properly!
Yes, mother, we will!
They'll be here soon. Take this in, movement! Yes, mother, we will.
They'll be here soon. Take this in, Mummett. Okay.
The joke works really well.
Oh, good. I must try it.
Mmm, these look nice.
Oh, stiff. Leave them alone, will you?
Oh, all right. Just this one.
Huh? Huh?
They're here.
Come on, everybody.
They'll soon be at the door.
Right.
Come on, children.
Help me with the flowers.
Oh, dear.
Fireworks now are later on.
Oh, later on, I think you'll very hold finally. Welcome to Moomin House, Mrs. Philly John. It was very kind of you to invite us, Moomin Lama.
Come in, please, and make yourselves at home.
Oh, thank you all very much indeed.
Welcome to Moomin Valley.
Welcome to Moomin Valley. Welcome to Moomin Valley. Welcome to Moomin Valley. Welcome to Moomin Valley. Welcome to Moomin Valley. Welcome to Moomin Valley. You're watching, Deed.
All in my hair. It looks very untidy, doesn't it, mother?
It's a surprise.
They should have been rose buds,
but we couldn't find any at all.
Oh, yes.
Dear, what a mess. Mrs. Mrs. Philly chunk let me introduce the
children. They all look different. Well yes only
movement is really ours the others are sort of I'm sure they'll all get on. Oh
I'm afraid my children do not play. They would much rather read or study.
Oh, are you sure they've got to have some time for play?
I'm sure.
Well, come into the dining room anyway.
You can watch the others play.
Make sure the chairs are clean.
Yes, Mother, we will.
Won't you let them play at all?
No, I will not.
Come on, everybody.
Wouldn't you like to have a go on our slide?
No.
Hmm.
You'd really enjoy it once you got going.
I know you would.
No, thank you. No, no, not at all.
No, definitely not.
And you're really quite sure, are you?
Yes.
I thought so.
Then we've got it all to ourselves.
Yahoo! No! No! No!
No!
No! No! Oh, and that's little May and sniff.
Your children seem very quiet, Mrs. Philly junk.
Good children are seen and not heard right here.
That was one of mine.
And that was another.
Well, it sounds like they're having fun for once.
To have a biscuit Mrs. Philly junk.
They have an unusual taste.
I'd run out of flowers, so I used them.
Oh!
Don't worry.
Move them a little bit after them.
Oh!
Go on.
It's your turn now.
Wee!
Wee! Wee! Oh! Go on, it's your turn now.
Yay!
Whoa!
Oh, my children!
Yay!
Oh!
Stop it, it's too dangerous.
You might hurt yourself.
Yay! Oh, come on! It's too dangerous. You might hurt yourself. I see. No!
Ha ha!
Oh, come on! Stop it at once!
Now, don't you worry, Mrs. Villageunk.
I got ointment in my bag if I hurt themselves.
But you'll hear mother.
Ha ha ha ha!
Stop children! You hear me? We're going home now.
Stop it.
Oh, this is really hard for us to kill them.
I think it's time for the glorious finale, Papa.
I can't say I wasn't warned.
Exposing them to this,
Movement Valley is no place for proper children.
No place at all.
Oh, dear, what's this?
There are fireworks in your honor.
Fireworks?
I made them especially to welcome you.
Goodbye! Come back soon!
Yeah, welcome to the park! No, you will not!
I don't think Mrs. Philly John can enjoy her party.
She's very lucky that I didn't think Mrs. Philly John can join her party. She's very lucky that I didn't bite her.
She should have had a go on the slide.
I'm sure she would have loved it.
And then she wouldn't have shouted at her children.
Don't up, don't slide down, shoot sniff.
They're too afraid of looking silly.
Whoa!
Oh, oh.
Papa.
Oh, I'm very sorry, moment, but don't worry, I'll fix it.
It is nothing much broken.
What happened, my dear?
Well, I thought it had been such a long time since I'd been on the slide that I'd have a go.
I didn't think I'd be too heavy for it.
I know. When we mend it, why don't we make it strong enough for me and Mama to play on as well?
I think she'd like that.
That's a good idea, Papa. But we want to use it too.
Well, that's a course. I just try it out. Now and again.
I want you to stay here while I'm out. What if somebody asks us to play? What do you mean? Play.
I hope you're not thinking of the mommens, are you?
I don't want you mixing with those noisy children ever again.
You hear me?
Where are you going, mother?
To look for another house.
It was a terrible mistake coming to Mumen Valley. again do you hear me where are you going mother to look for another house it
was a terrible mistake coming to move in valley
look there's Mrs. Philly drunk good afternoon please stay away from my
children but why?
We thought they might like to come and have an adventure with us.
Oh, never mind. Let's go.
Hey, hang on a minute!
Hey!
Oh, your tar-sa! Yeah!
Oh! Oh, no! Oh, no! Oh, no!
Oh, no!
I can't see!
It's too late for you now, Sniff!
Oh, no, not the hungry crocodile at the bottom of the porch!
We should have brought the Philly Junks with us.
But Moon and Mrs. Philly Junks... We need to look tall, her.
Have you been killed and eaten yet, Sniff?
No, I fell on top of the crocodile and knocked him out, and then swam ashore.
Sniff, but I thought you couldn't swim.
On your own business.
Hey, that looks like the Philly Junks!
Why don't they come over here? I bet their mother told them not to talk to us.
Huh? See if I care you!
Hey! What are you doing? Why aren't you playing with Mormon and the others?
I don't think they want to play with us.
They didn't call for us when they went past.
Stinky's arrived and wonder what he's doing here.
I bet you it's no fun stuck in that garden.
No, we'd rather be out here playing.
Well, I know somewhere much better than moments.
It's a great place to play.
Do you?
Yes, would I lie to you?
It's a bit of a way off, but it'll be really exciting
and lots of fun so do you want to come or not.
Well, it is a bit boring here.
Yes, very.
Do you really think they don't want to play with us?
Doesn't look like it.
Your brother's absolutely right.
So come on if you're coming, because I can't wait.
What stinky up, too?
I don't trust him. Okay, now this is the place I told you about. Good, isn't it? Now, if you hang on to that rope, you can swing over to the other side and back again. Don't worry, it's quite safe.
That's great. I've never been anywhere like this.
A bit frightening.
Without the thrill, where's the fun?
You need a bit of danger to spice it up.
Gee, Willikers, it looks like the other side is higher than this side.
Yes, I bet it's all right. You just have to put your legs up. That's all.
Who wants to go first?
I've got it. Why don't you all go together?
What?
The three of us?
See, this way it won't feel so scared, will you?
No, not together.
Well, why don't you go one at a time then?
That way it's always more fun.
Can you do it, stinky?
Don't be silly. Of course I can. I do it all the time.
One of the things I'm best at. Even if I do say so myself. So why don't you show us Stinky?
Moonin! I didn't know you were such a rop swinger Stinky. I'm sure he didn't either.
So this is your usual place, is it? Well, sort of.
You know something? If you hadn't said that you'd done this lots of times,
I wouldn't have believed that I could have done it myself.
Come on, Stinky, show us how you do it.
If you go first, I'll be second.
No, it's alright. You can go first, Mom.
But I want to see how it's done. Then throw me the rope and I'll follow.
Now, tell the truth. You've never done it. Have you stinky?
Of course I've done it, stupid!
Now come on, come on. Don't be such a spoiled sport.
We're all here waiting to cheer you on.
Alright, everybody. I give you the brave, evolved Tarzan Stinky.
You watching?
Are you ready, Stinky?
A big cheer, everyone!
Ready?
Yeah!
Oh, Stinky, my big brave here, oh, jump!
Well, go on, we're all waiting for you, Stinky.
Come on, Stinky, show us how to jump.
Come on, Stinky, come on, you can do it.
Come on, you can do it.
Jump! Stinky shorts out. Come on, Stinky! Come on, you can do it. You can do it. You can do it.
Whoa!
Huh?
Oh, so this is how you've done it lots of times before, is it?
Yes, the rope is the straw!
He was trying to fool you.
It was a dangerous game, and he knew very well it couldn't be done.
I did it!
Now, why don't you come with us and play properly?
You're gonna be tired, as long as you like!
And when you get tired, just let go of the rope!
All right, Steve?
Mama, take it!
Yeah!
You can't just leave me here, you fuck!
Uh, uh, innocent, fair please!
Help! Don't leave me here!
Woo!
Woo! Woo! Woo!
Woo! Yeah!
But Stinky was left on his own to decide whether to climb up the rope or drop into the river.
And the Phyllis-Jong children had more fun than they'd ever had before,
but they didn't get home until very late in the evening.
Bye, we'll see you tomorrow.
Okay, mommy. Okay, Moomin.
Bye, Moomin.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Oh, my dear children, I told you to stand home.
What earth have you been?
Where have you been?
With movement and the others.
They kidnapped you, did they?
No, we've been playing with them.
Well, you can just forget about the movements.
We're moving out as soon as we possibly can.
Moving, mother?
Yes, right away from this valley,
this is no place for a spotless and well-ordered home.
What's the matter?
No, we don't want to move.
Ah.
We want to stay, mother.
Oh!
Muminhouse is nice and dusty.
We want to stay in Mumin Valley forever.
Oh, please, mother. We love it here.
Oh, after all I've done for you children.
And my experience children usually get what they want. What? And that was how Phila Junk and her three children became permanent residents of Mumen Valley.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements, believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements, the movements, the moment.