Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
Therefore you are your TV.
They are the movements.
So what do you think?
I think it's a good idea.
I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. with me, therefore you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements,
so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land, you can fly just like a bird,
sing that song ever, there were a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement,
there was a movement. All over the moon down, bits of paper were fluttering down.
Oh, we're so excited!
I'm so excited!
Let's go slow!
They were even falling over the lake.
What's this?
Oh, litter. There's some writing on that piece of paper.
I think it's a message.
Hmm, hmm.
Let's see.
Moment, theater presents, written by Moment Papa.
Moment, Papa.
The last children of Moment Valley.
Sarring Moment Papa, Moment Mama, and SNF
and introducing Emma.
Emma?
I'm sure that's my ad.
She works in a theater.
Hmm. Admission fee? Anything edible.
Yeah.
They're putting on a play. So they can't be lost.
Hmm. I haven't seen a play since I was a kid.
It was wonderful. The best play ever.
All about a princess.
She fell asleep in a rose bush.
She was so lovely.
I've got to see that one again.
But who will guard my prisoners, I wonder?
I'm a good idea, officer.
You could take the three of us with you to the theater to see the play.
Good idea.
We love the theater, so we won't try to run away
off as the red promise.
Hmm, not possible.
I won't let you out of this jail until you write out
it's forbidden to burn signs 5,000 times each.
That's the punishment for vandals.
Well, in that case, you won't be able to see the play.
Ah, who cares?
Oh, well.
Yes, I must see it, I must go.
So you'll take us with you?
No, you stay right here.
Well, then you can't go either, officer.
Quiet, you're upsetting me.
No, no, this isn't good enough.
It's not true drama.
Ah, please, Moomin, Papa.
I don't want to be just a lion's ugly behind. But, Sniff, I did give you another part.
I don't want to be a baby either.
And she said you wanted parts without lines.
Could you do the dusting a bit later, Emma, please?
He's scripture be ready now.
We have to start practicing for the opening night tomorrow morning.
Don't worry, Emma. It's coming along.
I'm only half done.
I shall never get ready in time, woman mama.
You're right to worry for the curtain will rise tomorrow, no matter what!
Huh! Huh! Huh!
I'm really not going to remember to give Emma lots and lots of lines.
She's really looking forward to her first performance.
All right. Now leave me. I must be left alone to concentrate.
The writer needs peace and quiet.
There are some things I don't like about this script.
Well, I'll discuss it with you after the performance, Sniff.
After.
If it's a story about lost children, why do you have to have a stupid lion?
I'm too good an actor to be cast as a lion.
I'll keep them out of my hair when indeed he's giving me a headache.
You come with me, Sniff. I'll keep them out of my hair when indeed he's giving me a headache.
You come with me, sniff.
We'll practice our parts.
This could be a wonderful play if you'd only skip the lions behind.
I've heard enough about this behind.
Remember we have a lion's head too, dying to show his acting skills on the stage.
This is my play and I refuse to write out the lion's part.
I refuse to write out the lion's bot. I refuse.
Here is the key.
I want you to keep a keen eye on them until I come back.
Do you understand me, cousin?
Are they very dangerous?
Yes, they certainly are.
They bite if you let them out.
Okay?
We certainly wouldn't bite anyone, officer.
I've had enough of your lies.
Don't listen to my dear cousin, they do.
Well then, now I'm up to the theater to see the play.
Take good care of them while I'm gone.
Excuse me. You seem to be a very good knitter. Oh, thank you.
Nobody ever said that to me before.
I enjoy it.
What are you making?
I'm not sure.
I don't really know.
Nothing in particular.
It's just that knitting is so reassuring somehow.
Nothing bad can happen while you knit, can it?
The trouble is I always seem to forget to decide what to make before I start.
But it feels nice and warm and I love the color.
Couldn't you make socks? It's a very nice sock color.
Socks?
Yes, it's very, very cold in here.
Oh, yes!
That's a very good idea.
Listen, if I needed each one of you a pair of warm socks, would you really put them on?
Of course!
That would be nice.
I'm almost freezing to death in here.
It's so very, very cold.
Is it really that cold?
Yes, like tea's a chattery, so I could hardly talk.
Honestly.
Oh, dear, oh dear.
What should I do?
Maybe some steaming hot black currant juice
would help to warm us up a little.
Possibly, although it might already be too late.
My cousin would be very angry with me if he knew, but I think... What you think? What?
I think I'll let you out so that we can all be nice and warm indoors.
Really? Really?
Wait! Wait!
Don't cry now, baby.
There's a good boy. Don't cry, honey.
That's enough, baby.
Whoa!
Oh, moment mama, you need to show much more emotion.
Try to be more motherly and more loving.
Listen dear, this is a very heavy baby.
How am I doing, moment papa?
You're just perfect for the part sniffing your performance was excellent
Look at these I think they might be ready by now. I hope they're tasty. They don't always come out very well.
You're so kind! We've had so much already!
But they smell really delicious.
They sure do!
Thank you so much. Now I feel warm again.
How about some more black currant juice?
Or maybe one of these freshly baked cookies?
It's very kind of you, but no thank you.
I couldn't eat another thing.
I'm so full up.
Me too.
Oh dear, the party is over then.
I'm afraid so.
It's really sad, but I have to lock you up again.
But at least I know your warm in there.
We're real sorry too, but you don't need to worry
because actually we're not going back to jail.
Oh aren't you?
We've got other plans. We're going to the theater to see my parents play.
And I suppose I should say hello to my Aunt Emma who works there.
Oh what shall I do? My cousin will be very cross with me.
But you see we're innocent. We didn't do anything wrong. You didn't?
I swear it. Do I look like someone who pulls up signs in a park? We just burned some
flotsum left by the flood, but your cousin wouldn't believe it. He jumped to conclusions,
wrongful arrest. That's all it was. Oh dear, why didn't you tell me that it was. Oh dear why didn't you tell me that it once? Oh people shouldn't go to jail
when they haven't done anything wrong. So we can go to the theaters that okay? Of course
better leave right away my cousin will be very disappointed but I guess I can't be helped.
Wait for me. I think I'd better come along and explain to that cousin of mine that his three prisoners are innocent of the charge against them.
All right, all right, bring it in.
That's right, Mumm, Bupa, stop there.
Okay, sniff.
Mumm and Mama, what have you got there?
A baby's crib.
I want to use this in the play.
If that's all right with you.
Mumm and Papa,, woman, Papa.
I've just read your script, and I think you have a big problem.
Who is going to pay the parts of a woman and snort maiden
in this play of yours?
I don't know yet.
We don't have any more children, and Sniff can't take the part.
Are you utterly mad?
We only have a few hours before the curtain
goes up, and you don't even have ashes for all the parts.
What kind of director is that? Maybe one of us could stand behind something and sort of read their line. We only have a few hours before the curtain goes up, and you don't even have ashes for all the pot.
What kind of director is that?
Maybe one of us could stand behind something
and sort of read their line.
We did kill us!
I did it!
Let's hope the credits are proud.
Hold on tight, all of you.
Now!
Listen, kids. You can be as noisy as you like out here, but once we're at the dinner, you
have to be quiet.
You understand?
You're right. The audience is waiting for us. Ladies and gentlemen, thank you so much for giving up your valuable time in order to come to our show tonight.
The world premiere of the Lost Children. This is a brand new company and the players never been performed before.
Ladies and gentlemen, sit back and enjoy the superb acting.
What's that?
A baby's cradle.
It's for you, Sniff.
For me?
We sincerely hope you'll be thrilled by the originality of the plot.
And so now dear friends, let's get started.
Let's get started.
Come on.
Come on, come on! Come on!
Oh, thank you, Sydney. There's a good boy. Don't cry, honey. Please don't cry.
Hmm. A woman snorkemaid in my darling children. You've been lost for a whole month and we haven't heard a word from either of you.
Oh, he's forgotten all about me!
Shh!
I'd give the whole world to be rid of this most terrible,
agonizing despair.
Ah, ah!
Oh, I'll make your husband try not to fret,
so I'm sure he'll be back before very long.
Little children, come and free me from this plight.
Your mother worries all day through the babies awake all night.
Come home, come home, my children too.
With all our hearts we're missing you.
Eh, eh, eh, eh, eh, eh.
Mm-hmm.
Loud or sniff?
Eh, eh, eh, oh, well, mama.
But what's wrong with you, Sniff?
This rocket's making me sick.
Oh, dear, and right in the middle of movement, pop is play.
Oh, oh, oh.
Mama, let us set forth and find our loved ones.
We cannot leave our baby here.
Oh, anyone would love to have him sweet little thing.
For how long, pray, do you think we would be gone?
For as long as it takes, I can no longer stand
being this frightfully upset about my children.
Oh, baby!
Yeah.
Hurry up, sniff!
I'm trying! Hurry!
Seen two is about to start!
Help me somebody!
I can't get out of here!
When do they put the princess on?
We still have very far to go.
I'm afraid so hurry, Mumin!
I am hurrying!
It's 4 p.m.
It's 4 p.m. What are you writing on that that? My cousin won't give up, I'm sure.
So I better ride this 5,000 times. It's for bitten. It's for bitten. It's for bitten.
A full two weeks has passed. Oh, what shall we do?
Our dear children have disappeared from the face of the Earth.
Oh, what's happened, dear Apple, of my heart?
I think I sprayed my hands really badly.
Oh, it hurts.
If you were in trouble, apart from the wolves, we're all alone.
I'll pull you out.
Oh, stop it, stop!
Why must this happen in my theater?
I've been squeezed in here to make me look smaller!
Help!
I'm trying to!
We can't have the land on stage without his behind!
Wow!
I'm so nervous!
Come on!
Whoa!
We have to face the worst and spend the night right here in the wilderness.
Dear husband, will it be all right?
Fairly in these unhulled woods, I feel quite queasy.
Sweet wife, I too can smell those frightful beasts,
howling for a blood.
May not just smell them, dear.
Anything that I can hear them now.
I can hear the howling of those hungry beasts.
Painting is the roar, but I can make it out a lion!
Ow!
Oh!
Oh, sniff, what's up?
Where are you going, dear?
Oh, listen, I have to go and stop that stupid lion who's roaming around the countryside watching our every move.
Hey, don't worry, I'll be right back, my dear.
Was he supposed to say that?
Hey, what are you doing here? You're supposed to be on stage.
It's not my father stuck in his crib.
Moment, mama, stuck on stage. Roll lion! I feel sick! Ah! What are you doing, moment papa?
You can do it with a cradle on, sniff.
No, I can't stop it! Please don't do it, moment papa!
They'll laugh at me out there!
Don't worry! Nobody knows it's you hiding in there.
Come on now, hurry!
Ah! A lion! A lion! Is this to be my most untimely end?
Don't you dare let me do it!
Whoa! That lion can eat! Move it, Mama!
Oh, no! what might you do? What should I do, Lauren Papa?
I'm scared. Can't be quite to clear.
Let's run off across a stage here.
We were supposed to run off together.
The situation has changed.
I'll have to come to your rescue some other time here.
Oh, help me out!
Oh, please don't work, please! Please, oh, now, ever again, I'm gonna be sick!
Help me, please! Someone come quickly before I get killed!
Oh!
Coming, moving, mama!
Come here, we got you!
Oh, it's only snap!
Little Maya, I'm so glad you're all right.
Shirley, weren't worried about me, Momma.
Well, just a little maybe, but you're such a lucky girl.
I knew you'd manage.
Momma!
I don't believe it.
Momma, it's me, Momma!
And it's me, Snork Maiden!
Momma! Momma!
Momma!
Moment Snork Maiden, is it really you?
Come here and let me see you!
We've come back, Mama!
I was dying to see you!
Oh, it's wonderful to have you back.
You're not my niece?
And Emma!
Oh!
You look so grown up!
And Emma, so sorry to have missed your show,
but I have so much to tell you.
Hi, everybody.
That was a great performance.
Snuff pin, I'm so glad to see you.
Glad you saved a movement.
Yay!
Those are my prisoners.
They've escaped from jail. Catch them. B.A.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E.R.E. Very well! You are both under arrest! No! No! No! No!
We were these pretzel children.
Dear dear cousin.
Eh?
Eh.
It's forbidden. It's forbidden.
Five thousand times. That's what you wanted.
And are you sure there are five thousand?
Oh yes. Quite sure. I've counted them.
Huh. One, two, three, four.
Now that we are all together again,
I would really like to go back to Moomin Valley.
What shall we do with all these little pests, Nuffkin?
Well, little Mai.
Someone might like to foster them.
You can leave them in my car, sir.
You always am odd.
Yes.
Now I have some acting experience.
I think I would like to start an acting school, exactly what this theater needs.
What a good idea.
Do you think I would be too old to attend?
Perhaps character parts.
Like in my play.
All is arranged for the best, so now we can go home.
It is, Mom and Papa, I think it's high time.
Quiet, please, I've lost my cup.
Now I'll have to start again right from the beginning.
Mom and Papa, do you think we should thank the audience for their patience? Quiet, please! I've lost my cup! Now I'll have to start again right from the beginning.
Moomin Papa, do you think we should thank the audience for their patience?
Because they're still watching us, you know?
No, you're right.
Ladies and gentlemen, that's all for tonight.
I hope you have enjoyed the performance.
I think it was very kind of you to stay to the very end.
APPLAUSE
Sometimes I could almost believe the truth is strange
and the fiction of it.
Where it is, isn't it, William Parker?
No, not really. We writers are no better.
I'll write more play.
Oh, what a very good idea, Moomin, Papa.
I think you're as good with plays as you are with memoirs.
What are you two?
Right, I'll start on the sequel as soon as we're all back home.
There it is, I lovely home.
At least I got a proper wash.
I've never seen it so clean.
What about in shine?
Oh, redecorated, probably.
Yeah. Let's go.
The moving family spent the whole of the following week
making their house cozy and comfortable.
And soon each carpet, each cup and saucer
and every piece of furniture
was back in its proper place once again. We're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The Moons are having fun day after day
The Moons
The Moons The Moon, the Moon.