Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So, what do you think?
I think it's a good idea.
I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. Yeah, with me, they're for you on your TV. They are the movements.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
There were the movement, there was the movement,
There was the movement, there was the movement,
There was the movement, there was the movement, When the Hennon first told Moomin about the golden fish, to himself that it must look something like this.
My grandpa told me that his mother had actually seen it. So you never saw it yourself, Mr. Hamlin?
No, I'm a batonist.
It comes to the surface only under very special conditions.
It's very rarely seen.
Conditions? Yes. First of all, it must be right between summer and autumn.
But that's now. Yes. It has to be in the afternoon sunshine after heavy rain.
Oh, yes, that does narrow it down. And there must be no wind. Grandpa said not even a ripple on the water.
Oh dear. And there are some other conditions that he really didn't
know about anyway to see it. You must be extremely lucky. Hmm. Just getting to the lake itself
isn't too easy. It's way beyond lonely mountains. Going over lonely mountains and back would
take at least two days. Not really, because I know a shortcut movement.
I could take you there and back in one day.
Oh, could you do that?
Yes.
Have you already been there, Snuffkin?
Just once.
Oh, will you show me the way?
You really want to go?
Yes.
I must see that golden fish with my own eyes and maybe capture it.
It won't be easy to capture.
Why not?
From what I've heard, the golden fish is far too clever to get caught.
I know, but it would be so much fun.
You going alone?
Well, Snorkmaiden said she wanted to come along.
She gets these ideas, you know.
Just Snorkmaiden?
Uh, maybe a little my.
What about Sniff?
I think he wants to come along too.
For both you. In that case, we'd better go across the mountains. Why's that? Why can't we take the shortcut?
The path is rather steep and dangerous, you know, Moomin. Especially in the forest of witches.
I know witches? Not now, maybe. Oh, so it's safe then. But it's a very deep forest, dark and scary even in daytime.
That's okay, we'll Don't go. Shh.
Shh.
Shh. Shh. Shh. Oh dear!
Good morning, Snuffkin! Sorry, Snuffkin, guess I overslept.
Snort Maiden a little my aunt here yet.
You're very early.
Hmm, I dreamt I caught the golden fish, and then of course I couldn't go back to sleep.
Well, let's go.
Shouldn't we wait for Snort Maiden a little my?
Oh, they're not really great walkers, are they?
And anyway, didn't we decide that we wouldn't wait for anybody? Wait for snork maiden and little Mai? Oh, they're not really great walkers, are they?
And anyway, didn't we decide that we wouldn't wait for anybody?
So it might be better this way.
What's better this way, woman?
Oh, little Mai.
Why don't you stay here?
This will be a very tough expedition.
I'm tougher than you.
Wait for me!
Hey, you walk any faster, Snapp? I'm still so sleepy!
Why did we have to leave so early, Moomin?
To get there back in a day, Snorkemaid.
But we aren't taking the shortcut, are we?
Yes, but it still might get dark before we're back.
I won't be able to walk back this fast, you know,
because my bucket will be full of water for the golden fish.
Well, don't be disappointed if you don't catch it.
But that's my whole reason for going.
But you heard what the Himmielin said, Sniff?
We'll be extremely lucky to even catch
side of the golden fish.
I heard him, and now's exactly the right time.
Maybe the others made too much noise.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Don't you worry, I'll catch you, alright?
Where are they?
We're going sorely in the morning.
How far is the forest of witches? Where are they? We're going sorely in the morning.
How far is the forest of witches? I'd say about two hours.
And can you also tell us how long from one end of the forest
to the other's naufkin?
About the same.
Uh, eh.
Eh, eh.
Are there really such things as witches?
No.
Baby, because I'm not a bit scared of them.
Aren't you?
Not the least little bit.
There used to be some, though.
What witch is?
Well, of course, sniff.
What else do you think that they call it the forest of witches, huh?
And you're absolutely sure that there are no witches now.
I haven't heard of any coming back.
Mm-hmm.
So you're not absolutely sure that there are no wedges.
Where's Moomey and her still in bed?
He was off before you woke up, Papa.
Hmm.
Oh, the golden fish.
Good morning, dear.
I wanted to go with them.
But you're writing your memoirs you're far too busy.
And that's very true, with the thought of the fish that no one has seen.
That might have been a whole chapter.
Do you think they'll catch it?
No, I doubt it very much. It's highly unlikely.
In that case, you should have gone with them.
No, I do know a thing or two about fishing.
Snuffkin does too, but he's still so young.
Oh, don't worry, I'm sure Snuffkin will manage.
Oh, this is a spooky forest.
Maybe the witch is every time.
Stop it, little mime!
Listen, everybody, don't stray away from me.
Promise, you might get lost. Oh, it's so dark in here.
Sure, Razz, and so thick the sun can't get through.
That's because of those clouds.
I can hear the wind, but we need calm. That's because of those clouds.
I can hear the wind! But we need calm.
Yes, but we also need heavy rain.
You're right. That's what the Hemiellin said.
It sure looks like rain.
Not only looks like...
Oh, it's raining!
Here. Oh, thank you.
My God, I say this rainstorm was very sudden. Don't worry, it won't last that long.
How do you know that?
Vagabons do.
This rain isn't that heavy.
No, it's not bad, but we better hurryer.
We won't get to the lake till noon, and that'll be too late.
I don't think we'll get very wet down here, Mum.
So why don't we move on?
You're so excited.
What should we do? It's nothing so why don't we move on? You're so excited.
What should we do, it's nothing.
Well, we could move on, couldn't we?
Yet! We really are getting too early. We better find some shelter quickly.
About where can we shelter?
There's nothing in this wood-exec tree.
On your tree, then, again.
Yeah!
What is it, Snorke, Nathan?
There's a house over there.
It's fallen to wreck and ruin. Well, at least it'll keep the rain off. Hello there.
Anyone home?
There's lived here for a long time. I wonder who could have been lived here all alone.
Huh?
I know who it was.
And so do we all.
Don't we?
It's your lady.
Don't we? I know who it was, and so do we all.
He sure is, don't mean.
The witches, of course.
Look around for dried spices, magic herbs,
brown sticks, and a black cat, a niren pot, a pile.
But now, cruel!
No, the witch rode away on it.
Oh!
There's someone here.
Who is it?
Let's get out of here.
Can't come over there.
No, don't. That's okay, Snuffkin. We gotta get out of this place.
Hmm.
I can't move, Snuffkin. Stinky? Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, I'm so proud of Snip the faint when he hears my voice. Where are you after anyway?
Oh, come on, tell me. Can't you even take a joke? Come on, wait for me.
That way. Okay. Come on. Okay.
Come on.
Come on. Come on. This is it, isn't it? Yes it is. Where's the golden fish? I really don't know.
I've never seen it either.
I've never seen it either. I've never seen it either. I've never seen it either. I it? Yes it is. Where's the golden fish? I really don't know.
With rain, sunshine and calm,
I'm sure the fish will come.
The golden fish?
Help me catch it!
I just gotta have that golden fish!
Now! Oh! I can't see any fish anywhere. Maybe it was Hemiellin's idea of a very funny joke.
The Hemiellin doesn't joke. Let's sit down and wait.
I'm sure the golden fish will appear for us.
I don't believe it. Do me the say you came all this way here just to see some stupid old fish.
I came to catch it.
Well, that's even more stupid.
Hey, stop making those ripples.
Uh, I'm going to say you came all this way here just to see some stupid old fish. I came to catch it.
Well, that's even more stupid.
Hey, stop making those ripples.
Eh.
So they really got excited and walked all the way, you say?
Oh, to be young again.
Well, I would have gone with them if I hadn't over slept.
I didn't know that you were that young woman, Papa.
Oh, I'm not exactly old, you know.
Pretty interesting to see a fish that hardly anyone's ever seen.
Snipset that he would catch this golden fish
if it's the last thing he did.
Oh, how?
Well, he had a net and a very large bucket to carry at home, then.
That's a good one. What do you mean? and a very large bucket to carry at home, then. Hmm, can't see it from up here. Hmm, oh, the hemulin was certainly right.
Hardly anyone has seen this golden fish
and we're not gonna see it either.
Maybe somebody ate a mure's ago.
Stinky be quiet, please.
Oh!
Huh!
Did you see it?
Where did you see it?
Huh!
I saw a fish jump, but I couldn't tell if it was golden. It was much too far away.
With the sun over there we just see the outlines, Nork Maiden.
Yes, we couldn't really see the color. Look everybody, look! I can see a raft over there!
Hey, let's take it and go out to the middle of the lake.
But it's much too small for all of us.
Don't worry, Sniff, this won't sink.
I'm staying.
You do what you like, but you'll never catch any fish
if you're afraid of water.
Stinky, you can help me. It's gold, you know.
We can sell it for a lot of money
and then we'll both be very wealthy.
I think it was somewhere around here, wasn't it?
Or, alas, I suppose, hard to say.
Well, I can't see anything.
I can't see!
There's certainly no sign of it now.
Well, we'll just have to sit and wait here.
We have no choice.
And I'm not going home until I've seen it.
I'm happy to wait all day.
You won't find it by looking up at the sky.
You know what?
Fish like it in places where there are lots of wings.
Oh, the rafts in the middle of the lake.
They just want to see the fish, but you wait. I'm going to catch it.
Maybe somebody's already caught it and you can get it in a tin.
Huh?
What? Did you see that?
Over there! Something shiny jumping!
What did you see? That's all it did! Now keep quiet!
I hate fishing. Guess we better think about getting back otherwise we'll never get home before nightfall.
I don't want to get lost on a raft in the dark on this lonely lake.
Perhaps we were expecting too much.
Maybe your right's not made in, but I really thought we'd see it.
This is the most disappointing day of my life.
We can come back.
Yes.
It's not gonna stop.
Hang on. Did you see a moment? Shh. Oh.
It's gigantic. I'm not going to die. Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh it! First, it was I believe about it! So great!
Thank you, man!
Oh, that was great!
I really saw it!
I saw it!
First, it was I believe about it!
So great!
Thank you, man!
Oh, that was great!
I really saw it! I saw it! First, it was I believe about it! Oh!
Got it! Got it!
Got it!
Hey, I'm home in!
I did it! I caught it!
God, what?
Why the golden fish and horse?
What?
I've got the golden fish in here if you want to have a look at it.
See, it's in this bucket.
You don't really believe that is the golden fish.
It's just another stupid fish. I can swear that it really was golden when I caught it.
It must have been the sun making it land in the water.
It was you said it was the golden fish.
Why don't you let it go?
You know it's not the right one, and he hates it in that bucket.
Huh?
Hmm...
There he goes.
It looks so happy now.
It really was gold when I first saw it.
We believe you, Sniff.
Now let's go home.
Steph and Stinky never really got over their belief that it was actually the golden fish they had caught.
But moving in the others were in no doubt about what they had seen.
They and the emulators were great friends. We're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The moments are having fun day after day
The movements, the movements, the movements The Moons.