Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
They are the movements, they are the
movements, so come with me give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment
land, you can fly just like a bird, sing was a moment, there was a moment, there was a moment, there was a moment La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la Ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba With all the excitement of that night, Sniff decided not to go home and was sharing
Moomin's bed.
Snuffkin, as always, preferred to sleep in his tent.
You remember what happened?
The horrible greek coming after thingamy and bob
and everything freezing?
For a moment, however, the night wasn't quite over yet. Mommy, papa! Help me! The girl gets after me!
I can't run anymore! Oh, oh! Sniff!
Morning, Mama! Good morning, Moomin.
Is Sniff up yet?
Huh, you're joking.
Where is the thing on the mampon?
They haven't stirred yet.
The poor things are tired out.
Papa's not still asleep, is he? No, he's looking at my rose bushes.
Are they okay, Papa?
No, frozen to death and look.
What?
That's where she was standing over there with a grass is dead.
She must have been real cold to freeze the roses.
What a shame, they were very pretty.
Well, there's not much left of them now.
We'll have to grow some new ones.
I dreamed that she was chasing me, Papa.
Oh, don't worry, moment.
I think she's only after thing of me and Bob.
So there are not fugitives from justice after all?
I have a feeling that they would prefer that moment.
Aren't thing of Ian Bob coming down?
Yes, if they could have breakfast in their room if you didn't mind.
Well, what did they tell you?
What? About why the greek is chasing them.
Oh, they just looked terrified and wouldn't say anything
about her at all.
You know, we really ought to find out why.
Yes, you're right.
Mum and Mum, why don't you take their breakfast up
and see if they'll tell you anything
if any of us can get it out of the mukeh.
Who's that?
It's only me. I've brought you both a nice breakfast. Well, what did they say?
It seems that the greek is after the suitcase, not them.
I wonder what's in it! Perhaps they've stolen her mummy as well!
And they also said that it did use to belong to her.
Oh dear, if they've stolen it...
I don't know about that.
I asked them how they got it, but they wouldn't say another word.
Well, this is too much.
We could be harboring criminals.
I know they don't look like it, but you never know, do you?
You can ask the girls!
Shh! Don't shout!
No, that's no good.
We don't want to come back here most definitely.
Let's ask the police inspector to question them.
We don't want to get the police involved. Well, you'll suggest something, Anne. Quint, shouting, sniff.
Look, why don't you just wait for them to tell you, Moomin?
I know it seems strange, but I've noticed that if you pretend not to be interested,
people can't wait to tell you those secrets.
They told Mama about the suitcase, but they wouldn't say anything to Papa.
You know something, Moomin. People can't wait to tell you their secrets. They told Mama about the suitcase, but they wouldn't say anything to Papa.
You know something, Moomin?
They might open up to Snork Maiden.
She's someone more their own age.
You could be right.
Hey, Snork Maiden!
Where are you going?
Moomin house.
I'll come with you.
But I thought you were living there.
I was until mumble came back yesterday.
How is she?
Bossie, and she snores too.
Woman!
Snorke maiden.
Where are you off to?
Well, I was just on my way to see you.
Oh, that's so nice, and I've come to see you, Moomin.
I brought you a little present, Moomin.
A present for me.
Yes, and it's very beautiful.
What is it?
Something you must never break or lose.
I promise I won't.
There you are.
Thank you.
Go on, open it.
A lot of beautiful shell!
I spent all of yesterday on the beach searching for it, just for you.
Look, we can see ourselves in it.
So we can!
Thank you very much, Snorkmade, it's my heart, and I want you to look after me.
Oh, I will, Snorkmade, and I will.
I'll think of you whenever I look at it.
I'll move in.
I promise you that I'll always kiss the shell
before I go to sleep.
It will be my most precious treasure.
Apart from me?
So what shall I do?
Take them for a walk?
Yes, but take your time and don't rush them.
I'll let them cry on my shoulder.
Yes, and try and talk to them as well, though.
I feel very important and a little bit nervous, too.
Have some tea first.
Thank you, Mum and Mama.
Ah!
We don't need your help, Little My. Ha, that's what you think.
I'd be able to weedle out their secrets.
It's not an interrogation.
We only want to talk to them, you know?
So you can weedle out their secrets.
I'll be very quiet.
Little My, have you ever managed to be very quiet?
Not really, but there's only one way to find out.
You must let me go with Snork Maiden.
No, this situation needs a tender understanding, one.
That's me, exactly!
You ready? I suppose so.
Hello, it's Moomin. Can I talk to you for a minute?
Hello? This is Snorth Maiden. She's a very good friend of mine.
Hello, I'm very happy to meet you both.
She's very tender and understanding and she'd like to talk to you. Can she come in?
Well, if she has to, moment.
Come in, then.
Yippee-yippee-yippee-yippee.
It's very beautiful, a perfect heart shape.
I've never seen anything like it, moment.
Would you like one, Mama?
No, my dear. There should only be one shell like this.
Then would you keep it somewhere safe for me?
Well, self-kin.
I'm sure Snorkmaiden will get it out of him.
I do hope so. I think they like it or anyway.
I have a feeling in my bones that Groke will be back tonight.
Oh.
If we could find out why she's after them, we'd know what to do.
Mama won't have any garden left if that monster comes back every night.
Moment.
Hmm? Move it. Move it. Huh? Well done.
Snork maiden.
Little Mai!
Oh no, she'll ruin everything if we don't stop her.
If you win the fear, I'll be the one who will be the one who will be the one who will
ruin the fear.
I'll be the one who will be the one who will be the one who will be the one who will be the one who Oh no, she'll ruin everything if we don't stop her.
If you win to fear a little, my I'll never forgive you.
What? Interfear? Me? Never.
Look, let's just leave it up to snork maiden now, little my.
You'll need me of snork maiden that tend to and understanding enough.
Hey, moment!
So, how is snork maiden getting on her taking them for a stroll? and understanding enough. Hey, moment!
So, how is Snorkmaiden getting on her,
taking them for a stroll?
Where are they?
If we were narrow...
Papa, if we get much closer...
And the last thing we want is for them to see us.
Looks like I'll have to go and talk to them. You're all too big.
I'll come back later and tell you what they said.
No, don't. You'll upset Snorkmaiden.
You're the one who's upsetting her!
Shh!
All right. Can I ask you again about the suitcase?
Yes!
Does that suitcase belong to you or is it the Groaks?
No!
Yes!
Let's try it another way.
Who's is that suitcase?
It's ours, it's ours!
But you told Mum and Mama that it wasn't yours?
It was the Groaks!
Yes, we did!
Oh... that it wasn't yours? It was the Groakes! Yes, we did!
Oh, do you mind if I ask you one more time?
Please do!
Right, here we go.
Now all I want is a simple yes or no.
Is that suitcase yours or not?
No, yes!
Oh, take your time, Snorkmaine, and don't rush them, he said.
What was that, Snorkmaine?
Look, I'm sorry, but can I ask you again?
Yes, as many times as you want.
Thank you. This is the very last time, so please tell me the truth.
Now then, the suitcase. Yes, you know which one? Yes. Does it belong to you? Yes, it does.
So it's not the Grookes. Yes, it is not the Grookes. At last we're getting somewhere, praise the
booble. We're very happy for you. Snork maiden is really having to work hard. I wouldn't have, I'd scare them into talking.
You should have let me go.
Yeah, but we wanted someone gentle.
Snork maiden is nice.
Everybody in this house is nice.
Do you think they'd let us stay here forever?
Of course. If we can keep away from the grog.
Mm-hmm.
It took a long time, but in the end they trusted me,
and now we're good friends.
Who wouldn't trust you and want to be good friends?
Thank you.
It wasn't easy, though. They kept speaking together,
and I got rather muddled.
But they did tell me somehow.
Rather muddled. I told you, guys, you should've let me do it.
Oh, I'm afraid I didn't get very much, though. I knew you guys you should let me do it. Oh I'm afraid I didn't get very much though.
I knew you wouldn't.
So what did you find out then, Snork Maiden?
Tell us.
Well, first of all, the suitcase does seem to be theirs.
That was one thing they made very clear.
Lennel can the grog.
Just a minute, Moomin.
What's in the suitcase on the other hand belongs to the grog.
That's the problem.
Oh dear, so they do have something belonging to a...
Well, Snork Maiden, what is it?
They wouldn't tell me what it is little my,
only that it is the most beautiful thing in the world.
How is it?
I wonder.
This is very difficult to understand.
I mean, thingy and bob don't look like thieves at all, do they?
So, the gropes just wanted back what is hers?
I don't see how that big ugly monster could own the most beautiful thing in the world.
Well, what they said was that she just happened to have it.
They didn't say whether it belonged to her or not.
So she might have stolen it herself.
They shouldn't have taken it, though.
Oh dear, oh dear.
Bob and Thingamy are very frightened
of how she'll take her revenge if she catches them.
But they're very determined to keep what's
in the suitcase, Moomin, Papa.
Oh, this is a fine mess, indeed.
The gropes should have come back tonight.
What can we do?
What can we do? What can we do? What can we do?
We can do the same as before.
Yeah, but it's not fair to drive her away.
If what's in the suitcase really does belong to her?
She means to get the suitcase
and I don't think it will be so easy to get rid of her this time.
And if she stays, we'll have a never-ending winter.
Well, I'll cover up the petunias just in case.
Are you all going to stay here?
I'll look after Snork.
I will, Mum and Mama, I'll stay.
You'll stay, won't you, Snuffkin?
Don't look so clam, everyone. I've got an idea.
But it would help if we knew what was in that suitcase.
But even if we didn't, it could still work.
Uh, what is it, dear?
Just wait, Papa. You'll see.
Ha-ha-ha. I Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, I hope women Papa can do something.
It's your girl, little mom. Yes, I know.
There's the king and the queen.
Uh, this one?
Uh...
Uh-oh, uh-oh, she's coming.
Just when I was winning.
You better hide under the table, little mom.
Don't be stupid.
How can I hit her with my roll and pin from there.
Where is she, Papa? Exactly where she was yesterday.
I'll go for a toast, alright, Papa?
Let me go first, and then the rest of you can fan out behind me.
Moment, Mama.
What is it, papa?
Perhaps now's the time to tell us your idea.
We haven't long.
Wait, Grog. Don't go know. We want to talk to you.
We know that you've come back to get what thing of me and Bob took from you.
That is right, isn't it?
Won't you let them keep it, perhaps?
No, we'll you sell it to them?
Oh, dear.
I have some very beautiful things here in my bag.
Maybe you'd like to trade, Groke.
What about this pendant? Isn't it lovely? So you don't like that? What about this then?
Or this?
Oh. Or this?
Oh. All right. Why don't you choose?
Take anything you want from my handbag, except the hair slide.
Which one do you want, this one? Let me see with this.
Oh, this one?
Oh, dear, that's not really mine to give to you.
Snork maiden gave that to Mumen.
Is it all right if I give the shell to her
Mumann? Oh Mum! You'll never allow! Are you all right? Yes, my hand was suddenly frozen.
No, you've got the shell Mrs. Groke. Do you promise not to come back anymore? Because I'll get you if you do!
Well, that was a close thing. I'm glad that's over.
Oh, you were marvelous, Mama.
I'm so sorry, Moomin.
I forgot that I had put your precious shell in my handbag to keep it safe.
It's all right, Mama. You gave it in a good cause.
What snorkman gonna say, Moomin?
I heard you. You said you'd never go to sleep without kissing it.
Or something equally stupid.
Well, I'm not gonna tell Snork maiden,
but I think Mama did the right thing.
She'll find out. I'm fed up with secrets.
I'm always gonna tell the truth from now on, no matter what. Oh!
Oh!
Mumin, Mumin! Look! I found one! Really?
Well, it's very similar, but the one snort maiden gave me was much bigger.
Oh, a lot bigger, was it?
Mumen had decided that he had to find a shell that was exactly the same as the one snork
maiden had given him.
Then with luck, she would never find out what he'd done with it.
Oh.
Oh. Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, I'm sorry. Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm sorry. Valley, miracles do happen.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements You're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes and played
The movements are having fun day after day
The movements
The movements The moment, the moment, the moment.