Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
They are the movements. You can fly just like a bird, sing the best song ever.
There were the moments, there were the moments, there were the moments.
There were the moments, there were the moments.
There were the moments, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement Ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba It was a lovely day and Mumen, his family and friends decided to go for a trip in the
boat they'd found washed up on the beach.
They didn't know where they were going, and thought it would be much more fun that way.
Mama, we're not going away forever, you know.
I hope not.
I don't think we'll need all these pots and pans.
It's best to be prepared at sea.
What do you mean?
Well, you're only complaining if you don't get a hot meal.
I never complain.
And you know how hungry the sea air made you all last time we went out on a boat.
You'd have been glad of food then.
Hmm, you got to rough it a bit if you want an adventure.
Yes, but it will be more fun with coffee and pancakes.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, pancakes. Aren't you too ready yet?
Hello, Mummian! Hi, Snorkvagan!
Whoa!
Oh!
Oh! Whoa!
Ugh! Ugh!
Ugh!
Must you use that ladder?
I'm all right!
Mom, and you're gonna hurt yourself one of these days!
It's good practice!
Is Snork coming with us?
He says he hasn't got time for sailing boats at the moment.
I'd much rather a real sailing boat than a paper flying ship any day.
Are mom aren't Papa ready yet?
They're packing a path the kitchen.
Oh, it's too full.
Have we got to take all that with us?
Mama thinks it's better to be safe than sorry, and she's usually right.
Tell me, Moomin, where exactly are we going?
We haven't decided yet.
That's right. Wait and see. Oh, Mr. Hamillin! Oh! Have you found a rare plan for your collection yet?
Unfortunately not.
There are lots of things to do.
I'm not sure if I can find it.
I'm sure I can find it.
Mr. Hamillin!
Oh! Have you found a rare plan for your collection yet?
Unfortunately not.
There are lots of these in Mumen Valley already.
Goodness, where are you taking all that?
We're going sailing.
How exciting, charting new seas and exploring desert islands.
I have an owl.
If I help you load up the boat can I please come with you?
Captain the bridge! Man the yard arm!
Hankers away! Sailors beware! Spice the manbrace! All hands on deck! Full speed ahead!
Hey Sniff, any son of the mule? Not yet. It's a great day to go sailing. I wonder where we're going.
I don't have any idea. I don't actually like sailing much.
Do you get sick?
Well, not really sick. It's just that I can't swim.
And if it's rough, it frightens me and I panic a bit.
It looks like it's going to stay calm.
So don't worry.
Right, that's the lot.
Now, all aboard.
Mama, little Mai,
Stafkin,
Mumin,
Snork Maiden,
and Mr. Hambylin' of course.
Isn't he a bit old for adventures?
Not at all.
No, Mumin Papa has promised to find a deserted island
where I shall search for rare plants. Oh, there's no room. Don't be silly, sniff, of course there is.
It looks very full, almost thinking.
There's no way this boat could sink.
Now come on, get in.
Oh. It looks very full, almost thinking. There's no way this boat could sink.
Now come on, get him.
Oh.
Really?
I promise it'll be all right.
Won't it, Papa?
Well, if it stays like this, it will, moment.
I'll come next time.
Let's go, moment, Papa. He's just a scary cat.
Hmm. We'll go without woman, Papa. He's just a scary cat.
Mm.
We'll go without you then, Sniff.
I think that will be best.
Anyway, someone did better stay and look after Mom and House,
and it might just as well be me.
That's very thoughtful of you.
There's a pancake on the kitchen table
that you can have for lunch.
Thank you, Mom and Mama.
Have a nice trip.
I wish Nuford come. He's a big softy.
Well, he's not very good at swimming,
and he doesn't eat rather a lot. This is the life, isn't it, Mama? It certainly is, dear.
Oh, look, not a breath of wind. Shall I start rowing, Papa?
Yes, you'd better get snuffkin' to help you.
Aye-aye, Captain.
Tardly moving! You'll have to do better than that.
We're doing our best.
You two would be useless as galley slaves. It's good that we're not then, isn't it?
So then, what's your excuse?
It's not easy rowing against the tide. You try it.
No, dear, at this rate, I should be lucky to find one rare plant.
Well, Mr. Hamlin, you could always try collecting some seaweed instead. There's plenty of that.
I have heard tales that if you whistle, those who perished at sea will send you a wind.
Land! A Hoi! Look, Moomin, Papa!
That's too small to be any good.
You're right. Hey, look, Papa! We're moving again!
The tides turned and the winds up.
What a beautiful island!
And a perfect place to land, too.
Oh, I bet this place has got some rare plants.
Be careful when you explore. There could be wild animals there.
Now if someone will go and collect some wood, I'll get a fire started.
I've had none of you will say no to coffee and pancakes.
Watch me, you land lovers. I'll go and pull the boat ashore.
Hmm, I suppose you will ride. This will come in handy. As I said, Papa, it's always better to ruff it with a little bit of luxury.
I wonder if we're the first to set foot on the island.
Thank you, children.
Is there anything else you want us to do?
No, I don't think so.
Is it okay if I go explore the island?
Of course, off you go.
Coming, Snort made up.
I'll stay and help Mum and Mama with the cooking.
Mama, you said we needed firewood, is this enough?
My goodness for a lot.
You know, I don't think anyone lives on this island.
I haven't seen anyone unless they're hiding in the bushes.
I've seen someone.
Oh yeah? Who?
Well, they weren't very big.
What do you mean? This big? Well, they weren't very big. What do you mean?
This big?
Well, same as me.
What did they look like?
Sort of white and ghostly and not very friendly looking either, Moomin.
Well, you probably just thought you saw something a little mic.
I did see them. I did too!
Keep your hair on.
I'm not saying you didn't see anything.
Goodness, this is magnificent. Oh, what a find!
And what's this? Yes. Oh, well, well, well, well.
I've never seen such rare and beautiful plants.
Huh?
Whoa.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Well, what's this? Goodness, it's a barometer. Now let's see.
Rain and storm. Probably broken.
Oh, hello. Who are you?
Oh, I see. This is your barometer, isn't it? Now watch it.
Mind you don't travel on those flowers, will you?
Oh, no, no, no, no. They're coming to get me. Don't go away. Don't go away.
I think what little my saw was a haddy fatner.
They're not ghosts. Are they? Snuff can?
No, they look kind of like it, but they're really harmless enough movement.
Oh, leave me alone!
Oh, dear, what on earth was that?
It sounded like Mr. Hamulin! Don't get away, oh, oh, oh, baby, please. That's it! That's what I saw! It's Mr. Hamulin.
Help! Get me down!
Why are they after you, Mr. Hamulin?
What'd you do to them?
I don't know! I just tapped on this post and asked them to be careful with the flowers.
They seem a bit angry to me.
Well, then I tapped the marombin in the tent.
I'm going to get you a little bit more. I don't know. I just tapped on this post and asked them to be careful with the flowers.
They seem a bit angry to me.
Well, then I tapped the marrometer to check the weather and they came at me.
Well, I don't think it's a flower's a mad about.
Maybe they thought you were trying to steal the marrometer.
I don't want it to keep it.
My goodness, I'm collecting flowers, not marrometers.
Well, hang on.
I can't hang on much longer, hurry, please.
They don't look so easily frightened.
No, now let me think.
Hurry, I'm slipping.
I've got it, Mr. Hemmulin.
The hadifattoners can't see or hear very well,
but they are very sensitive.
We'll have to try and frighten them.
I suggest you shake the post as hard as you can
Harder harder mr.
Look they can feel the ground moving keep going mr. Hemmielin
Are you sure this will work Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. I'm getting really tired. Her big sausage, if I can't. They're not going, self-kin.
Are you sure this will work?
Yeah.
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
You can stop now, Mr. Hemmilen.
Mr. Hemmilen!
Oh, dear!
Hey, are you all right, Mr. Hemmilen?
What disgusting creatures!
I have a good mind to take their precious barometer.
I don't think that's such a good idea.
It's no good anyway. It's not working.
How do you know that, Mr. Hemmulin?
Look, it's a beautiful day, isn't it?
But according to this barometer, it should be pouring down with rain.
This is the way to explore real home cooking.
It just takes a little thought.
And woman papa is always prepared, aren't you dear?
Double zero. It can't get any lower than that.
What does that mean?
If it was working, it would mean we'd be in for a terrible storm.
Hmm. I think the reading might be right after all, Mr. Hemmulun.
See the way the sky is darkening.
Look at those storm clouds. We better go before it's too late.
But there won't be time to get home. We'll be shipwreck moving, Papa.
Surely there's still time.
We don't want to go back to Moomin Valley yet. We've only explored half the island.
Besides, you never know what we might find, Snort Maiden.
I wanted to get my hands on those haddy fat nurse!
That's the last thing I wanted to do little mind, the very last!
I think we ought to leave now.
What do you think, Mama?
Well, you're the captain, dear. It's up to you. So I am. Now, let you think mama well you're the captain dear it's up to you so I am now let me think Oh, can we? Yes, but we must put the tent up before it starts raining. What tent?
Always be prepared.
That's my motto.
You're very clever to think of everything.
First, we must lower the sails and pull them up.
Oh, can we?
Yes, but we must put the tent up before it starts raining.
What tent?
Always be prepared.
That's my motto.
You're very clever to think of everything.
First, we must lower the sails and pull the boat up so that she's out of harm's way. Oh!
That should do it! Oh!
Well done, everybody.
It should be safe here.
Now hurry with the tent, the storm's nearly here.
Are you all right, Mr. Hemmulan?
You stay here and rest, eh?
We'll manage without you.
I am a bit tired.
You get your breath back first, but don't forget to tie the boat to that tree before you come up.
It looks bad. A real humdinger.
You can trust me.
Right, let's get that tent up.
Oh, dear, what a day! Oh dear, what a day! Oh dear, what a day! Oh dear, what a day!
Oh dear, what a day!
Oh dear, what a day! Oh dear, what's this here?
Oh, yes! Well, fans, see that I've never seen one of these before.
Snuffkin?
What's happening? It's coming good. What's happening?
It's coming really fast.
Look at the rain over the sea.
We're gonna get soaked if we stay here.
Just a minute.
But we'll get wet.
I know, but it's so exciting.
Things which you have no control over.
You can see this great big storm coming towards you,
and you can't do anything about it.
No.
You have to time it just right.
When to make a run for shelter, you mean?
I knew you'd understand.
I wonder what the haddy Fatterners are doing.
Waiting for the thunderstorm.
Why?
Because they get energy from the electricity and the lightning.
Really?
That's it!
Come on! I've never seen rain like this. It'll be over soon enough, Momen. You're dressed, Mom.
I know.
It's all right.
I'll look after you.
I know.
I know. I know. Oh!
It's all right.
I'll look after you. The That was a close one. Too close. I think it's over, Snork Maiden.
I think it's over, Snork Maiden.
That was a close one. Too close. I think it's over, Snork Maiden.
What a find I made today!
What a find I made today! If, like the movements and their friends, you're stranded on the desert island in a huge storm.
All you can do is wait until it's blown itself out.
But what if the waves are so high that your boat has caught up and washed out to sea?
That is a different story altogether. They love the laughter and they love the living the moments
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the moments The movements. They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements. They love the living, the movements
We're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The movements are having fun day after day, the movements The Move is...
The Move is...