Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So, what do you think?
I'm going to say that I'm not going to say it. I'm going to say it. Here with me, here for you on your TV, they are the movements.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
There were the movements. There was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la The seeds that movement and his friends had found in a box that had been cast up on the
beach had grown into a tropical forest.
It was beautiful, but also dangerous,
with man-eating plants kept a bay by snuffkin playing as harmonica.
But for how long?
Oh dear. Oh!
Snuffkin, don't stop playing your harmonica whatever you do, or they'll only get angry and attack us all over again.
If I don't stop soon, I might never want to play again.
Well, perhaps the music has made them more friendly.
Be careful, Mr. Hemmullen. Oh, don't worry.
Mr. Hemmullen and look out! What? Oh, oh, oh, oh!
I want him.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
I don't think the quickly stuck in play again! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
Ah! Papa, we must make sure the trap door won't open again. Ah, yes. What's this about a trap door?
In the kitchen. They almost got him before in the tag mama. We reached her just in time.
Ah, there they are. I feel sorry for them. It can be helped, Snuffkin. If we let them out, we'll be...
It's no life.
It makes me feel very uncomfortable...
having man-eating plants under the floor.
Oh, I see.
I feel sorry for them.
It can be helped, Snuffkin.
If we let them out, we'll be...
eating a life.
It makes me feel very uncomfortable... having man-eating plants under the floor. Now, we'll be... it in a life!
It makes me feel very uncomfortable having man-eating plants under the floor.
Always keep a kettle of boiling water
and in case they break through.
The children are playing Tarzan.
They might as well, seeing as they've got a jungle to play in.
Still, planting those seeds might have been a terrible mistake.
Well, mama, I'm very glad that you did.
Just think what I would have missed.
And, moment, valley suddenly being full of tropical plants
is wonderful.
I'm not fond of traveling, as you know.
And you've brought the plants to me.
Well, the trees make it much cooler.
But those man eaters.
I could do without them.
Oh!
You're just like Tarzan.
Tarzan loves Jane.
Oh, what bliss!
I knew it!
Stinky's over there.
Stinky.
Tarzan, teach old Betty lesson.
Yaaah!
Ah!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
Pretty stupid moment playing Tarzan without wild animals. Animals don't come from seeds. Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, Maybe it's chimpanzee. I know exactly what you need.
Cheese.
Bread.
Ah.
What are you doing, Mama? Well, I don't like the thought of all those man-eaters still in the cellar.
So your father and I are going to sleep in the bathhouse.
We'll sleep outdoors too. We've just built ourselves a hut.
Snork maiden and little Mai too.
Yes, there's plenty of room.
All right, so that only leaves Mr. Himmelon sleeping in the house.
And he still busy checking all the different plans.
Mama, is everything ready?
Oh, yes, dear.
Oh, aren't we ready?
Yes, we are, Mr. Himmungen.
See you later.
Stinky said he could get some wild animals, Papa.
We're ever fro.
I don't know.
I wouldn't trust him. He'll probably put a hedgehog in your sleeping bag.
There it is. The hunt.
Oh, oh, that very well built. I'm not sure if I can get a chance to see the other other
other
other other other I tell you, it's a wonderful place. You'll love it. A real tropical jungle. Are you sure it's quite nice here?
Well, of course, there you are.
Oh. Oh, lovely it is to run free. Darling, let's be the first to get to Moomin Valley. Eh. Eh. Eh. Soon I'll have the largest collection in the botanic world,
and I will be famous, and people will come from all over.
Now what have we here?
Go away, I'm not a zoologist.
Look, Moon. Those must be the monkey stinky promise to us.
Well, that's a surprise. Not like him at all. I just don't trust him.
What sweet things!
Just like in Tarzan.
Huh?
What was that?
I don't know.
Huh?
That sounds like some really wild animal, a lion or a tiger.
I'm frightened, movement.
Huh?
Very odd, just like home, isn't it?
Even if it isn't very big.
Perhaps we could live here.
Let's go hunting first, ice mill, humans.
Or be careful, darling. You're very out of practice.
I must warn them.
See anything?
No other thing. It must have been imagination.
Run man!
Keep quiet!
Little Maw!
I've just seen some tigers.
They're coming to get you!
Tigers!
Let's get back to the house quick!
There's no time!
They're nearly here!
We'll go to the bathhouse!
Shall we eat him up? You know that Hamilins upset your tummy, dear, Est?
I wonder where the movements are.
Huh?
Ah, just more animals that's all.
Papa! Papa, help!
What's the matter, Mumin?
Little Maya's seen two tigers and they're looking for us.
Tigers after us.
That rotten stinky probably told them we're good to eat or something.
Maybe we are.
They'll be here in a minute.
Right, moment.
You go and find the biggest stone you can
and bring it back with you.
OK. This way.
Papa will this one do? Yes, that's perfect. Right, get into the bathhouse and it's wiggly now. Here they come.
Are you really going to eat them, Dearest?
Of course, my love. You see, I think they're hiding in that little house up there.
They've been very quiet if they are.
Huh, they're just too scared to move.
That's all.
Why's that stone there?
Whoa!
My darling! Hey, it worked Papa! Well of course, Mumann.
My husband is drowning.
Oh, I'm so sorry Papa we must help.
He was just about to try and eat us Mama.
I'm sure he won't do it again.
I suppose so, Mummyn. Hmm. I never thought I'd see the day. Moments rescuing a tiger.
Here you are, dear.
Tithe is tightly around him and we'll lift him out.
Thank you, mother. Oh, darling.
Why, you are right, my love.? What happened did we eat them?
No you were drowning and they rescued you!
Oh?
Now embarrassing!
Well they're in that cabin behind you if you still feel hungry but it was rather good of them to save you.
No my appetite's completely gone.
We'll come back here then and we'll go.
I'll just jump over.
What?
Oh.
What's the matter?
I can't remember how to jump.
We've been stuck in that zoo for too long.
Well, try and swim across, dear, East.
OK. the class dearest. Okay. Hmm?
We copped everyone.
The tigers are leaving.
I'm glad he didn't grow.
I knew they wouldn't be mean enough to eat us after saving him. Let's throw.
I knew they wouldn't be mean enough to eat us after saving him. Shall we jump in and swim back as well? It's not far.
Yes. I'll go first.
I want to go first.
Don't, little mind. Be careful, movement. Look over there.
Crocodiles!
Oh hurry up, moments!
Swim around the back and come up the ladder!
How can there be crocodiles in the sea? I thought they only lived in fresh water.
How are we going to get back to the shore now?
We'll have to wait for a boat to come past.
No, I'm afraid we'll have to think of something else, Mama.
We could be waiting for a wink or something for that to happen.
A whole week!
But we'll starve, all they'll find is our bones bleached, waiting the sun.
Don't worry, little my. Papa will think of something you'll see. I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back!
I'll be back!
I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back! I'll be back! I didn't fancy landing a sea monster.
Help! Someone help! Help anybody!
That's Mr. Hemmulin. Oh, the Tigers must be after him quickly! I never made you so cross. I just told you not to eat my plants. Let me in! Oh!
That fella's always been clumsy. We can't really help him.
No.
Oh.
Are you all right, Himmulan?
Oh, dear, I think so. What about you? Oh, yeah. Oh. Oh, you're right, Himmungen. Oh, dear, I think so.
What about him?
Oh, dear.
What are you doing, Irino?
Get stuck in your brando.
Oh, this is anew, and on me.
So I'm loose.
I can't think of any other way.
You have to be very careful, though.
I think you're tasting? Yeah, I think you're tasting. Yeah, I mean, you think you're tasting.
Ah, look where you're going.
It was you who brought all the animals in, wasn't it?
Yes, you're right.
That's what you wanted.
It's a jungle now.
I did a good job.
Oh, really?
Well, they're not wild animals at all.
They're quite friendly.
Friendly?
Ugh. They're quite friendly. Friendly! Uh... See what I mean? They make very good pets. Cute, aren't they? Ugh. Snake!
I'll stick where are you!
Why do you want?
The rhino and the tigers have become pets of the movement family.
You're not going to let that happen to you.
Well, are you?
I'm not.
Snake!
Snake, where are you?
Why do you want?
The rhino and the tigers have become pets of the movement family.
You're not going to let that happen to you.
Well, are you?
Snake!
Snake! Snake! Snake, where are you? Why do you want? The rhino and the tigers have become pets of the movement family.
You're not gonna let that happen to you.
Well, are you?
It's not.
I'll bring snorked maiden and movement here tonight.
There's no need to eat all of them just bite off their tails, alright?
Okay.
You'll be really amazed like I was.
It's big enough for both of you to sit on.
How lovely, a giant water lily.
I wonder if the seeds came from that box you all found.
Oh, I can't wait to see it.
Looking at the size of the jungle, there must have been an awful lot of seeds in that box.
I suppose the wind could have blown them anywhere.
Where's the giant water, Lily? Let's see now.
Uh, over there.
Oh!
How wonderful!
You see, I wish you'd learn to trust me.
I'm a very honest guy.
It's so soft and pink and beautiful.
How romantic to be on a boat made from a flower.
This is unbelievable. Our old box seems to have grown into a tropical swamp.
It's a lot nicer. Hey, stinky.
Stinky?
Oh.
I can't see him anywhere.
I wonder how far we'll float.
It's getting dark, moman.
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
Gotcha!
We must get away!
We're!
I don't know!
Yet?
Locke, there's the sea!
Put the crooked aisles!
Over there, Stark made them!
A boat!
Well, it's the only way we'll get away from this monster!
AHHHH!
UGH!
Keep going, Snork Maid. We're almost there.
Wait!
Mumin and Snorkmaid kept swimming as fast as they could.
They had a head start on the snake, but now he was catching up.
Even though movements are very good swimmers, unfortunately for them, so are snakes.
They love the laughter,
and they love the living, the movements.
Believe it is sharing and caring,
and giving the movements.
They're always happy, and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements, the movements, they love the laughter
and they love the living, the movements
We're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The Moons are having fun day after day, the Moves, the Moves