Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So, what do you think?
I think it's a good idea.
I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. Here with me, here for you on your TV They are the movements, they are the movements
So come with me, give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land
You can fly just like a bird
Sing that song ever, there were the movements
There were the movements, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la Now it's very nice to get letters, at least every now and then.
However, in Mumen Valley, they're rarely sent or received.
And yet they do have letter boxes and even postman.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, All in this time. What? Come on. This way, towards me. Come on.
Come on.
Oh!
So, my God!
I got him!
Did you take that hole?
Yeah.
No, weren't, didn't it?
All right.
Who's responsible for this?
Are you all right?
Did you take this hole, young woman?
Of course not.
Who was it then?
Hi, you I should have known.
Come here, you just wait.
Uh, hold on, Mr. Postman. Can I help my letter please?
Just you wait. The past is too late.
Here's a letter, Mama.
Hmm.
A goodness, a letter.
I think it's from Mumble. Oh, really?
Where's little my, Mum?
Well, she's um...
So, who's this letter from?
It's from my sister mumble, isn't it?
Oh, should I know?
She went on holiday to get away from me.
I bet she's coming back because she's missed all the fun.
She'd stay away if she had it in the sense.
This is the third time I've fallen into a hole.
Yes, I know.
But this is only the first time I've seen you do it.
What a horrible little child you are.
Artite.
Whoo!
Whoo, that was close.
Go on, fall off.
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! Go on, Fola! Whoop!
Whoop! Whoop! Whoop!
Come here, wait till I get my hands on you!
Mumble says that she's coming back.
She feels that she's ready to cope with Little My again.
Oh, that's good news, Mum and Mama.
I think that we should go and give her house a good clean.
Have you told Little My now Mumbles coming?
She'll be able to go home.
No, I expect the postman is still chasing her
around the garden.
Don't tell me why I don't want to know.
Mama, mama, is the letter from Mumbles?
What does she have to say?
Is she coming home?
And a few days later, Mumbles Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, That's Mum and Valley over there. It's not full of creepy crawlies, is it?
Not as far as I know.
Is there a house over there?
Maybe they have food, let's go.
Oh, that's Mum and House.
Oh!
Are you going to Mumomin Valley, too?
Yes, we got me red.
That's nice, so am I.
We can go together.
Your suitcase looks very heavy.
Would you like a hand with me?
No, no, no, no!
Okay.
Are they nice the people that live in that house?
Yes they are.
Could we stay there?
I'm sure you can.
My little sister is staying with them.
Follow me. I know the way. Shall we go?
What's the matter?
Nothing. We're following you.
All right.
Mumbo!
Hello. How are you?
Fine, you.
Jamnice, rest without me. Come on, everybody's waiting to see you.
Oh, by the way, I'm at two very small strangers who said they were coming here.
Coming here, mumble?
Yes, they're both the same size as little mine.
Both a bit odd and they're carrying a very large suitcase.
Right, I'd better make them up a small double bed then.
Thanks for the tea.
Now are you ready to come home with me now little my?
No, not yet.
We've got to go home and tidy the house.
It hasn't been aired for the whole winter.
It's all right, mumble.
I cleaned and swept the floors the other day and opened all the doors and windows.
Thank you very much. It must have been a relief to be asleep most of the time with Lamai's been staying with you.
They said they haven't been bored once since we woke up, and we've had a really good time together.
Isn't that right, Mumen?
Bye now.
Well, well.
What does well-well me, Papa?
Just that I might be able to hear myself think again now.
I know what you mean.
You're not thingin' me. No, it's your turn to be great. What if they scream when they see us?
But the lady told us they were friendly thingamy.
Go on, do it.
Excuse me?
No, no, no.
Oh, no.
Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no. Oh, no. Go on, do it.
Excuse me?
No!
Now, what's the matter with you two?
Don't forget your suitcase, will you? I'm so glad to see you, Mom! What are you doing there? Oh.
Well, nobody said that you did.
Then you haven't come to arrest us.
Have you?
Of course I haven't.
I've come to see the movement family.
It is our suitcase.
It is.
Of course it is.
Now if you come to see the movements too?
Hello?
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
Oh, there you are. I thought it was you.
Are you expecting these two guests, Smoomin Mama?
I think so. And they've got a suitcase, so they must be staying.
That's nice. You will stay, won't you?
Is it alright with you?
Of course it is. I'm Moomin' Mama.
I'm Dengany, and this is my friend Bob Moomin' Mama.
You're welcome. Come in and make yourselves at home.
I think it'll be okay, Dengany.
Careful! He must must have drive it!
They are a bit strange, aren't they?
Yes, definitely.
So, what can I do for you today, Inspector?
Oh, well, I heard that mumble was back from holiday, so...
Yes, that's right.
Oh, do you hear now?
No inspector, I'm afraid she's gone home with little Mai.
Oh, right.
I have to keep an eye on things, you know? Very important.
Who goes away? Who comes back?
Well, I'll say goodbye then, Mum and Baba.
I do believe he's fallen for mumble.
But has she fallen for him?
I wonder.
What if the new guests do he?
Looking scared mostly.
Who one, do one, do one. Here you are. I've emptied these drawers for you. There should be enough room. Thank you, Mormon.
Where should we put this suitcase? Let's see.
In this drawer?
Oh, the other place to hide too.
Oh look at this.
They made such a pretty bad boy's.
I like the movements. They didn't scream at all.
You still gotta be careful though. We've had some very strange people staying at our house, but I think these two are really weird.
Well, they're northerners.
I guess so, with names like Thingamy and Bob.
And that suitcase.
They look a lot like fugitives to me, Snuffkin.
And perhaps they're dangerous criminals on the run.
Do you want to see them?
Yeah, I wouldn't mind, movement. Oh.
Ah, there you are. What are they doing now?
No idea. I couldn't hear anything, so they must be asleep.
We think they're fugitives, Moomin Papa. They're probably on the run from the law.
Well, they are a bit funny about their suitcase.
Gold coins.
Stolen state secrets.
Arsonists. We better hide all the matches, Papa.
Public enemies, numbers one and two,
but they don't look like it, though.
How about some tea, Snuffkin, sniff?
Yes, please.
Any cakes as well? Oh
Bename Oh no! This suitcase is gone too! What am I gonna do? What am I gonna do? What am I gonna do? You wake already? What a nerfie you're doing under the bed!
It's the safest place!
Something's about to happen there! I can feel her coming.
That's what woke me up.
Don't be silly. She can't know we're here.
She can. And I know she'll be here tonight.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Hmm. It's very windy tonight, moment.
MMM. You windy tonight, moment.
Mmm, now chilly too, don't you think?
Mmm, oh, hello.
Did you sleep well?
Would you like some tea?
Hey, so that's them!
Don't worry.
These are good friends of mine.
Let me introduce you.
Sniff and snuff can.
And what's the matter?
She's coming! Yes, she is.
Well, who is my dear?
The girl. The girl.
Yes, she's terrible.
Who?
You know who she is?
Yes, I've never seen her, but I've heard she's a scary monster, all right?
Scary monster?
And this Grog is after you.
Yes, she is. Now don't you worry she'll think twice before she tangles with me.
We'll see.
If she's a scary monster.
Monster or not. If you're a guest in Moomin House, nothing will harm you.
Right everyone. Like all the doors and you two go to your room.
Thank you, Moomin Papa.
Nobody is going to get in here. I'm going to get in here. house nothing will harm you. Right everyone, lock all the doors and you two go to your room.
Thank you, Moran Papa. Nobody is gonna get in here. Well said. To Am's family, to Am's.
Ready for more tea, anyone? What's the matter? We're going to be attacked by a huge scary monster! Heavens!
You'd better get the frying pan, mama.
Oh, dear.
All right.
Has everyone got a weapon, huh? I'm going to get you. Well, it's midnight. I don't believe in that stupid grog. I hope you're right.
I hope you're right.
I hope you're right. I hope you're right.
She's coming. She's here.
Yes, she's very close now.
I'm going home.
This is silly. We can't wait up all night. Besides, I'm getting very sleepy.
It's up to you. Right. I'm going, man moment papa. Watch your back.
Yes, keep in the open. Huh you guys are only trying to frighten me.
Well, it won't work.
She's here. No, she's not. There are no such things as monsters.
Just a trap blowing a candle, though.
Hmm.
You see? There's nobody there.
Well, in that case, there's nothing to stop you going home, Sniff.
Hmm?
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
You think I'm scared? You're making it up. Come on, admit it. There aren't any...
Groakes!
Not at all. Well...
You see? There's no one here at all! Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh.
Oh.
Oh, be careful.
Watch what you're doing.
It's here.
Where?
Hey, right outside that door.
Big and black and horrible!
Right.
No, don't open it!
You'll get in!
Come on, everybody.
Well, there's nobody here, Sniff.
Are you sure?
I can't see anything. I must have scared that silly old Groc away, moment!
That will teach her to come sniffing around here, all right?
What the fash is?
WAAAAAAA!
Mm-hmm, Mrs. Groke, we'd like you to go home.
Now you just go on.
You're upsetting our guests.
And you're freezing my roses?
Yes, you big bully.
I'm sorry, but you really must leave.
Please go before I count to ten. Three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, nine and a half. Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Are you alright, Moomboma? Look at the ground!
It's all frozen! Help me, Dad!
Help me, Dad!
That's a Groke's voice!
It's cold!
Isn't it?
I don't think she'll be back tonight. It's cold, isn't it?
I don't think she'll be back tonight.
Let's all go in and have a hot drink.
The Groke didn't come back that night,
but what did she want in the movement house?
And will she return perhaps another night
when they're all asleep.
They love the laughter and they love the living,
the movements, believing in sharing and caring
and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements, believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes and played.
The movements are having moment, the moment.