Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So what do you think?
I think it's a good idea.
I think it's a good idea. I think it's a good idea. with me, therefore you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements,
so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land, you can fly just like a bird,
sing the best song ever, there were the movements, there was the movement
There was the movement, there was the movement
There was the movement, there was the movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la During the long winter in Mumen Valley, almost everybody living there, hybronates until the sunshine comes again in the spring.
But for some reason, Mumen and Little Mai woke up
in the middle of it and couldn't get back to sleep.
Ah, this is great.
I'm really starving, I hope there's lots.
Oh, this plenty left.
Mama thought she'd made too much this year,
but it's lucky for us she did.
I don't know what we'd have had to eat otherwise.
Shh.
They're still sleeping.
Well, at least you got me to play with Moonman.
Whoa!
Wow!
That was fun! What are you ever go, Moonman?
I'm probably a bit heavy for it. So get something else, dummy!
I might later. Anyway, I thought we were gonna see Tuteki.
Come on, I'll pull you.
Okay.
I know why you don't want to go-moo-man.
You're scared of sliding down from the top, aren't you?
No, of course I'm not.
Do you think he's not here? I wonder where she's gone to.
That's her over there, isn't it?
Oh, yeah, I think it is.
J-Mumin, she looks like she's sliding!
Slighting?
Yes, it's obvious. She's sliding, of course!
She's coming over!
What were you doing out there, Tiki?
Watching the sun go down.
It's the only place you can see it from.
I just caught it for it disappeared over the horizon.
Where did it go to?
It comes up again in the south and will probably shine on snuffkin.
Hey, Tiki, what are those things you got on your feet?
They're called skates, and they're the best thing possible
for moving across the ice quickly.
Just what I need.
Come on, show me how to do it.
Yes, okay.
That's great.
I'm gonna make myself some skates too.
It's not as easy as you think, little lie.
Pathetic.
Ianid is a sword and knife on your shoes
and that sounds easy enough to me.
You know, it's strange,
but I've got a funny kind of feeling
that there's someone else apart from us in the bathhouse.
Hmm, well there is.
Who is it?
Where are they?
Little Maya can't see them.
Huh, what do you mean I can't see them?
Where are they hiding in the cupboard?
No, they're invisible.
Look, I'll show you.
Oh, oh, there's something on my head! See, that's two of the schoomis. There are eight of them all together.
Now, don't walk on the line.
I didn't see any schoomis here in the summer.
Although, if they're invisible, I wouldn't have done.
No, probably not.
As in the summer when we come across new little animals
that we've never seen before,
we'll be able to see the little ones.
I don't know if they're invisible invisible, I wouldn't have done. No, probably not.
As in the summer when we come across new little animals that we've never seen before,
and who likes snuffkin, go away when the wind and snow comes.
Then when the days are shorter, and everyone else is hibernating, they come out,
and summer so shy they're invisible and dear.
I'm afraid I don't understand winter at all.
Well, of course you don't.
You moments have always slept through
and don't know very much about it.
Oh, I can't wait to tell Mum or Puppa about all this.
They'll be really amazed.
Moomin!
What is it?
We will wake up tomorrow, won't we, Moomin?
I'm sure we will. Why?
I just don't want to go on sleeping and sleeping until spring.
Well, we woke up today, so...
But we don't know about tomorrow!
No, of course not. We'll have to wait and see.
If we're awake, we'll know, and if we're asleep, then it doesn't matter.
Hmm.
Well, if I'm not awake, can you are, wake me up, okay, Moomin?
Yes, alright. Go to sleep now.
What if it's the other way around, Moomin?
Well, what if I wake up and you're still fast asleep?
I don't mind sleeping all winter. Now stop talking to me, my.
You'd better wake me up or else. Hey little mine. Huh?
Hey, little my! Where have you gone to?
Huh?
Oh!
Hello!
Well, well, wonderful place for skiing you've got here.
What are those funny things on your feet?
Hey, what? You're joking.
Huh?
You mean you really don't know what these are?
That's why I'm asking you!
Well, they're skis, didn't you see me come down?
Yes, I did. Can you slide on the ice with these and go just as fast?
Oh no, on ice you have to use skates.
What is that young lady?
Oh, it's a snowboard. You slide on the snow with it.
That's not bad, but it's only a silver tray, isn't it?
That's right, mister.
I'll teach you to ski.
No, thank you.
I'll learn by watching you.
Won't take me long at all.
I'm afraid skiing is not that easy, young lady.
Don't worry.
It won't be for me.
Everything is once I decide to do it. Oh, so you spend all year going where the snow is? That must be tiring. Not at all. Life should be a struggle.
This jam is really good. Does it always have to be winter, catch a struggle in spring and summer instead?
Well, no, that would be too easy. You could just sit back and relax. No, you've got to face up to the cold and exercise to keep warm.
That sounds very interesting, Mr. Brisk.
One clear cold bath a day keeps all those unnecessary thoughts away.
My own little poem.
What? You don't mean you swim in this weather, do you?
The water must be very close to freezing.
Well, the sea is a lot colder than that.
It is frozen.
Is there a river?
Yes, there is, but the water looks very, very cold.
Sounds just right.
Have you got any more of this wonderful jam?
It's delicious.
There's some more in the cellar, but we've got cranberry up here
if you'd like that.
No, thanks. This will do for now here if you'd like that. No thanks.
This will do for now.
I'd appreciate some after my daily swim.
It'll work up an appetite.
Oh!
Yeah!
This is great!
It's great!
It can hardly watch.
It makes me shiver all over.
Is everybody like you?
Where you come from?
I'm, of course, Mblynat.
Why did you come from?
I'm cross-moving that. Why did you join me?
No, thank you.
Hello? What are you two looking at?
Oh, hello, there, little dog. We're watching that madman down there
he looks like he's swimming moving valley is full of very odd people he's not from moving valley is a matter of fact how are you I'm sorry you and I'm looking
for my brothers I don't suppose you've seen them, have you? Your brothers, have you lost them?
Are they hibernating somewhere, do you think?
Oh no, not them. They never do that.
Well, everyone else in Moomabali is hibernating,
except little Mai here, now two tiki and the invisible mice,
me, oh, and that crazy person down in the river.
Whoa!
Oh, yeah!
Ah! Oh, ah! I'm a person down in the middle. Whoa! Yeah!
My brothers are up in the Lonely Mountains. Is that far from here?
No, not far.
Lonely Mountains!
I know there are wolves up there,
but I never heard of any dogs.
Well wolves and dogs are brothers, didn't you know?
Oh, you know, this tastes even better after an invigorating swim. That's my favorite jam, much nicer than cranberry.
Oh, I agree.
Ah, doggie, now don't you want your jam?
What?
No, you have it.
Ah, thank you.
Now, you look as though you're a bit worried about something.
Yes, I suppose I am.
Worried fat?
Put it out of your mind.
Why do you think your brothers are wolves?
Did someone tell you they were?
Of course they are.
Everyone knows that.
And besides, I can feel the wolf in me.
Well, you might feel it, but nobody can see it for a star.
Wolves are much bigger than you.
I want to go and find them and then we can all hell at the moon.
I've been practicing.
I can see why he wants to be a wolf but we'd better keep him here.
He could get her if he goes up there on his own.
You don't really want to live with wolves do you?
Oh I do very much.
Why don't you travel around with me, sorry you?
I've got little dogs.
They could be your brothers and sisters if you want.
Well, I don't know.
Look, I'm going to stay here in Moomin Valley for a while,
and we can become great friends.
You're going to stay here?
Oh, yes.
Marvelous slopes find swimming the most wonderful jam,
and I'll build myself an igloo.
An igloo?
You mean a house made of snow?
Yes, that's it exactly.
If it's alright with you,
I'll take this jam with me just to keep me going. Hello there. Can I borrow your spade for a minute, Mr. Brisk?
Of course. What for, my friend?
I want to break up this barrel.
Oh, that's easy. Allow me, little mind.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. How's that, young lady?
Oh, that's easy.
Allow me, little mind.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How's that that young lady?
Mr. Brisk really loves this gem. He can't stop eating it.
Well, it's very nice, Moomin. I can't imagine anyone not liking it.
Do you know how to ski to a tiki?
Well, of course I do. I just haven't done it yet.
Mr. Brisk says that he's gonna teach me.
Oh.
I can't move my legs tied up like this.
That's the whole point. You don't have to. You just move your skis. Easy as winking.
No! No! No!
First of all, you have to learn how to fall properly.
But if I learn to ski first, then I wouldn't fall.
Wee!
Ah!
Little my Husky too.
Well, they're just made from an old barrel.
You're so much more sophisticated.
Now, and then, Genese, and Lean Forward, are you ready?
I don't think I like this. It's too steep.
Can I practice on something a bit flatter?
Well, maybe next time. Now then, off you go!
Trying to start an avalanche, moving? You know, I think this hill is even steeper than the last one.
Nothing to worry about.
You've already mastered falling down, huh?
You go again.
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh, stop it, please!
You can do it yourself, just calm down.
Oh!
Oh, look at that!
Marbles, you need!
Please, someone stop me, please!
Oh! Oh!
That was terrific moment. Let's do it again!
Oh!
What are you looking at, sorry you?
I can hear all my brothers howling out there.
They're probably hungry and looking for food.
No, I know they're calling me.
I'm going to see them. I've really got to a moment.
What a... Oh. Got anything? No, not yet. I'm afraid there's going to be trouble. We're running out of jam.
Mr. Bresch is opposed.
You can't stop eating it.
Well, you have to ask him to leave.
I can't do that.
Well, of course you can.
It's your home and you can choose who you have.
Oh. I can't do that. Well, of course you can. It's your home and you can choose who you have.
A snowstorm is sweeping through the valley.
Usually a sign that spring is not far away. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. Hello, Moomin!
Oh, hello, Mr. Brisk. Look, I'm sorry, but all the jams gone. And just an empty jar.
Oh, well, never mind. It was a great jam.
But I have more important things on my mind.
You see, now that spring is here,
I have to leave, Moomin Valley.
Oh, do you?
It's sad, but there you are.
I have to go.
Goodbye, Moomin.
Goodbye, then, Mr. Bursk.
Keep some jam for me. Hello, I'm sorry, I'm your brother, I've wanted to be with you for a long, long time.
I'm afraid I'm not very brave or strong, but if you'd let me stay with you.
Oh, don't you know me?
Looks like I was wrong.
Oh, well, go on.
Eat me if you want to.
It's a pity I didn't sleep at night instead of learning to howl.
Mum and I was right, I shouldn't have come. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go.
I'm going to have to go. I'm going to have to go. Oh hello little doggy, what are you doing here?
Have you been waiting for me?
We'll have a great time traveling around the world together. Ah!
Hooray!
See?
Hooray! D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D- Little mine.
That was spring breaking through the ice.
Look at the theme moment and it's free again.
Will Little Mike get back?
Oh.
Oh my goodness.
Little Mike! Little boy, hang on to me. Thank you, Moonman. Let's go.
It's all right, Moonman.
Don't panic, I'm with you.
You're okay.
Oh.
Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh. It's alright, Moomin, don't panic, I'm with you! You're okay!
Uh! Uh!
Over there, Moomin! Quick, do!
See, if you knew what I'd tell you, there's nothing to be afraid of. Just trust me, Moomin.
I'm always right, aren't I? Yes, I know you are, little lion, but we'd still better hurry.
Come on, you two just a bit further!
Uh-oh! Whoa!
Whoa, it's cold in here.
Quickly, let's get inside and light a fire. You'll soon warm up.
Phew!
And so Mr. Brisk and the ice both left human valley
and spring returned once more after a long and They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
The movements. Living the movements Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and goes at play
The Moons are having fun day after day
The Moons The moments, the moments, the moments.