Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
They are the movements, they are the movements,
so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement land, you can fly
just like a bird, sing that song ever, there was a movement, there was a movement, there was a movement La la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la la The rain was falling on Mumen Valley as though the heavens had decided to empty themselves.
It was the wettest weather that anyone could remember. I'm going to go to the next room. I'm going to go to the next room. I'm going to go to the next room.
I'm going to go to the next room.
I'm going to go to the next room. I'm going this? Of course, dear. And this one too?
Yes, dear, but what do you need them for?
I'll give you some.
I'll give you some. I'll give you some. You'll miss one too? Yes, dear, but what do you need them for? It's a secret.
A secret?
Yeah, sure.
I'll want to see a back moment, but you can keep the jar, if you like.
Thanks. Oh, dear me. Oh, there are puddles everywhere. Oh, dear me, Mr. Hemmielen.
What a mess.
Hello, Mr. Hemmielen.
Oh, dear me.
Mr. Hemmielen. What a mess dear me, Mr. Hemmielin, what a mess!
Hello, Mr. Hemmielin!
Oh, good morning, Momen!
Oh, it's all misty now.
What are you doing, Momen?
Observing very closely.
Oh, splendid, my boy. I'm glad you find botany so exciting.
Oh, what exactly is boy. I'm glad you find botany so exciting.
Oh, what exactly is it you're observing?
I'm sure I saw a beautiful crayfish in there.
Crayfish?
Excuse me, young man, but that is the wall
of Zeequette, the most uninteresting field. There it is. Oh Oh! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! I got him! I got him! I got him!
I got him!
Huh?
Oh, dragon!
Oh, dragon.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Papa!
Oh, what have you got there?
Oh, oh, nothing, Papa.
Everything's so fresh after the rain.
Oh, woman.
Yes, it is.
I got to show this to Snuffkin before anybody else sees it.
Oh. Oh Boom moment! What do you got there, Moonman?
Oh, nothing! Nothing at all, little lion.
Oh yes, you have, I saw it! Don't lie to me!
It's just one of Mama's old jars!
Liar! Liar! I know there'sar, liar, I know there's nothing.
I don't think there's nothing.
Then why are you hiding it?
Oh, right, you little mice. See me, it's not fair.
Dragon. Ah, yeah, I was right.
It must be a baby dragon.
Probably the very last one on Earth and washed up by the rain.
A dragon of my own.
Well, that's wonderful.
Oh, I hope I did it frighten you.
I know what frighten you.
I know what I'll do. I'll take the lid off the jar so you can get some fresh air and little dragon.
See? That's better, isn't it? Come on, little fella. We'll give you a cut so make you be starving. I'll get you something from my nighttime emergency food box. I've got lots of things in there. Bound to be something you like.
Go on. Take anything you won. Ah! Oh!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Gosh!
That's really clever, little dragon!
Moving! Lunch is ready!
Coming!
Now you stay here.
Don't worry, I'll be back in no time at all!
Remember, you're my own little dragon!
Oh! Remember, you're my own little dragon. Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Where's Sniff? I thought he was here as well.
He's collecting worms for fishing.
He'll be here soon.
We'll start without him then.
You know, Mama, certain people keep secrets and glass jars.
Secrets?
Oh, yes, a little secret that hisses.
Moment mama, I found this near the big puddle.
Thank you, sniff. Moment, I told you I wanted it back.
It's my very best one.
Sorry mama, I was so excited.
I must have left it when I found, I mean when I was was and I'm sure you know who I mean by certain people.
Did you catch anything with the sieve moment?
Yes he did something that's now hidden in his room.
Big mouth.
If it's a secret little my perhaps he doesn't want to tell anyone.
Yeah probably because his new pet bites.
Well it hasn't bitten you yet, hasn't it?
Huh, if it did, I'd bite it back.
Is it true?
Does your secret really bite people?
Well, it couldn't bite very hard
if it was small enough to go in a jar, good at papa?
I suppose certain people might keep
other small things in jars, beetles and spiders,
mosquitoes, scorpions, or poisonous centipedes, horrible things that multiply
and multiply every week and grow and grow until the jars
are too small.
See, like that.
And there'll be so many of them, thousands and thousands,
and they'll take over moving valley and eat us all.
Oh, well, I haven't got a centipede.
I wonder if centipedes come from out of space.
But this is the Earth's deer.
The rain could have brought them down from space, Mama, couldn't it?
Well, you could be right.
It was raining very hard yesterday.
And it wasn't like ordinary rain.
I saw a puddle as big as a lake.
What's the matter, Moomin?
It isn't a centipede.
Ha, we're on the right track, though. Well, I'm glad it's not a poisonous centipede.
I shouldn't have liked that.
Oh, you're asleep.
Moomin's little dragon.
Oh, you're asleep. Moments little dragon. Is it okay if I go see Snuffkin, mama?
Have you finished already?
Yes, I have.
Tell them they mustn't go into my room.
Or they'll have to take the consequence, sis.
All right, Momen.
I'll make sure no one goes in there.
I promise.
Oh, but he's gonna tell Snuffkin. I have to take the consequence, sis. All right, movement. I'll make sure no one goes in there.
Oh, but he's gonna tell snuck in the secret.
I should think he is.
Best friends always come first, little my. Hey, Snuffkin!
Hi!
Fishing again?
Yep.
The cards told me that if I caught five minnows, one right after the other, I'd be traveling south.
South?
You're joking!
Not at all.
I believe in the cards.
I'm not joking.
I'm not joking. I'm not joking. I'm not joking. I'm not joking. The cards told me that if I caught five minnows, one right after the other, I'd be traveling south.
South?
You're joking. Not at all. I believe in the cards.
But snuffkin, winter's not here yet.
I know that, but the cards tell you things for a reason, movement.
Oh, do they really?
But it would be awful if you and your way snuffkin, just awful. I mean, I'd be very lonely.
And anyway, who would I talk to or tell my secrets to?
Oh, snuff can quickly.
You must come up to the moment house.
Now?
Yeah.
Well, I suppose I could fish later.
No, no. There's no point.
But I have to catch five minnows.
Oh.
The fish won't bite after all his rain.
You'd catch nothing.
It'll be better to wait until it's stopped flowing so fast.
Well, perhaps you're right.
So what's this big secret all about?
Hey, Moonman.
Have you ever seen a dragon snuffkin?
No, of course not.
They all disappeared off the face of the earth many hundreds of years ago.
But perhaps they didn't all disappear.
What if there was one alive somewhere?
That's impossible.
It could be so small that it would go in a glass jar, though, again.
Are you sure you're not daydreaming, Moomin?
But still, anything is possible, I suppose.
But you know me.
I have to see it right in front of me before I believe it.
Oh!
Oh, where is it? Mama promised me that she wouldn't let anyone in.
I's not here either.
Well, you were right, Moomin.
Huh? here either. Well you were right movement. What?
Ah there he is. I think you found a real dragon. How do you get up there? He
mustn't fall. He might lose his tail. Don't move little dragon and snuff can keep quiet.
He might get frightened and do something silly. Don't worry, I'll soon have you down. This will do a lead on the floor here.
Jump, little dragon.
Don't be afraid.
Come on, hold onto this.
It will bring you down slowly.
Don't panic.
I don't think it's a very good idea, Moomin.
You'll only scare him away.
Why don't you just leave him alone?
He'll come down when he's ready.
Dragons aren't helpless, you know, even little baby ones.
But he's so small. Come to a moment.
Come on. Don't you understand?
Hold onto that and I'll listen to you.
Oh!
Look at him! My dragon can fly! He's flying!
He's flying!
Come down, little dragon!
You might crush into something!
Come down!
Oh!
Be careful, Snuffkin. He might bite.
I don't think so. He's a very unusual pet.
I think he likes you more than me.
Ah!
What a charming little creature, Moon.
He's lovely. What's his name? He's called Little Dragon.
Ha! I don't think he's lovely at all. Small but savage, if you ask my opinion.
That sounds just like you, little mime.
You think so?
Ow!
Yeah!
No, oh, oh, oh.
Whoa!
Oh!
Ow!
Now look here.
Oh, wait.
Ah.
He seems to have a thing about ears, doesn't he?
Step Snuffkins, why doesn't he bite him?
Go on, dragon.
Go on, vitamin! He's really tasty! Go on!
Good news, I think he's trying to heat up Snuffkins coffee.
He must really like him.
Clevver little thing.
Well, I hope he's careful with that hot breath.
We don't want to start a fire.
All right, that's enough.
He might be useful.
When he's bigger, we can put him in the cellar
and he'll be able to keep the whole house just like a furnace.
No, we will not.
Huh? Not Go away you pass
And you he only thought you were trying to get his fly I'll get him if he bites me again just you watch me doing
Come on little dragon.
I'm sure that'll keep him quiet. That better go. Thanks for the coffee, Moomin' Mama.
Oh no, it'll suffocate him! He only seems to like Snuffkin.
Well we all like Snuffkin.
Stupid old dragon. No, he isn't.
Moomin, dear. Why don't you take him to your room?
He'll be happier there.
This will be best for him.
Oh, I wonder if he'll come back to visit us.
Why did you do that?
He was cute and weak and aball is more an ear muff.
You can visit him in Snuffkin's tent.
I expect little dragons already sitting on his shoulder.
It doesn't matter anyway. Snuffkin's going south soon.
We'll be able to go together.
Oh, my dear, Moomin. Never mind.
Well, you're a bit of a problem.
I don't want you here, little dragon.
Go on, go away. Go to movement.
Don't do that.
Oh, come on, please go to movement.
Look, you're very nice and it'd be fun to have you along.
But there's movement, and he'd know you were here and you'd be upset.
Oh, there's another one.
That's the fifth? Oh, dear.
Hm? I'm sure you'll get hungry. Yeah, what do you want in return? A small favor.
I'm sure you'll get hungry. I'm sure you'll get hungry.
Yeah, what do you want in return?
A small favor.
I'm sure you'll get hungry.
Yeah, what do you want in return?
A small favor.
Take this as far as you can, open the lid and just leave it. What? Just leave it?
Yes, in a nice quiet place, with lots and lots of flies.
Flies? What's in there?
A dragon. A dragon? Does's in there? A dragon.
A dragon? Does it bite?
Well, it might.
This is a big favor. I don't even like minors.
Oh, they're not too bad if you rose them.
Keep the lid on, but make sure you open it up later.
So it can catch the flies.
All right, as long as it doesn't try to bite me.
Don't worry. It won't.
Hello. Hi.
Oh, oh, oh.
Where is he?
Who is that?
My dragon. He must have come here snuffkin. Oh
Really I thought he was home with you sleeping in your room
No, I let him out
Well dragons are very fickle all they really care about is big fat flies. It's best to forget about a moment
Did you catch your five minnows?, you were right. The water is too fast.
Oh, really?
So I won't go soft until winter comes.
You'll stay here then?
Well, I'm sure it wouldn't do to go against the cards.
Now what did Moomin' my friend?
Oh, that's great!
You're staying stuff, kid.
Fantastic! That's really, really good!
Ah, perhaps I shouldn't have painted the float bright red.
It might have scared those little minors right away.
Okay, let's go.
Yeah.
That dragon was sort of stupid.
Baby dragons are.
They make the world's worst pets.
They never want to settle in one place.
Yeah, you're right.
It was very funny though when it bit little mice here. I think it could be a little bit more fun. They make the world's worst pets. They never want to settle in one place. Yeah, you're right.
It was very funny though when it bit little mice here.
I think it gave her a taste of her own medicine.
LAUGHTER
The woman was very happy that Snuffkin was staying in Mumen Valley
and not going south until winter.
And as for the dragon, well, who wants to be loved by a silly old dragon?
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements
They're always happy and always at play. The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living.
You're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements, the moment