Off we go then, Hank is away, he won't have to road too hard, the wind will pick us up soon.
Goodbye, have a good time, everyone.
Goodbye, Snuffkin, now don't forget to shut all the windows if it rains, will you?
No.
Up towards!
Hey! Wait for me, I want to have a good time too!
Hey, wait!
Look, Snuff is still waving.
He's a sweet boy.
Let's keep waving, Moonman, till we're out of sight.
Bye, Snuffkin! Bye, bye!
Bye!
No, I'm not waving goodbye, I want to go too!
Don't eat all the road, Mary Tabo, we're gone!
It's no good shouting little Mai, he can't hear you.
He's giving us a great send-off though, for Snuff, he should have come with us.
Nancy, I'm going off and leaving me here on my own.
Snuffkin, if you wouldn't mind, I think we need some music to send us on our way.
What do you say?
Are you sure we're on the right course for the island, Papa?
Yes, the winds with us and the sails are fine.
I bet if we keep this speed up, we'll be there by tomorrow.
Well, if the wind stays like this, you could be right.
The wind's not dying down at all.
I'm surprised, I never thought we'd keep up this speed.
Now make sure you're allergic.
Of course we will be, Papa, if we carry on like this, perhaps we'll see the light from the lighthouse while it's still dark.
Well, we don't want to hit anything at this speed.
Don't worry, we're watching.
Ah, this is the light.
Papa, the wind's dropped.
Well, that's strange, it shouldn't happen that quickly.
Do you want us to start rowing, Moomin, Papa?
No, Snuffkin, I think we'd better get some sleep.
Stupid wind, I really wanted to see the lighthouse at night.
It's getting foggy too.
I can't even see the stars anymore.
Right, Snuffkin, wake me in two hours and I'll take over.
Okay, Moomin, Papa.
What's the matter, Little My?
I thought I heard something.
It's coming from over there somewhere.
Can you see anything?
No, but I can hear it.
It's so good eye, and it's getting closer.
Little Moomin, Papa, get up, Moomin!
Stop it, Little My! What's the matter with you?
You too, Moomin, quickly, before it's too late!
What's the matter, Little My?
I can hear her ship, I can't see it, but it's very close and getting closer.
A ship? Where?
Over there, and she's bearing down on us.
Quickly, we don't have much time.
Yes, by the boobalier right.
We must let them know we're here, a signal.
Right, all hands on deck.
Maybe if we all shout as loud as we can.
Look!
Oh!
Too late for shouting!
It's huge!
Look out! It's gonna hit us!
I think Moomin's right, what can we do?
It's too late for anything, just brace ourselves and be ready to swim for it.
Quick, get down, Little My!
Oh!
I don't believe it!
Little My!
Huh?
That's hard, the ship didn't hit us.
Oh yes, he did!
What?
It went straight into our rudder when nothing happened!
It went right through us!
Right through us, that's impossible she couldn't have.
I wonder if there was anyone on board that ship.
I can't see any lights.
I know, Snuffkin, I think it's a ghost ship.
A ghost ship?
Well, there's no wash and no damage to us.
It's the only explanation, I think she's right.
A ghost ship, we've actually seen one.
Oh dear, oh dear, I need to sit down, all this excitement's too much.
Papa, don't they say that if you see a ghost ship, something terrible is gonna happen to you?
What happened in the first place to make it become a ghost ship? That's what I wanna know.
Well, that's just some old sailor's tail, Moomin.
If it had been a real ship, we'd probably be sinking now.
Don't you think so, Snuffkin?
Yeah, I suppose.
That's one way of looking at it.
Come on, cheer up you guys, at least it was fun.
What's the matter?
Has something happened?
What are you laughing at?
What's so funny?
Are you going to tell us?
Why didn't you wake me up, Moomin?
Oh!
Well, I think we're doing very well.
We're doing very well.
Oh!
Well, I think we're doing very well.
Oh, what a beautiful sky, just look at it.
Oh, the fog is lifting.
Oh, what's it dozed off?
Another beautiful day, not a ghost ship in sight.
The lighthouse.
Hey, wake up everybody, the lighthouse.
I can see the lighthouse we're there.
Oh, the sun shining, we must have slept for hours.
Oh, there it is.
This is ridiculous.
We've been next to it all night.
We could have gone and slept there.
I can't wait to go ashore.
All right, everyone, jump to it.
Man the old.
There's something strange going on here.
What is it, Snuffkin?
I'm not sure.
Moomin Papa.
Our boat didn't move at all last night, did it?
No, it doesn't seem to have moved at all.
So why couldn't we see the light from the lighthouse,
even when the fog cleared?
I can't work it out.
Yes, you're right, Snuffkin, it seems very odd.
We should have seen it.
Well, perhaps the lighthouse keeper forgot to put it on, Moomin Papa.
I don't think so, little Mai.
You can't forget a thing like that.
I suppose it could be broken.
There could be lots of reasons for it.
Why don't we hurry up and get ashore,
and then we can ask the keeper.
Look, there's someone in a boat.
Hmm.
It looks like he's fishing.
He know about the lighthouse.
He probably lives on the island.
Let's get closer.
Easy now.
Now, hoi there, good morning.
Any luck?
Not yet, but it's still early.
Hmm, yes, quite.
I'll ask him straight out.
Do you know if the lighthouse was working last night?
I don't know.
Sorry, I didn't catch that.
He said, no, it wasn't.
What did I tell you?
He forgot to light it.
Oh, it wasn't only last night.
You'll never see a light in that lighthouse.
Not even on stormy nights.
We'll never.
So what does the keeper do then?
Nothing.
There is an lighthouse keeper.
Why?
I'm sorry.
I'm afraid I don't know.
All I can say is I haven't seen one.
Do you live on the island?
Hey, mister.
You're asking too many questions.
Who are you?
I'm Moment Papa from Moment Valley, and this is my family.
We've come a long way in order to do some important work here.
No work on this island.
No, you better go back home.
You see, I've come here to research an epic novel about the sea.
Just turn around and go back.
You're too far from home.
Oh, please, wait.
Shh.
Dear, don't shout.
We mustn't scare the fish away.
Let's go a show and have some breakfast.
I expect we're all hungry.
Bunny, pair.
The old ones lost his marbles.
Look, Moment Papa. There's a path here leading to the lighthouse.
We'll leave this stuff here and we'll go and explore it first.
Right, to the lighthouse, everyone.
Up, bow.
Come on!
What's wrong?
Why do you always get so upset when somebody mentions the lighthouse?
It's not your call, sir.
Business boy doesn't concern you at all.
You were like that when I asked you about it before.
Maybe if you were to tell me, I might be able to understand.
I could try anyway.
Either talk about something else or keep quiet.
You understand that?
It's so very rocky, I don't think it would work.
What? A garden.
Hello there!
Is there anybody at home?
There's nobody here.
That boy was right. It's been empty for ages, I think.
Oh, the door was left unlocked. I know we do it, but most people don't.
Something terrible's happened.
Something terrible! Please, little my, you know I had things like that.
Don't worry, snort maiden.
Little my, it's just trying to scare you.
I don't like hearing about anything horrible.
Flag your ears then, snort maiden, because I haven't finished yet.
And the next bit's really horrible.
Oh, well, where have you been finished there?
Well, the lighthouse keeper is still up there.
He got scurvy and hats and been able to move for months.
And nobody's heard his cries for help.
And with no food, he's almost a skeleton.
If he isn't dead already, he'll be at the top of the stairs, crawling towards his fingers,
lading and ripped up ribbons and flowers, mouth.
God, it's endless, mouth.
Shut up, little my.
That's enough.
It was a good imagination though.
I'll let you use it in your book, if you like.
Come on, tell me what did she say, Moonman?
Oh, nothing, really. Nothing at all.
Tell me, Moonman, but leave out the bits I wouldn't like.
Where are you going, Papa?
Well, listen, everyone.
First, I'm going to get the lamp working.
Then we'll give the place a good clean and then we'll move in.
We'll be the new lighthouse keepers.
And once again, the seas around this island will be safe for ships to navigate in troubled water.
Come on, Papa!
Careful, careful.
Touch anything, that's dangerous.
Oh!
Will Moonman Papa be able to get the light working again?
Where is the lighthouse keeper?
And what could have made him go without locking the door,
leaving the ships in peril and the seas with no one to guide them away from the rocks?
And who is the mysterious fisherman?
They love the laughter and they love the living, the moments.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me.
Give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
The movements came to this island to visit a real lighthouse, but when they got there,
I found it was completely deserted, no light, and no lighthouse keeper.
Woman Papa is going to try and mend the lamp, and the others are all helping to clean up.
This is it, then. Do you think it's broken, Papa?
Well, I'm not sure. I've not had a great deal of experience with this sort of thing.
Look over there, woman. It's the boy and the fisherman from the boat.
They're a bit strange, aren't they?
They must live somewhere here on the island.
Hmm, let's see. Let's see.
Oh, my God.
Oh, thank you. Leave it by the door when you haven't quite finished yet.
Well, at least we can see the floor now.
I think the keeper must be lying dead under the dust.
Nobody's cleaned here for a long time, that's for sure.
That probably means the lighthouse lamp hasn't been working for ages either.
I wonder if Papa will be able to fix it.
I wonder if they're going to manage to get the light working all right.
Well, the lighthouse without a lamp is pretty sad, isn't it?
Come on, light, will you?
Right, I'll give you one last chance.
Then I'm getting the big spanner. Now, you don't know me, but I don't give in easily, especially to machines.
Have you thought, brass brain, what will happen tonight if there's a storm and there's a ship out there looking for land or trying to keep off the rocks and there's no light to guide them?
You'll be sorry, Dan, but it'll be too late.
And all I can say is that if the light hasn't been working for some time,
then I'm afraid that there could have been many shipwrecks.
Oh, that's awful.
It would be dangerous to come too close to the island without a light to help you.
I wouldn't be surprised if that ghost ship went one of them.
It all seems very strange, and I wonder what made the lighthouse keeper leave in such a hurry.
Unspeakable horror, please be quiet, little my.
It's obvious.
Close thrown above dishes left unwashed, jigsaw puzzles have finished.
It's an unsolved mystery of the sea, just like the Marie Celeste.
And if you don't understand that, then you're being even stupider.
Then usual.
Oh dear poor man, I wonder what he was like.
He must have been very lonely here on his own.
He scribbled messages over the walls like no side of a ship.
It's Christmas, another month gone.
I must clean the lamp, and I need to talk to someone.
Oh, well, if he didn't see many ships, at least they could have been many shipwrecks either.
Oh, I hope not Papa.
That would be one good thing anyway.
Perhaps the sea came and took him on a dark and stormy night, and he was swept out, and no one saw him go.
That's rubbish, little my.
On dark and stormy nights, lighthouse keeper sits safe by a fire drinking hot tea laced with rum.
He might have run out of rum and gone to get more.
Well, I don't think anything terrible happened to him.
He just got more and more lonely and fed up, and then went off and got a girlfriend.
Be careful, snuffkin.
It's very rough and not even, and you don't want to fall into the sea.
I certainly don't.
Now, watch your step. The rocks are very slippery.
Are you alright?
Yes, Lang, so I didn't think they'd be a slippery as all that.
What's the matter?
Look over there. There's something moving, but I can't see what it is.
It's probably a boat.
No, that's what I call a real ship.
It's not a real one.
What do you mean?
It's the ghost ship, the one we saw last night.
You're right. Why isn't it come back snuffkin? What does it want?
I don't know. Perhaps it followed us to the island and for some reason wants to make contact.
Let's go home snuffkin. I don't like this.
What's up?
I'm having a great dream and you can be with me.
Oh, it was horrible. Someone stepped on my face.
Well, none of us sleep.
We were all asleep. What are you doing?
It's very odd.
No, somebody's on my stomach now.
Don't be stupid.
Oh, I have a look snuffkin. There must be something there. Please snuffkin, please.
I can't see any.
What's that?
What is it?
I don't know yet, movement. I think I can see a pair of feet.
A pair of feet.
No legs, just feet.
But that means a ghost.
Oh, help! Get it off me! Go away, go away!
Let me at them! Where are they? I'll teach them to spoil my dream!
They're on my face now. Go away, will you?
Show me it, but no, stamp on it!
Stop it, move!
No, it's my foot!
You go fishing again today?
No, I'm not.
Oh, do you need me or is it alright if I go and see those people?
In the lighthouse.
Oh, don't let you want.
Okay, goodbye then.
You mean this room is really haunted?
It certainly is.
But we only saw a pair of feet.
I'll sleep here tonight. Don't worry. I'll protect you.
Are you going to scare it away, Papa?
Mm-hmm.
I can't find any good shells.
You're me.
What about this one?
Oh, yes, that's lovely.
Go on, take it. I don't collect them.
Who are you?
Well, I'm a ghost, sort of.
Are you the rat who walked over us last night?
You were lucky I didn't grab you.
Sorry, it wasn't just me.
There were a few of us.
And walk over each other.
Can I give you a present?
You can't get around me that easily.
You better show yourselves or you'll be sorry.
It's just me.
The others have all left me and gone off with the ship.
Ha, so why didn't you go with them?
Oh, I wanted to, but uh, well...
Come on, out with it.
Never got me and left me all of my own and I was frightened.
Well, I can see why they wouldn't want a drippy thing like you around.
You call yourself a ghost.
No, I'm sorry.
I just can't work out what's wrong with it.
Let's try and see what happens here.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, heavens, oh, my.
Oh, good.
Oh, no, oh, what?
You were right, papa!
Oh, thank goodness you're here.
Quick, open all the windows, I'm choking!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh...
Mmm, this is great. That soup I've had for ages, Moome and Mama.
Would you like some more?
Oh, he has, please. Can I have the recipe? I could make some for the fisherman. I know he'd love it.
I'll write it out for you. What's his name?
I don't know. He doesn't say. I've come from the north. I left about three months ago.
Although it seems a lot longer, and I'd been rowing south in my small boat, trying to reach Moome and Valley.
Oh, really? We live there.
Do you? You're lucky. It must be very nice. I've never been there, but I've heard that it's beautiful.
Anyway, there was a violent storm in my little boat capsized. He rescued me, and I've stayed with him in his cabin ever since.
And he doesn't talk about himself at all. That's very strange.
No, but I think he does have a big secret.
How do you know, Toft?
Well, sometimes he just stares and stares at the lighthouse in any sort of size.
I wonder why.
I did ask him once, but he glared at me in such a nasty way.
I haven't dared say a word about it since.
You don't want to stay with him then?
Oh, yes. Well, most of the time he's really nice to me, and since I've been here, I've sort of taken care of him, because you see he doesn't really look after himself.
Can I have a cup of tea, please, Mama?
Yes, dear. How is the light coming along?
Oh, not very well. There's still a few more things I could try, though.
Hello. You were on that boat fishing, weren't you?
Yes, I was. My name is Toft, Mum and Papa.
Oh, please, to meet you. Is your friend here as well? I wanted to ask him something. There's something ever quite important.
Ask him what?
Well, about this lighthouse for one thing.
Well, he won't talk about that. He just refuses to.
Oh, dear, does he? The thing is, I'm trying to light this beacon, but having no success.
I wondered whether he might know if there's an easy way of doing it. You never know. I haven't missed something.
It's very quiet.
He might be out fishing, you know.
Come on, let's go.
Where are you going, Moomin?
I want to ask that man some questions.
He doesn't seem to be the kind of guy who does a lot of talking.
Do you think he might know something about the lighthouse keeper?
That's what I want to find out.
Hello, my name is Moomin, and this is my friend Snuffkin.
What's your business here?
I wonder, do you live here? I suppose you must have met the lighthouse keeper, have you?
I didn't want people to talk about that.
We were just curious about why you left the lighthouse. Do you know why?
No, he kept himself to himself.
Oh, so you do know it. When did he leave? Where did he go? You must know.
Get.
Oh, please. Had the light stopped working before he left?
Why did he leave the door open? Were there any shipwrecks?
Oh! Wait a minute. Just one more question, please.
Oh, don't go. There's something very important I need to know.
You're the only other person on the island apart from the go ship.
Oh, please come back. Look, my father is trying to get the lamp working again,
but not getting anywhere. So if you know where the keeper is, or better still,
how to light it when you please help, it's not only for us, but for all those ships
that might be in danger without it.
Moomin.
I don't think that man knows much about anything.
Well, at least he's heard you and knows what you want.
Let's go, Moomin.
Look, over there, what's Moomin Papa doing?
Snork made an a little Maya helping him.
Hiya!
Come on.
Yeah.
It's about time. Where are you two being?
What are you building now? We're making a raft. Why?
Because we wanted to stupid, why else would we build it? Do you like it?
But why do you want a raft?
It's not really a raft, is it Papa?
Let me present our very own hand-built ghost ship.
A ghost ship?
He must be here somewhere.
Well, if he's the one that walked on me last night, I want a word with him.
Yeah, sorry. I'm afraid that was me.
I want a word with him.
Yeah, sorry. I'm afraid that was me and my friends.
Oh, where are you?
Show us a bit of leg at least. I like to see you I'm talking to.
Yes, all right.
Oh, well, at least he looks like a ghost.
Thank you.
Ghosts look pretty silly when the sun's shining if you ask me.
Well, it was your idea.
I always thought ghosts were frightening.
Yes, we forgot our chains last night.
It's very hard to be ghostly without them.
We did our best to scare you, though.
The ghost came to this island because a lighthouse was a bit like an ancient castle.
We feel more at home in castle.
And now when they found us here, they changed their minds and gave up.
That's funny, isn't it?
What's the matter?
You look a bit fed up.
That's because he's been left behind by the other ghosts.
They've gone off in the ghost ship.
Wow, they didn't tell me they were going straight away.
And I'd gone to the lighthouse keepers cabin.
The lighthouse keeper?
Why did you go there?
Well, I wanted to tell him that some strange people.
I'm sorry.
I mean, strangers had moved into the lighthouse and that he'd be better off with us
because ghosts don't damage things.
I didn't know you then, of course.
But some people are very kind.
Where is his cabin?
Is it easy to find?
At the southern end of the island.
But it was a waste of time because he wouldn't talk to me.
I shouldn't have bothered.
And then I would have caught the boat.
Anyway, he's not going back to his job, so that's that.
Bye-bye.
Thanks again for the raft.
Take care.
I hope you catch up with your friends real soon.
Thank you.
You're okay for mortals.
I promise next time we meet Abbey Rally's scurry.
Chains and all.
Lots of chains and we promise to be terrified.
You can come and scare me anytime you want.
Bye-bye.
Relating a try.
He said anything that could float would do.
But that raft seemed a bit flimsy to me.
I wouldn't like to chance it.
It can be rough out there.
Well, it doesn't matter anyway.
Those can't drown.
Can they?
They're dead already.
Mama.
What is it, Mum and Dia?
Papa's gone fishing again.
Well, he enjoys it.
Well, that's all he seems to do these days.
He's not working on the lamp at all.
Well, perhaps living in a new place makes him want to do a new thing.
And he does catch one now and again.
What are you making, little boy?
An elevator.
An elevator?
Yes, and when that's finished, I'm going to build a house.
Oh, my goodness.
A house of my very own.
Mum and Papa doesn't seem his usual happy self,
even though he enjoys his fishing.
He's upset that he couldn't make the lamp work
and isn't used to failure,
but nothing he tries makes any difference.
What a pity it would be to leave the island
without seeing the beautiful beams shining over the water.
What a pity it would be to leave the island.
And when that's finished, I'm going to build a house of my own.
I'll build a house of my own.
And that's all he's got.
Yeah, hey, coming up along, everyone, I've finished my house.
Ah!
Hey, Mum and Papa!
Come here, the fisherman's coming!
Wow, the fisherman!
Yes, and the boy is with them!
He's off to his outside?
You don't want to do it, do you?
No, but I gotta do it.
Right!
Here you are.
So, what can we do for you?
Oh!
Happy birthday! Happy birthday to you!
Hmm?
Tough just told us it's your birthday today, so all the best wishes from us.
My birthday? Is it really?
Excuse me for asking, but how old are you?
I just don't remember.
It doesn't matter. I'm sorry we don't have any presents.
I haven't had coffee for many, many years.
Bring the barrel, woman mama.
Yes, dear.
Now, let me see. I found this...
...sawester.
I wonder if it suits me. What do you think?
Well...
I suppose this must belong to the lighthouse keeper.
Why don't you try it on?
You look good in a sowester. There it suits you.
We'd love to know why you left the island and why you didn't come back here.
And also why you didn't like the land.
We really would like to know if you feel you could tell us.
I was so lonely.
For years and years.
Then I just went away.
I'm afraid that's all.
But you did come back. Surely that must mean something.
I knew I'd lived here for too long. Much too long.
You see, I didn't really fit in anywhere else.
This is the lighthouse keeper's uniform, isn't it? Why don't you put it on again?
And look, it's nice here. I'd like to stay. Would you mind that?
I'll stay if you let me.
Ah, I'd love that.
It'd be fun to see you looking like a lighthouse keeper.
Oh, hooray!
Three days later, the Moomans left the island.
They decided to leave at night with the safe blow of the lighthouse beans guiding their path out and away to Mooman Valley.
Mooman Papa had quite forgotten about his epic novel of the sea, but couldn't wait to start again on his memoirs.
The Moomans
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the Moomans
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moomans
They're always happy and always at play. The Moomans are having fun day after day. The Moomans
The Moomans
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the Moomans
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moomans
They're always happy and always at play. The Moomans are having fun day after day. The Moomans
The Moomans
Here they are for one and all. The Moomans are about to call. Come on and sit down here with me. They're for you on your TV. They are the Moomans
They are the Moomans
So come with me, give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land
You can fly just like a bird
Sing that song ever, there were the Moomans
There were the Moomans
Mom
Everything's so boring
Let's do something then
Like what, for instance, I think we've done everything one could possibly do
None of you three can think of a single thing to do. You're useless, aren't you?
Well, can you think of anything except catching grasshoppers?
There must be something we can do
Now we've all had times like this, haven't we? Fortunately, right then, the mailman arrived
Hello, a letter for you
Oh, a letter that must be from my sister for me
Oh no, it's from a woman Papa this time
That's all? Who would write to him? A woman? Someone called Jane?
Huh?
See that he gets it now
Who could this Jane possibly be?
It's your father's old girlfriend, of course
Never
Oh, I'm sure he had dozens and dozens
Moom and Papa was very kind and handsome young man
A voice from the past
Moom and Papa, liquid, I've got for you
Hmm
Oh, no
I was right
Yeah, you were
Moom and Mama, I think you should go back to the kitchen
Whatever, for a little lie
Because Moom and Papa store me youth is catching up with him
Please, Papa, tell us it's not that kind of letter
Oh, what would you do?
Don't worry
Whatever it was, it was a long time ago, long before I ever met you
No, it's not that kind of letter
What sort of letter is it then?
Oh, much worse, it's from Aunt Jane
Who's that?
Mine, my dear, is on my father's side
Oh, how boring
You look very pale suddenly, dear
Yes, because she's coming for a visit tomorrow
Oh, don't worry, there's plenty of time for arranging a welcome party
But I don't like her, and I don't want her to come for a visit
Moom and Papa, why not?
Well, you'll soon see, she's very rich
Very rich
Yes, and she bosses everyone, and we won't have a moment of peace
Oh, maybe she's so rich, she'll give us all wonderful presents
Goodness, this is so unexpected, why is she coming here all of a sudden?
Oh, she says she wants to discuss money matters, good heavens with me
She says there's no one else, so you see, I'm in a very difficult situation
Oh, why can't you tell if you're not an expert?
You don't tell Aunt Jane things, she tells you when that's that
Is that what you explained?
When you meet her, you'll know exactly what I mean
What do I know about money matters?
Nothing
Not surprising since we've never had any
How can she expect a poor creature like you to know anything about money?
Also, she's very, very suspicious
And she says money is a terrible burden
Oh, I wouldn't mind shouldering her burden
Maybe you'll inherit it, and then we could share the money
And have a wonderful time together
This time, I almost did it
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
I'm sure she jumped at it. Hmm, there'd be no harm in asking, I guess. What's the matter, Mr.
Hamilton, you look so unhappy. I'm stuck, that's my problem. How's that?
Stuck in my research, this magnifying glass is very good, of course, but I just can't get any further with my botanical research with this old fashioned equipment.
What I really need is a microscope and a laboratory. Hmm, and they're expensive, I guess. Yes, they are, and I don't have any money.
Well, moment Papa's aunt is coming over tomorrow, and I know she's got any amount of money. Any amount, Sniff?
I'll get her to finance you, Hamilton, and we'll get a big greenhouse, and you'll grow orchids and roses and other things, and then we'll sell them, oh, oh, I'll get rich. You too!
Hey, you over there. Hmm, are you talking to me? Of course I am. Who else? I say do you know the way to move in a house young man? Yes, she might say I do. Show me where it is then.
Over there, it's tall and blue, just follow that stream and you can't miss it. Good, would you be kind enough to take my suitcase?
I'm sorry I can't, I'm too busy. I'll reward you handsomely for your efforts, think again young man.
But all I want to do is fish. What? You don't want money?
I heard you were coming to visit moment Papa, you're a Jane, aren't you?
Oh, well, please to meet you, I'm here to take you to moment house. Is this your suitcase?
Wow, this suitcase is very heavy.
Should be, it's full of golden coins.
Oh, I'll take care of this. Let's go and take.
I can't stay in this house, I don't think I can take Aunt Jane. I'm going to hide out in the cave until she's gone.
Bye bye, then dear. Careful now Aunt Jane. The banks have been slippery here and there.
A roundhouse, how stupid, typical of my nephew.
Welcome to moment house Aunt Jane.
Welcome Aunt Jane.
I'd like you to meet us up in a minute.
Please to meet you.
She's very small for a daughter.
Oh little Mai isn't ours, she just lives here.
And I won't get any bigger, either.
Hmm, she's like a member of the family.
And where's my worthless nephew? Why isn't he here?
Oh, well, he's not, is he not at home?
Well, no, when will he be back? I don't know.
He's away looking for inspiration for his work, so he won't be back for a while.
Since when has he worked? I'm here to see him.
Maybe you can see me instead.
What a splendid idea, how clever of you, moment.
Ridiculous, he knows nothing about money.
In that case, it is high time he learned. As for his father, I may still disinherit him.
I'm a member of his family, too. I could talk to you about money matters.
Really?
Oh, sniff is a great friend of mine.
Hmm.
But hardly a member of the family.
Hello, moment. And you must be on Jane.
I brought my brother to snort with me. He wanted to meet you.
This is Aunt Jane, the nice dog.
Welcome to Moomin Valley and Jane.
This is my lovely sister, snort maiden, who is Moomin's special friend.
The snorts and the Moomin's may one day be related.
So in a way, we're all really family.
You maybe, but not to me.
I'm an inventor, and due to an accident, I'm looking around for a sponsor.
A golden opportunity for anyone with some loose capital.
Welcome to Moomin Valley and Jane.
I'm Hemmielin, a botanist of note.
I heard that you might be willing to fund my scientific research, Aunt Jane.
A golden opportunity for anyone with some spare money, eh?
You'd like me to fund your research?
It was my idea.
If we built a greenhouse and grow rare orchids and roses, we can make a lot of money.
And you'll make a lot of money.
Young man, I have a lot of money already.
Oh, hasn't sniff discussed this with you, Mom?
Yes, sniff.
Well, I was just getting around to it, Hemmielin.
Confusing?
When I am famous for my botanical research, Aunt Jane, I...
I don't know that will ever happen.
This is very confusing indeed for me.
Now, you're snorkemaid and a friend of Moomin, is that right?
Oh, no, I'm the snorric snort maiden's brother.
I'm a friend of Moomin, Aunt Jane.
Did you really explain about my important research, Sniff?
Did you really explain that I'm a member of the family?
Hey, she got it!
So, Aunt Jane would be grateful to all of you and make you a member of the family.
Thank you, Aunt Jane.
Here's your rule, Aunt Jane.
Oh, I do hope you'll be comfortable here.
Just call if you need anything.
Oh...
Come out.
Here's your suitcase.
It was very heavy.
Thank you.
Hemm...
What is it?
You want a reward?
No, no, Aunt Jane.
I mean, yes, I do, but...
Uh...
Which is it?
Will you make up your mind, young man?
I know where Moomin Papa is right now.
He's a whale and a trip, I know.
No, no. He's somewhere quite near.
Quite near here?
Well, where is he?
Moomin Papa said not to tell you where he's hiding.
It's a secret.
A secret?
Yes.
I suppose I could tell you, but he'll be very angry.
Where is he? Tell me now.
Well, if I tell you I'm taking a big risk...
Hmm.
Oh, very well.
How much do you want?
I'll leave that to you.
Thank you for the information.
Now you shall have your reward.
Hold out your hand.
Oh, is that all?
Until I've seen him for myself with my own eyes.
Yes!
Huh?
What?
Oh, there's nobody here.
Where is my worthless nephew?
Hey, this is very strange.
You tricked me, haven't you?
Well, no, I swear I would never do that.
You certainly deserve no reward.
Huh?
But no, wait.
If we just look around, we'll find him.
He's in here somewhere I know it.
Hey, Moomin Papa, I got rid of her.
Moomin, Mama.
Yes, Aunt Jane, what is it?
Tell me where my nephew is hiding.
Well, as I said before...
I want to know the truth.
Dear, he's...
Now let me see...
Come on, hurry up.
He's hiding in the cave down by the beach.
I've just been there, Moomin Mama, and I can't find him.
Then he really must have gone away on a trip.
And why should he want to hide from me anyway?
I think he might be a little bit afraid of you.
Afraid of me?
Afraid of his own aunt?
But why?
Mostly he's afraid of money matters.
Incredible.
Afraid of me because of money matters?
He must be utterly mad.
What a family.
I don't understand.
It seems that only Smith knows anything about money.
I know where Moomin Papa is right now.
So you want some of my gold, who do you young lady?
I couldn't care less about your silly gold.
My silly gold indeed.
With silly gold, I assure you you can do just anything you want.
Seems to me your silly gold doesn't even help you to find Moomin Papa.
Hmm?
I think you should forget about your money.
Young lady, money isn't something you can just forget about.
It needs constant looking after.
That's why I must talk to Moomin Papa at once.
Now take me to that rascal nephew of mine.
If you really know where he is, do you hear me?
Do you have me?
Of course.
Oh wow, frivolous.
Not really.
If I could find a small enough boyfriend, I'd be frivolous just like them too.
Oh well, Frederick and I were frivolous once.
Really?
Of course.
Oh wow, frivolous.
Not really.
If I could find a small enough boyfriend, I'd be frivolous just like them too.
I'd be frivolous once.
Really?
If you say so, I suppose I have to believe you.
Huh?
Look.
What?
Little May and Anne Jane walking together.
What are they doing?
Little May is plotting something.
Really?
Moomin?
Sniffs are right, really.
But sometimes he just can't withstand the lure of gold.
Check me.
No.
Well you can't be right.
Let's go back then.
Fine, just take your time.
Hi guys.
Little May, what's the matter?
We have a guest.
A guest?
Hmm.
Move it, Papa.
What?
Oh, so?
This is where you've been hiding.
Oh, what else?
Wait.
Oh, I'm here to shoot you.
I'm here to save your friend.
Wait, Jane.
No, you wait.
What are you worst?
Wait, please.
Moomin, Papa, was sort of on his way back from a trip
and then stopped by to play chess with me.
Yes.
Exactly.
No, yes.
Moomin, Mama told you the truth.
Oh, I sort of stopped by.
Why are you so afraid of me, young man?
Well, I'm not, not really.
I mean, it's not you.
It's your money.
I'm afraid of it.
Really scared.
Scared of my money?
Well, I'm not.
It's perfectly good money and all in gold coins.
Listen, nephew.
I'm depending on you as my only relative.
Yes, yes.
Please depend.
When I get too old to do it,
you must look after my gold for me.
I'm relying on you.
No, that's not possible.
I know, and Jane, we can give it all away.
Must be those who'd love to have it.
Must be those who need it more than we do.
Oh, a green pearl.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah.
She's crazy.
Don't worry.
We'll think of something.
Oh, you would throw my money away without a cut.
Why didn't you mean to hurt you, Aunt Jane?
I know.
Let's put it all in the bank.
Money likes being in the bank.
My money would hate being in a bag.
It could be a terrible idea.
Oh, no.
Banks are so nice nowadays.
They are.
Of course, they have flowers and shiny piggy banks
and pretty paintings on the wall.
Is that really true?
Right.
Come on, everybody.
Let's hurry home and fix a welcoming party for Aunt Jane.
A party?
Yes, any reason is good enough.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
This was Grandma's best cake recipe.
Welcome at Jane.
Let's drink a toast to the only millionaire
in our small circle.
May she live a long and healthy life.
Cheers!
Now, this is your welcoming party at Jane.
What's the matter?
Never in my life of I and my money
felt ourselves as welcome before.
I'm so happy I could cry.
Oh, and once you start crying,
you just want to go on.
Not again.
Please don't be unhappy at Jane.
Don't cry.
Dear.
Oh, dear.
Mom and Papa.
Yes, Aunt Jane.
What is it?
I'll put some of my gold in a bank,
but you must look after the rest when I'm too old.
Oh, hmm.
And why not?
All right.
We'll keep it in the cellar
and make a nice little niche for it with seashells and moss.
And I'll have someone go down and look at it every week.
Don't you worry, Aunt Jane.
Your money will be in safe hands.
Not quite, but I had in mind.
I know.
But I suppose it can't be helped.
It sounds rather nice.
A cozy little niche down in the cellar.
And if you take a look every week,
but oh, dear, it will miss me.
Oh, Aunt Jane.
Very well.
I have made up my mind.
I'm leaving this sink.
It's with you now.
So you and my gold can get sturdy used to each other.
Do what you want with it.
Your friends seem to have ideas about how to spend it.
Flying ships and botanical research sound rather splendid.
Oh, dear.
I'm so happy for you.
Darn.
I should have let us up better than flowers.
So ended the visit of the dreaded Aunt Jane.
And I'm sure Sniff will be able to think of some other use for the gold.
They love the laughter and they love the living the movements.
You're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever!
There were the movements.
One day in Newman Valley, not long before mid-summer on a perfectly ordinary day, Snuffkin suddenly announced that he was going on a short trip.
Where are you going, Snuffkin?
Well, not very far. I'll be back right after mid-summer.
Oh, but Snuffkin, you'll miss the bonfire at the big party.
But why in the world are you going away?
There's something I've been dying to do for a long time, and it has to be done on mid-summer eve.
I promise to tell you all about it, Moonman, as soon as I'm back in Moonman Valley.
Little did Snuffkin know that before he came back, the underwater volcano, which had kept quiet ever since Moonman Papa's youth, would wake up again.
What's all that smoke? Is it the volcano and your father's memoirs?
I don't think I like this.
I think it's exciting. In that case, you can have it.
Moonman Mama.
Yes, what is it, dear?
This hammock is shaking. It's very unpleasant.
I think it's that volcano you told us about.
Yes, I guess it must be.
Mama! Papa!
Oh!
There's smoke rising from the sea, Papa!
Smoke!
Oh, that's very odd.
What is it, Papa?
Let me see!
What's going on?
I don't know, really. I guess there isn't much we can do.
I can't see.
Where is it?
Let me see now. It's my turn.
No, I'm at first.
Yes, no, I've got it.
Oh, I'm clean. Let me see.
No, I'm at first.
Moonman Papa, will the Earth quakes as big in your youth?
No, they certainly weren't. And this one's underwater.
Oh, my net cause a tide of waves?
A tide of waves, oh my goodness, I've never thought of that.
Hey, what's your turn?
Snatch me the net.
What do you think? Can you see anything unusual, Moonman Papa?
I've never seen anything like it. This is very unusual.
Oh my, I want to see it too.
How can you bite during a catastrophe?
Whatever you do, don't rip the top off with you.
You're so stupid, you should have let me have it first.
It's all your fault little my, anyone can see that.
How dare you say it was all my fault.
Oh.
Snork maiden?
Yes.
I'm standing watch over my flying ship, so why don't you stay over in Moomin House?
You'd be careful.
You look after her, won't you, Moonman Papa?
Certainly, Snork. I don't like the look of things.
No, do I. No, do I. We better get inside, Moonman, house quickly.
Yes.
It's scary.
Yeah, the earthquake started.
The earthquake started.
Oh.
What's that noise? Listen, can you hear?
A noise? What noise?
I don't know. It sounds like water to me.
Oh no!
What's happened, Moomin House is drifted off to sea.
I don't believe this.
I think Moomin Valley is flooded. It really is.
What's happened to the kitchen and dining room?
Just because I fear.
What are we going to do?
Moomin Mama can't even prepare breakfast down there.
Oh, good morning. You're up early today.
Mama, Moomin House is flooded.
All of Moonman Valley is under water.
Oh, dear. I think you're right, Moomin.
It's Papa's still asleep.
Let's go and wake him up. He definitely wouldn't want missed it.
Boy, I'm sleepy.
I'm even asleep here.
I didn't sleep a wink because he was snoring.
Little my was snoring so hard the whole bed was shaking.
I'm going to have a nap as soon as I've had something to eat.
Hey, snap.
What's this? Where am I? What's happened here?
Moomin House is flooded, sniff.
This means I'll have to swim to get home.
You'll have to dive to get into your house.
Unless I'm mistaken, the water is still rising.
Moomin Papa, you've got to do something. Do something right away.
I think you better start taking swimming lessons.
And don't worry, sniff. I'll start organizing.
What do you want to organize, Moomin Mama?
Well, dear, I guess we should have some breakfast first of all.
Yes.
But how do we get into the kitchen, Papa?
You just leave that to me.
There, your kitchen.
I've never seen it from above before.
Oh, my goodness.
People should look at their rooms from above once in a while.
Look, cars of food floating from the cellar.
What luck we have a trap door.
Mama, shall I dive in and get them?
Yes, please, Moomin.
Be careful, Moomin. It's got to be done.
Hurry up, Moomin. I'm hungry.
Could you get us some bowls and plates this time?
Sure.
And indeed, the water was still rising.
It's coming. It's coming. Help!
The water's up to the third floor.
What are we going to do, Moomin, Papa? Where's Moomin, Papa?
He's up on the roof, sniff, with the others.
What are they doing up on the roof?
Ah, there goes another poorly built house.
Why doesn't our house float away, Papa?
It's all very simple, dear son. I've built it myself.
If you hadn't, maybe we wouldn't be about to sink altogether.
Here we are.
Are you coming to help me, everybody?
This is one of Grandma's best plates, so please be extra careful.
I know. But where do you think we're going, Mama?
Something will float by. Big enough to take all of us. We just have to wait.
I'm not going to wait for that. I think this family's out in touch with reality.
Something big enough will float by indeed, huh?
I'm going to sink my old skin while I'm still tired.
This is something I should have done immediately, but it's not too late.
Look, there's a whole house drifting by.
Oh, you're right. It's very odd looking house, though.
Yes, it does look funny, but I think we'd better take it.
Hmm. That's the one we're getting.
Somebody help me!
Wait, stop! I'm coming with you!
Don't leave me behind!
Where's that house?
Right over there. Just there. Can't you see it, Snapp?
Oh, that house. What? You call that a house?
Come on.
Hurry up, Snapp. What are you doing?
I just changed my mind. That one looks like it's going to sink.
No, it's fine. We're all aboard. Come on.
I don't believe you. As soon as I'm aboard, it'll sink. I can feel it.
He's scared of his own shadow. Let's leave him. Move any such a whimp.
Come on. It's all right.
Now, don't worry about me. You can let go of the ladder. I'm fine.
Stay behind if you like, Snapp. But what about your breakfast?
We have all the food here, and you might get hungry, and if you do, there'll be nothing to eat.
Why didn't you say so before?
Now, hold the ladder, Snapp. I don't want to be abandoned.
No, brother. He's kind of making you know what it is that he actually ever followed.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, I'm falling off your back.
I'm falling. Don't do the same after all.
Don't shake it.
Don't shake it. Hold the steady.
Excuse us. Hello, anybody home.
Don't worry. We're not dangerous.
You isn't breakfast ready yet. I'm starving to death.
There's no one here, Papa.
I think you're right. It certainly seems empty.
Oh, and the most exciting empty house I've ever seen.
Why do you say that? What do you mean exciting? Do you mean interesting or do you mean scary little my?
Interesting and scary. Look, Snorgmaiden. Look around.
Oh, what a lot of mirrors.
This house must have been full of women who loved clothes.
Or maybe just one woman Snorgmaiden who had as many faces as there are mirrors in this room.
I don't like that. Look, every mirror has a chair in front of it.
Place just like so.
This house was full of ladies and he chatted her a little mirror.
Thank goodness we brought some plates with us.
Woman, woman, woman. Look what I found. Bread and apples.
How nice, sniff. Now we can have a real breakfast.
But where is everybody?
Well, I don't know. Somewhere around.
Whoever lived here must have had a lot of strange hobbies.
You're so right.
Hey, who said that?
Wow, look at that cog wheel. This snork would love that.
I wonder what woman will say about this little my?
I'm sure he'll say you look better without anything.
One look at you and he won't even notice anything else.
Well, if he has any sense, he will fall for me like a ton of bricks.
You want about breakfast, woman, mama?
We'll have breakfast as soon as we are all here.
I wonder where they can all be.
You know, it's very bad for me to go hungry. I always feel unwell if I don't eat.
All right, sniff. You go ahead. But mind you don't eat all the apples.
Leave some for the others, won't you?
Oh, don't worry. Of course I will, mom and mama.
This is an apple.
Oh, but where on earth did you find them, sniff?
In a football.
But normal trick to play on people making false fruit.
I'm very upset.
Oh, this is not bread.
Oh.
Who could have done such a cruel thing to me?
Somebody with a very art sense of humor, I'd say.
Somebody without anything.
Have some cheese instead. That at least comes from moving valley.
And it looks delicious.
Whatever these levers for.
What's that hear you sound? It's creepy.
Can't you hear it? It sounds like a new earthquake.
Yes, I can hear it.
It's scary and spooky and creepy. All you have to try to be on my mind.
Oh, I wonder what it can be. It's very strange indeed.
I just don't think I can take another earthquake right now.
Oh, my goodness. Oh, look. What is it, sniff?
Last moment, mama.
Why? Our table is gone.
This is a haunted mansion, mom and mama.
Well, they can't take grandma's plates just like that.
You can have the plates back, but I'll keep the cheese.
I like cheese.
This is good cheese, dad.
Yes, I certainly did.
Better not let our food out of sight.
Let's get out of this house, please, mom and mama.
What's this?
What's happening?
Oh, we'll have to get out of here.
What?
Papa, was it the witch who was laughing?
No.
The laughter is coming from that ugly one.
Be behind there.
Did I hear someone call me an ugly thing just now?
Oh, excuse us, madam.
You must be the owner of this house.
No.
Oh?
Indeed I am not.
Most certainly not.
You are greatly mistaken.
This is no house you fool. This is a theater.
A theater?
Yes.
This is a stage where the heroin receives a standing ovation
at the end of the last act.
And the bread and the apples are props.
And the rumour you are playing is where the actors make themselves
up to become totally different people.
Kings are murderers.
Oh, and you are one of these actors?
An actress.
You understand less than nothing.
See this brum here?
This is my only prop.
I sweep the dust in this theater.
Oh, really?
I have wielded this brum for nearly 20 years.
Would nobody to help me?
20 years I have cleaned this theater beautifully.
My name is Emma.
Emma?
And you?
You better remember that this is at the theater.
This is no ordinary house.
And it is a great honor for you to be here at all.
That's true.
Does this mean that we can stay here just for a while?
Yes, until the actors return.
Today they all came to a low-verset.
Wow!
That's really cool.
Yes, it certainly is.
We'll try not to bother you, Emma.
Hey you!
Come on, get in the way!
Get out, get in the way!
Get in the way!
You're white.
Woohoo!
Oh!
Woah.
Well, what have you done?
We seem to have hit a tree, so the house has stopped.
This is a theater not a house!
Oh, it's a Rowan tree.
How lovely it looks, how nice to have crashed into such a beautiful tree.
It's gorgeous!
And that smell.
You know what?
I'd like to spend the night in that great idea, Moon.
I'm coming with you, how exciting!
You better stay here, you're bound to fall into the water.
Look who's talking!
Scary cat!
That looks safe.
We could easily spend the night here.
We better tie the theater to the tree, so it won't drift away.
If that's all right with Emma.
Emma, is it all right to tie the theater to the tree?
Do what you want, as long as you don't damage the theater to get here?
All right.
Don't whistle, you idiot!
Don't ever whistle in a theater!
That's the worst luck possible!
How dare you!
Oh!
This is great snorkemaiden.
We can look at the moon.
And the flowers, they smell so good.
What's the matter?
I hope that snorke's all right.
Don't you worry.
He was standing guard over a flying ship after all.
All you have to do is get on board and fly away.
What's going on here?
Huh?
Hmm.
Ah!
No, they're trying to destroy the pamphor's box.
I've never seen anything like it!
These people are bunch of vandals!
Ugh!
Meanwhile, movement and snorkemaiden are fast asleep, blissfully unaware of what was happening.
But whatever will they do, stranded on the treetop.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba.
Women and snorknaten were still fast asleep in the row and tree.
The sun was high in the sky and the floating theater had floated away a long time ago.
Oh, I feel so good.
I really slept like a log all night.
It's so lovely to be out in the fresh air with moon and a tree in blue.
No! No!
The house is gone!
I mean, the theater is gone!
What?
No! The house is gone!
I mean, the theater is gone!
Moomin!
Wake up, Moomin! Wake up!
There's been a catastrophe! Wake up!
What's a catastrophe?
Look down!
The theaters floated off during the night.
I don't believe it.
It has!
It's gone!
I can't see it anywhere.
It must be far away by now.
Moomin, your father's walking stick!
Huh?
It must have gotten loose in the middle of the night while everybody was asleep.
Crying won't solve the problems don't made him.
But we're stranded in the row and tree with water all around us.
No!
We're floating away!
We're drifting away!
Oh!
What are we going to do?
Moomin and Snorkmaiden are still up in that beautiful row and tree.
That's just typical.
Where is it?
And how can we have drifted so far away?
He was the last night, didn't you?
I told you never to do that in a theater and brings bad luck.
Oh, never.
What?
Oh!
No!
Stop it!
Backer to heaven!
Let's go upstairs!
Stop it!
Oh!
Little Mai!
Oh, no!
That was me!
Oh, dear!
Oh, little Mai!
Oh, get this hurry!
You're so mean!
Little Mai is drifting off!
Scenes were stranded and that's not a bad thing.
There shouldn't swim about like that.
I'm too scared to get over to your side!
You must be brave, Snorkmaiden!
I'll catch you so you won't fall, okay?
I told you so, the branch didn't break, did it?
Thank you for saving me!
Ah!
Are you all right, Newman?
I can stand up, Snorkmaiden!
Look, the water's only ankle deep!
Really?
Ah!
Are you all right, Snorkmaiden?
Yes, it's so shallow!
I wonder where I'm going to end up.
It doesn't matter, I rather like this boat.
I'm going to make some noise.
I'll go back to sleep for a while.
It's getting dark, isn't it?
Oh?
Yes, dry land!
Look there!
A fire!
Must be people over there.
Yes!
Of course, I've forgotten tonight's mid-summer eve!
What?
What a strange catch!
So the movements have split up.
Are they in trouble, little Mai?
Yeah, seems I was probably the luckiest one as usual.
Mark!
I'm sorry you can't have anymore, that's all I have.
I don't believe you, your bag's still full.
Yes, but not with food, little Mai.
What's in it then?
You'll soon find out.
Where are we going?
To a park.
I hope there's a hot dog stand there.
Those two over there are the park keeper and his wife.
Look, they're always watching.
They guard a lot of poor orphans who come to the park every day.
Really?
Look over there!
Unbelievable!
Hey, what's this?
Hey kids!
Come on everybody, we're here to let you out.
Come quickly, hurry!
What?
We can't go anywhere.
We have to sit right here so they can see us.
Yeah, otherwise they might lose one of us.
What a lot of signs, no walking on grass.
No shouting, no running.
What a lot of rules.
What are they good for, Snuffkin?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
And that's why we're going to pull them up.
No, you mustn't.
I don't think one is allowed to do that.
And you have to walk on the grass.
Yes indeed.
And I really like walking on the grass.
I always have.
No buts.
Come on everybody, let's make a start.
That looks like fun, I'll pull some too.
What are you doing?
Can't you read?
There's a sign saying it's forbidden to pull a charge.
This one?
Yeah!
Oh, oh!
Sorry!
Oh!
I'm beautiful sign!
Bye bye!
Oh!
There you free!
Go run!
Okay!
Stop!
Wait!
Oh!
What an awesome pose!
My goodness!
Those little balls are shining!
Oh!
Quick, Brian!
Those were howdy fat receipts!
Come on everybody, run!
Oh!
Get out of here!
Someone help!
The rest of me!
Get down!
Get away!
Quick!
That's terrible!
Where could that floating theater have gone?
They're still following us!
Come on you kids, you can go wherever you want!
Do what you like!
Yeah, but I don't know what I want!
Me neither!
Me!
I think they want to go with you, Snuffkin!
But I don't know anything about small children!
I'm not sure I even like them!
All we have to do is find a theater!
Moonman Mama will know what to do!
In that case, let's go!
A house!
Yes and look!
All the lights are on!
Maybe they're celebrating with some relief!
Shall we go there?
Yes!
Oh!
Ah!
At last!
Oh!
Hello!
Happy midsummer!
Thank you!
What can I do for you?
Would you have seen a theater drifting around somewhere, ma'am?
A theater?
Yes, you see a drifted away in the flood, and my powers are on it!
Oh dear, I haven't seen anything like that!
Oh, what a pity!
Thank you! We'll look elsewhere!
Have a nice midsummer party!
Party?
Oh yes, a party! Thank you very much!
Very well then, I'll say goodnight!
Did we say something wrong, Momen?
I don't know.
What's the matter?
I think she's crying.
Oh!
Hello!
Is there anything we can do, anything at all?
Aren't you having a party, ma'am?
No, unfortunately, she's not coming this year either.
Oh is she?
My aunt, my father's side.
I invite her every year for a midsummer party, but she never comes.
How sad! You must be very fond of her!
Oh no! She's an awful person!
If that's how you feel about her, why don't you invite someone else?
She's my only relative!
So invite someone who isn't a relative?
Yes, why don't you invite us, for instance?
Oh!
Can one really do things like that?
Just like that?
Of course one can!
Oh, how marvelous!
To be perfectly honest, we're very hungry!
I've made lots of extra pancakes.
Please come in and join me.
Thank you!
Although we have drifted apart tonight, is midsummer's eve?
Let's drink a toast to Momen, Snork Maiden, and Little Mai, and hope that they're safe.
You better drink to that no-good niece of mine, I guess.
Who's that, Emma?
My only relative.
She lives all alone in a small house by the sea.
Oh, is she all alone for midsummer?
Probably. I always invite me over for pancakes.
I don't like relatives, and I don't like pancakes, and she's boring, so I don't go.
Well, let's toast her anyway, and here's hoping we'll all be together again very soon.
Cheers!
Good health!
Oh, that was really good. Everything was delicious.
I think I've eaten too much.
Oh, please have some more. Oh, this is so nice.
I couldn't eat another thing.
Oh, sad. It's such fun having someone to cook for.
I'm so pleased you're not at my door.
All that's missing now is a bonfire.
We always have one on midsummer eve.
What a good idea. Let's have one.
Over there.
Help! Help!
So glad you came.
See these? The flood brought all of them.
They were lying all over the place, so I tied them into one big pile.
Would they make a good bonfire?
Oh, a terrific one.
Definitely.
Oh, wow!
We've walked for miles, but I can't see signs of a theater anywhere.
Oh, don't worry. We'll find it soon.
Huh? And what's the matter with you?
I'm hungry. Me too.
And me.
I can't walk anymore.
We don't have any food. If you want food, you'll have to look for it yourself.
Oh, don't cry.
Look over there, little lion.
What?
Over there, hidden behind the trees.
Whoa, I have.
And the lights are on.
We're safe.
Hey, kids, you can't go eating other people's food.
You can if they are home, and it's just what's left over from a party.
In fact, I will have some myself.
It's amazing. I'm always so glad.
Oh.
Hey, kids, you can't go eating other people's food.
You can if they are home, and it's just what's left over from a party.
In fact, I will have some myself.
It's amazing. I'm always so glad.
Now we must pick nine flowers.
Why is that Snorke maiden?
I don't really know. It's always nine or seven of something.
Okay, nine flowers.
No, not the same kind. You must pick nine different flowers.
And then what do you do?
You turn around seven times like this.
I get it.
And then you walk backward until you reach a well.
And then when you look down into the well,
there you'll see the man you're going to marry.
How do you get him up?
I think I see him. What a clever well.
That I must try.
I'd like someone more romantic.
Got you.
What are you doing?
I'm quietly now.
All we did is pick some unprotected well flowers.
I know what you did.
Hey, Snorke maiden.
Moon.
Ha, you know each other. That makes it conspiracy.
But I tell you, we've done nothing wrong, nothing at all.
We were only celebrating.
Better for you, if you haven't.
But why? Can't you light a bonfire here, sir?
I must warn you that all you say will be used against you.
I have a complaint from the parkkeeper.
You pulled up these signs from his park and you burnt them.
That's not true.
It is true that we burnt them, sir,
but we didn't take them from any park.
They were brought here by the flood.
Older-dash, here's the evidence.
Oh.
I've caught you when that's that.
Oh, I caught something.
Oh, it's just a piece of wood.
Had any ideas yet?
Not a single one. How about you, mama?
Same here, I'm afraid.
I just can't seem to think of anything at all.
You wouldn't have any ideas about what we should do next.
Would you, Emma?
About what?
Some ideas about how to let the children know where we are, of course.
How does anyone know where a theater is?
I don't know.
Please tell us.
Well, you put on a play.
A play?
Yes, that is correct.
This is a theater.
And when you put on a new play, everybody comes flocking to see it.
They come to laugh, to cry, to shout, and to applaud.
And when your children hear of it, they will be hearing a flash.
What a splendid idea, Emma.
That's exactly what we'll do.
Hmm, I'm sorry. We can't put on a play.
Why not?
We have no actors. They are pests, but one can't do without them.
I can be one.
And I'm also quite good at acting.
I can act very well.
There are only three of you and not one of you is an experienced professional actor.
Don't forget, we have you, Emma.
Me?
Well, I've always felt that I would make a rather good Shakespearean heroine.
And we can each have many parts, as long as they're not all on the stage at the same time.
He isn't at so moment, Papa.
Of course, it's possible to do it.
I want the part that finds the treasure.
No, that's impossible. We have no play.
Nothing simple enough for the likes of you.
A moment, Papa, can write one. He's very talented.
No trouble at all, my dear. Any number of acts.
But we don't want any number. We want three acts.
That's what all proper plays always have, moment, Papa.
Let's start right away.
We gotta print posters.
And clean the stage.
Whatever, if I started.
Aw.
And this was how Woman Papa got started on a short career as a playwright.
But while the birds carry news of the play far and wide,
what has to become of Woman and Snork Maiden?
Their troubles are real ones.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day. The movements.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all. The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV. They are the movements.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird and sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
About our brain.
All over Blven Valley, bits of paper were fluttering down.
No, we're so weak, are you still going?
They were even falling over the lake.
What's this? Oh, litter.
There's some writing on that piece of paper. I think it's a message.
Hmm, hmm. Let's see.
Moomin' theatre presents written by Moomin' Papa.
Moomin' Papa.
The last children of Moomin' Valley.
Starring Moomin' Papa, Moomin' Mama, and Sniff and introducing Emma.
Emma? I'm sure that's my ad. She works in a theatre.
Admission fee? Anything edible?
They're putting on a play. So they can't be lost.
Hmm. I haven't seen a play since I was a kid.
It was wonderful. The best play ever. All about a princess.
She fell asleep in a rose bush. She was so lovely.
I've got to see that one again. But who will guard my prisoners, I wonder?
I'm a good idea, officer. You could take the three of us with you to the theatre to see the play.
Good idea. We love the theatre, so we won't try to run away, officer. I promise.
Hmm. That's possible. I won't let you out of this jail until you write out.
It's forbidden to burn signs 5,000 times each. That's the punishment for vandals.
Well, in that case, you won't be able to see the play.
Ah, who cares? Oh, whoa. Yes, I must see it. I must go.
So you'll take us with you? No, you stay right here.
Well, then you can't go either, officer.
Quiet. You're upsetting me.
No, no. This isn't good enough. It's not true drama.
Ah, please, woman, papa. I don't want to be just a lion's ugly behind.
But, sniff, I did give you another part.
I don't want to be a baby either.
And she said you wanted parts without lines. Could you do the dusting a bit later, Emma, please?
His script should be ready now. We have to start practicing for the opening night tomorrow morning.
Don't worry, Emma. It's coming along.
I'm only half done. I shall never get ready in time, woman, mama.
You're right to worry. For the curtain will rise tomorrow, no matter what.
Women papa will remember to give Emma lots and lots of lines.
She's really looking forward to her first performance.
All right. Now, leave me. I must be left alone to concentrate.
The writer needs peace and quiet.
There are some things I don't like about this script.
I'll discuss it with you after the performance, sniff, after.
If it's a story about lost children, why do you have to have a stupid lion?
I'm too good an actor to be cast as a lion.
I'll keep them out of my hair when India is giving me a headache.
You come with me, sniff. We'll practice our parts.
This could be a wonderful play if you'd only skip the lions behind.
I've heard enough about this behind.
Remember, we have a lion's head, too, dying to show his acting skills on the stage.
This is my play, and I refuse to write out the lion's butt.
I refuse.
Here is the key. I want you to keep a keen eye on them until I come back.
Do you understand me, cousin?
Are they very dangerous?
Yes, they certainly are. They bite if you let them out.
Okay?
We certainly wouldn't bite anyone, obviously.
I've had enough of your lies. Don't listen to my dear cousin. They do.
Well, then, now I'm up to the theater to see the play.
Take good care of them while I'm gone.
Excuse me. You seem to be a very good knitter.
Oh, thank you.
Nobody ever said that to me before. I enjoy it.
What are you making?
I'm not sure. I don't really know. Nothing in particular.
It's just that knitting is so reassuring somehow.
Nothing bad can happen while you knit, can it?
The trouble is I always seem to forget to decide what to make before I start.
But it feels nice and warm, and I love the color.
Can you make socks? It's a very nice sock color.
Socks?
Yes, it's very, very cold in here.
Oh, yes. That's a very good idea.
Listen, if I knitted each one of you a pair of warm socks,
would you really put them on? Of course!
That would be nice. I'm almost freezing to death in here.
It's so very, very cold.
Is it really that cold?
Yes, my teeth are chattering, so I could hardly talk, honestly.
Oh, dear, oh dear. What should I do?
Maybe some steaming hot black currant juice would help to warm us up a little.
Possibly, although it might already be too late.
My cousin would be very angry with me if he knew, but I think...
But you think what?
I think I'll let you out so that we can all be nice and warm indoors.
Really?
Wait, wait, wait.
Don't cry now, baby.
There's a good boy. Don't cry, honey.
That's enough, baby.
Whoa!
Oh, woman mama, you need to show much more emotion.
Try to be more motherly and more loving.
Listen, dear. This is a very heavy baby.
How am I doing, woman papa?
You're just perfect for the part sniffing your performance was excellent.
Maybe I should add a part with some lines in it.
Look at these. I think they might be ready by now.
I hope they're tasty. They don't always come out very well.
You're so kind. We've had so much already.
But they smell really delicious.
They sure do.
Thank you so much. Now I feel warm again.
How about some more black currant juice?
Or maybe one of these freshly baked cookies?
It's very kind of you, but no thank you.
I couldn't eat another thing. I'm so full up.
Me too.
Oh dear, the party is over then.
I'm afraid so.
It's really sad, but I have to lock you up again.
But at least I know you're warm in there.
We're real sorry too, but you don't need to worry because actually we're not going back to jail.
Oh, aren't you?
We've got other plans. We're going to the theater. Just see my parents play.
And I suppose I should say hello to my Aunt Emma, who works there.
Oh, what shall I do? My cousin will be very cross with me.
But you see, we're innocent. We didn't do anything wrong.
You didn't?
I swear it.
Do I look like someone who pulls up signs in a park?
We just burned some flocks and left by the flood.
But your cousin wouldn't believe it.
He's a conclusions, wrongful arrest. That's all it was.
Oh dear, why didn't you tell me that it once?
People shouldn't go to jail when they haven't done anything wrong.
So we can go to the theaters, that okay?
Of course, better leave right away.
My cousin will be fairly disappointed, but I guess I can't be helped.
Wait for me.
I think I'd better come along and explain to that cousin of mine that his three prisoners are innocent of the charge against them.
All right, all right, bring it in. That's right, Mom.
Papa, stop there.
Okay, sniff.
Mom and Mama, what have you got there?
A baby's crib. I want to use this in the play. If that's all right with you.
Mom and Papa, Mom and Papa.
I've just read your script and I think you have a big problem.
Who is going to pay the parts of Mom and Snork Maiden in this play of yours?
I don't know yet. We don't have any more children and Sniff can't take the part.
Are you utterly mad? We only have a few hours before the curtain goes up and you don't even have actors for all the part.
What kind of director is that?
Maybe one of us could stand behind something and sort of read their lines.
Wait, thank you, us. I give up. Let's hope the credits are proud.
Hold on tight, all of you.
Listen kids, you can be as noisy as you like out here but once we're at the dinner you have to be quiet.
You understand me right?
The audience is waiting for us. Come.
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you so much for giving up your valuable time in order to come to our show tonight.
The world premiere of the lost children. This is a brand new company and the players never been performed before.
Ladies and gentlemen, sit back and enjoy the superb acting.
What's that? A baby's cradle. It's for you, Sniff.
For me?
We sincerely hope you'll be thrilled by the originality of the plot.
And so now dear friends, let's get started. Let's get started.
Come on, come on.
There's a good boy. Don't cry, honey. Please don't cry.
Oh, moment, snorkemaid and my darling children. You've been lost for a whole month and we haven't heard a word from either of you.
Oh, he's forgotten all about me.
I'd give the whole world to be rid of this most terrible agonizing despair.
Oh, make your husband try not to fret so I'm sure he'll be back before very long.
Little children, come and free me from this plight. Your mother worries all day through the baby's awake all night. Come home, come home my children to.
With all our hearts, we're missing you.
Louder, Sniff.
But what's wrong with you, Sniff?
This rocket's making me sick.
Oh, dear, and right in the middle of movement, Papa's play.
Mama, let us set forth and find our loved one.
We cannot leave our baby here.
Oh, anyone would love to have him sweet little thing.
For how long, pray, do you think we would be gone?
For as long as it takes, I can no longer stand being this frightfully upset about my children.
Oh, baby!
Yeah.
Hurry up, Sniff.
I'm trying!
Hurry, scene two is about to start.
Help me somebody, I can't get out of here!
When do they put the princess on?
We still have very far to go.
I'm afraid so hurry, movement.
I am hurrying.
It's for bitten.
What are you writing on that, man?
My cousin won't give up, I'm sure.
So I better write this 5,000 times.
It's for bitten.
A full two weeks has passed.
Oh, what shall we do?
Our dear children have disappeared from the face of the earth.
Oh, what's happened, dear apple of my heart?
I think I sprained my hands really badly.
Oh, it hurts.
If you were in trouble, apart from the wolves, we're all alone.
I'll put you out.
Stop!
Why must this happen in my theater?
I've been squeezed in here to make me look smaller.
Help!
I'm trying to.
We can't have the lion on stage without his behind.
Wow!
Whoa!
Oh, whoa!
We have to face the worst and spend the night right here in the wilderness.
Dear husband, will it be all right?
Fairly in these unhellowed woods, I feel quite queasy.
Sweet wife, I too can smell those frightful beasts howling for a blood.
May not just smell them, dear.
Anything that I can hear them now.
I can hear the howling of those hungry beasts.
Paint is the roar, but I can make it out a lion.
Whoa!
Oh, sniff, what's up?
Where are you going, dear?
Oh, listen, I have to go and stop that stupid lion
who's roaming around the countryside watching our every move.
Hey, don't worry, I'll be right back, my dear.
Was he supposed to say that?
Hey, what are you doing here? You're supposed to be on stage.
It's not my father stuck in his crib.
Moment, mama, stuck on stage. Roll a lion.
Ooh, that lion sounds very close.
My husband must be in great danger.
All right, under that stage, both of you.
Papa, I can't get this thing off, I feel sick.
What are you doing, moment, papa?
You can do it with a cradle on, sniff.
No, I can't. Stop it, please.
Don't do it, moment, papa.
They'll laugh at me out there.
Don't worry, nobody knows it's you hiding in there.
Come on now, hurry.
A lion, a lion is this to be my most untimely end?
Don't you dare laugh at me.
Whoa, is that lion gonna eat, moment, mama?
Oh, no, what might you do?
What should I do, moment, papa?
I'm scared, can't be bothered to do.
Let's run off across the stage, dear.
We were supposed to run off together.
Well, the situation has changed.
I'll have to come to your rescue some other time, dear.
Oh, help me.
Help me, please.
Please, hold out, everyone.
They got to really see it.
Help me, please.
Someone, come quickly before I get killed.
Oh.
Coming, moment, mama.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, it's only snap.
Little Maya, I'm so glad you're all right.
Shirley, weren't worried about me, moment, mama.
Well, just a little, maybe.
But you're such a lucky girl, I knew you'd manage.
Mama, mama.
I don't believe it.
Mama, it's me, moment.
It's me, Snorkemaiden.
Mama, mama.
Moment, Snorkemaiden.
Is it really you?
Come here and let me see you.
We've come back, mama.
I was dying to see you.
Oh, it's wonderful to have you back.
Isn't that my niece?
And Emma.
Oh.
You look so grown up.
And Emma, so sorry to have missed your show,
but I have so much to tell you.
Hi, everybody.
That was a great performance.
Snorkemaiden, I'm so glad to see you.
Glad you're safe, moment.
Yay!
Those are my prisoners.
They've escaped from jail.
Catch them.
No, cousin.
I let them out because they swear they're innocent.
They didn't pull up a single one of those signs.
That's right.
I was the one who did that deliberately.
And I helped him.
Very well.
You're both under arrest.
No, no, no!
We were these dreadful children.
Dear dear cousin.
It's forbidden.
Five thousand times. That's what you wanted.
And are you sure there are five thousand?
Oh, yes. Quite sure. I've counted them.
One, two, three, four.
Now that we are all together again,
I would really like to go back to Moomin Valley.
What shall we do with all these little pests?
Snuffkin.
Well, little Mai.
Someone might like to foster them.
You can leave them in my car, sir.
And yours, Emma?
Yes.
Now I have some acting experience.
I think I would like to start an acting school.
Exactly what this theater needs.
What a good idea.
Do you think I would be too old to attend?
Perhaps character parts.
Like in my play.
All is arranged for the best.
So now we can go home.
It is Moomin Papa. I think it's high time.
Quiet, please. I've lost my cup.
Now I'll have to start again right from the beginning.
Moomin Papa, do you think we should thank the audience
for their patience because they're still watching us, you know?
Oh, you're right.
Ladies and gentlemen, that's all for tonight.
I hope you have enjoyed the performance.
I think it was very kind of you to stay to the very end.
Sometimes I could almost believe the truth is strange to the fiction of it.
Well, it is, isn't it, Moomin Papa?
No, not really.
We writers are no better.
Go write more play.
Oh, what a very good idea, Moomin Papa.
I think you're as good with plays as you are with memoirs.
Are you too?
Right, I'll start on the sequel as soon as we're all back home.
There it is, I lovely home.
At least I got a proper wash.
I've never seen it so clean.
What about in sign?
Oh, redecorated, probably.
Yeah.
Let's go.
The Moomin family spent the whole of the following week
making their house cozy and comfortable.
And soon each carpet, each cup and saucer
and every piece of furniture was back in its proper place once again.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The Moons are having fun day after day.
The Moons.
Here they are for one and all.
The Moons are about to call.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the Moons.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the Moons.
One night, the moment was having a dream.
What a wonderful feeling to be flying like this.
Look over there, Moons.
What a beautiful lake.
This is one of the most fantastic experiences I've ever had.
Me too.
I never knew birds had such a marvelous life.
Seeing things from a completely different point of view.
We're flying pretty high aren't we?
I'm scared.
We're much too high.
Let's go down.
Please let's go down at once.
I'm not scared of heights.
Oh snort, this time you really have succeeded.
Will I could build hundreds of these if you wanted me to?
Snort, can I steer just for a little while?
Now you're here.
Oh, thank you.
Do you really know how to steer this thing?
Hey, stop it, stinky.
That's dangerous.
This is okay, really.
It's just a dream.
Oh gosh, my head hurts so.
What a strange dream.
Did my brother let stinky steer his flying ship?
Surely not.
I was talking to the snork while I looked away, suddenly stinky took his place.
Oh, and then the thing began tilting?
Hmm, but it was just a dream.
I don't care, I don't like it.
You shouldn't have dreams like that just when my brother's flying ship is almost ready.
Dreams often come true, you know.
But it was nothing like the ship your brother's building, it was totally different.
But tell me what happened to it in the end.
Did it fall down?
I don't know, I lost sight of it when I fell off and I didn't see it again.
Well, surely you could have turned your head to take a look.
Well, I didn't.
Listen, moment, don't say a word to the snork about this.
He's nervous enough as it is.
Of course not.
Why don't we just forget about it?
Pretend it never happened, eh?
Oh, snork, it's finally completed.
Sure it is, but it hasn't been flown yet, of course.
But it will, I won't snork, you don't think there's anything wrong with it?
Of course not, but it's just...
Is there some problem, snork?
Well, there might be.
So, what is it?
Fuel.
Fuel?
But you said you had developed a new fuel that was really good.
It's good, but you see, you see, it might not be powerful enough.
You mean it might not be able to fly?
No, it won't. You're quite right.
Or it will just be an ordinary ship, not a flying ship.
Oh, that would be nice. What can't go up can't possibly fall down.
But that's not the point if it won't fly. Everyone will laugh at me. I know they will.
I won't laugh, I promise.
Maybe not. Others will.
But you wouldn't care about that, would you? Who cares what other people think?
I've already told people that the test flight will be quite soon, in public.
But I'm sure people will be very nice about it, even if it doesn't get off the ground.
That's hardly what I want.
Moomin, I'd like to ask you a favor. That's why I sent for you. Will you help me?
I'll do anything you ask, snork, of course.
What I would like is for you, Moomin, my friend, to be test pilot for me tomorrow.
You want me to be a pilot?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
Stinky, I'm going to steer that ship, is that perfectly clear? You're not to touch the wheel, I'm the pilot now. What on earth was that about? Wouldn't you find it difficult to steer it? Oh, no, it's real easy, but of course, I'd need to practice before the public demonstration. Is the snorke going to fly his own ship? He'll be there, but he has to stay down in the
engine room, snuff can. I wonder if this ship will really fly. The only problem is the fuel. Only the fuel you say. That's a big problem. I suppose so. Listen, woman, suppose now the snorke's flying ship really gets off the ground. Well, of course, it's going to, Papa. That something could happen, something could break or you could fall into an air pocket. It's such a dangerous undertaking. Think, woman. Papa!
Not natural for movements to fly about up in the air. Is it snuffkin? Quite right. What would you and the snorke do if things went wrong? We will be wearing parachutes, you know? Parachutes. You do know what they are, don't you, Papa? Of course I do. They come down from the sky like this, like this. Exactly, but of course, we won't need a parachute, because nothing will go wrong. And I will be the first flying ship pilot ever!
Oh. Hi there. Hello, my young man. Hello. How do you do? How do you do everybody? Hello, sir. I wonder if you can help me. Do you happen to know where the snorke's factory is? You mean the ship? I must see him. I'm most eager to have a look at his famous flying ship. How do you know about that? It's supposed to be very secret. The information must have leaked out somehow.
You inventors know about what he is trying to do. He's famous throughout Moomin Valley this snorke. Really? Are you an inventor, too? Indeed I am. One of the more famous. I think maybe the most famous of them all. I am Moomin Papa. How do you do, sir? I'm snuffkin. And my name is Moomin. Please to meet you. A very good day to you, one and all. The muffles, my name.
He said I'm the muffle. You mean you've never even heard of me the most famous inventor? Oh yes, I'm sure I am. The muffle, isn't it? Yes, it is the muffle. Have you invented anything exciting, muffle, Mr. Muffle? I would be much easier to tell you what I haven't invented, young man. For instance, the pin that can't prick because it has two heads. The newspaper that reads itself the purse that moans and groans if you take money from me.
The adhesive tape that sticks only to itself. This is perhaps the greatest of all my latest inventions. Whatever is that? This is proper self a man powered fan. Infanible in Moomin weather. All these are my latest inventions.
You didn't know that, did you? No, it isn't. But try and get a handkerchief, the square balloon, the five wheel car, the hexagonal frying pan, the seven hole button, and a host of others. Indeed, how interesting. What did you want to see the snorkel boat?
I thought I might be able to help him out with one of my inventions. That's what? Oh, Jill, which one? My new? No, it's very top secret stuff I can tell you. Now, where is the snorke's factory? I'll take you right there. Very kind of you. Come, he'll be so surprised.
Must be off. See you again. It's a pleasure to help these budding inventors. Snorkel be so excited. A famous inventor, eh? What is your opinion, snorke? Have you ever seen a triangular handkerchief, Moomin Papa? No, when I don't want to either. I do wonder what he's cooked up for the snorke, though. It is sort of intriguing. Yes, indeed.
Moomin will be able to tell us later, I suppose. Yes, but anything could happen before then. Can we wait that long snorke? You're right.
No, wait for me. I'm coming with you. Oh, I thought we had several guests. Now, where in the world are they all gone?
Hm?
Now, where are they off to, I wonder?
Oh, look who's coming!
What are you doing here? We're just interested. Where are the muffle and the snorke? The snorke and the muffle are discussing some top-secret project. It's very harsh. Not a triangular handkerchief, I hope.
I don't know, Papa. As I said, it's top-secret. Let's see. Oh, bother. The curtains in the way, so I can't see a thing.
So this is the powerful fuel you've developed, is it, Mr. Muffle? Yes, it is. Not as original as my other inventions, I admit. But very useful. Yes, useful. I call it super fuel.
Only trouble is my engine has been designed for liquid fuel. No problem at all, young man. If you dissolve this block of fuel in 10 liters of water, your engine will run for at least 10 hours. For 10 whole hours? That's incredible.
If you doubt the word of the muffle, then try it out and see for yourself right now. Right now? Better still, I guarantee that if used as it is in a solid state, your engine will run not for 10, but for 100 hours.
100 hours? But that's incredible. You really must be some inventor. Indeed, if what you say is true, it would solve the last problem of my flying ship.
Oh, now that I've looked more closely at the padlock, this store isn't locked. No, it isn't.
So if one wanted to see the snorke, one could walk right in. But why would you want to see him, Papa? Well...
Why don't you tell us? I don't want snorke falling for one of the muffles crazy ideas, that's why.
Well, we'll find out pretty soon. Maybe you don't realize it, but the snorke is pretty clever, you know.
I think I know exactly what they're doing in there. Yeah, what?
I saw that man pouring something into the flying ship. What was it? Well, I guess it must have been fuel, movement.
Well, how come you saw him? There's a crack that's just about wide enough for me, but I won't tell you where.
What are those two in there talking about? Oh, yeah, so this is the great super fuel.
Wait a minute, snorke, there must be something wrong with it. Yeah, you're right.
What the hell? There you are. Solid fuel indeed, huh? A hundred hours? You're an imposter, sir.
No, it isn't true, if you just let me explain. No, thank you. I know very well why you came over here with that ridiculous story, off with you right now.
Listen to me. It is not ridiculous, and it is not just a story. Maybe we shouldn't have dissolved it in the water.
That was a mistake. Imposter? But I'm the muffler. I don't care. Maybe it's just a misunderstanding, and the fuel isn't suited for flying ships.
Wrong, it suits everything. Forget the fuel. That was just a trick so he could come here and get to see my flying ship.
So the muffler has come here to spy, man. Ridiculous. I don't steal.
Papa, was there anything you wanted to see me about?
Eh? No, I just dropped by. No cause for excitement. The fuels are done.
No, it's not. That's not true. I don't invent guns. What would be the point of inventing them?
Oh, listen to me, please. Let's try and use the fuel once more.
No, thanks. Once was once too many. I'll have to clean my tanks from your gunge. Get out of my sight.
Oh dear, this must have been a bit of a disappointment for the snork. I know.
Now listen, stinky. I'm doing this for the snorksake, isn't that so?
I don't care if you're doing it for all I want is to get a good look at the famous flying ship.
You'd need something very powerful to get a thing like that off the ground. Something so powerful that only I, the muffler, could ever have invented it.
Remind me one day to show you my famous triangular handkerchief.
Now all we have to do is not dissolve the fuel in water but use the solid fuel.
Hurry up with that lock, stinky, or maybe I should invent a lock pick.
Come on, stinky. Hurry, hurry.
There you are done.
Good, come. We don't have much time.
No, I'm dying to steer this ship.
Oh, stinky, stinky. We're flying at a height of just over 2,000 meters now.
Stinky! Yeah, I'm listening. What is it?
When you hear me say now, that's when I want you to start off the engine immediately.
All right, no problem. I guess it must be this one.
No, no, not yet. This is it.
Just a drop of water on the fuel block. Now that should do it.
Can I start it now? Not yet. All right.
Now, start off the engine stinky. Die, answer.
Did you really turn on the switch? Yes, I did.
The engine won't start. Are you quite sure you turned the one I pointed out to you?
I think so. Maybe I turned the wrong one.
Outside these two is where I'll come on.
Stinky, this is no joke. My reputation as a famous inventor is at stake.
These two do it, I think. Is that work, Mr. Mapple?
Nothing is happening. I knew I shouldn't have let you do it better to do it myself.
You're useless. Wait, Mr. Mapple.
I haven't tried the very last one in the row. This one switched late.
What? I better throw that one too. You never know. It might just do the trick.
It works. It works. I know it works. I know it works.
It is working.
I'm not surprised, but I'm so pleased with myself.
You should be here, Snork. This is my great moment. You should be here to share it with me.
Come on, I can't wait to try this thing.
Incredible. This ship's arrived.
This is one of my desert inventions.
Ha, ha, ha!
Pass! Pass! Pass!
Pass!
Pass! Pass!
Come on, let me go! Come on!
What's your power? I don't think the engine has started up.
I'm very much afraid it's exploding.
Hey, stinky engines exploding.
Where are you going?
It's going to explode any minute by wonderful invention.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh electrodes. Now, come to your nice room on the small side, but the very best one. That explosion, it really was most unexpected, officer. Everybody knows you're a great inventor. I wonder if you could help me, Mr. muffel. Look how? Could you think of something to protect my roses while you're staying with us? An-an explosive, of course.
Of course I couldn't.
Piece of cake, officer.
Oh, I really did want to fly.
Come, come now, cheer up, snorke dear.
Here you are, a nice cup of tea.
Thanks.
It's very strange, but I had a dream the other night about a flying ship.
Did you really move in? That sounds very interesting.
Yes, very interesting.
Moment, tell me about it.
Yes, it was a peculiar looking ship totally different from your flying ship, snorke.
Different? Oh.
Well, it was sort of round like this.
It had a propeller and something hanging underneath.
And we flew over a high mountain.
Round?
Yes.
And you were in a sort of thing hanging underneath.
Round?
Round, huh?
What ever is the matter, snorke?
What?
Oh, mama, thanks for the tea.
I think I'm getting a new idea.
Moment, see you later.
Papa, I must go.
Oh, there he goes again.
I know that, look, mama.
You won't get an intelligent answer out of him for the next month or so, honestly.
I'm very happy for him.
I must say that was a very clever dream you had, moment.
I'm a better inventor than the model.
You deserve a triangular acruchy.
So the explosion didn't distress the snort for long.
Soon he was back at his favorite occupation, planning.
But planning what?
Rome?
Yes.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and go as it played.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
When the Henry first told movement about the golden fish,
the woman thought to himself that it must look something like that.
My grandpa told me that his mother had actually seen it.
So you never saw it yourself, Mr. Hamlin?
No, I'm a botanist.
It comes to the surface only under very special conditions.
It's very rarely seen.
Conditions?
Yes.
First of all, it must be right between summer and autumn.
But that's now.
It has to be in the afternoon sunshine after heavy rain.
Yes, that does narrow it down.
And there must be no wind.
Grandpa said not even a ripple on the water.
Oh dear.
And there are some other conditions that he really didn't know about anyway to see it.
You must be extremely lucky.
Hmm, just getting to the lake itself isn't too easy.
It's way beyond lonely mountains.
Going over lonely mountains and back would take at least two days.
Not really, because I know a shortcut movement.
I could take you there and back in one day.
Oh, could you do that?
Yes.
Have you already been there, Snuffkin?
Just once.
Oh, will you show me the way?
You really want to go?
Yes.
I must see that golden fish with my own eyes and maybe capture it.
It won't be easy to capture.
Why not?
From what I've heard, the golden fish is far too clever to get caught.
I know, but it would be so much fun.
You going alone?
Well, Snorkmaiden said she wanted to come along.
She gets these ideas, you know.
Just Snorkmaiden?
Uh, maybe little Mai.
What about Sniff?
I think he wants to come along too.
What would you?
In that case, we'd better go across the mountains.
Why is that?
Why can't we take the shortcut?
The path is rather steep and dangerous, you know, Moomin.
Especially in the forest of witches.
Hi, the witches?
Not now, maybe.
Oh, so it's safe then.
But it's a very deep forest dark and scary even in daytime.
That's okay. We'll take the shortcut.
Oh, dear.
So long.
Good morning, Snuffkin!
Sorry, Snuffkin. Guess I overslept.
Snortmaiden, a little my auntie, yet.
You're very early.
I dreamt I caught the golden fish, and then, of course, I couldn't go back to sleep.
Well, let's go.
Shouldn't we wait for Snortmaiden and little my?
Oh, they're not really great walkers, are they?
And anyway, didn't we decide that we wouldn't wait for anybody?
So it might be better this way.
What's better this way, woman?
Oh, little my!
Why don't you stay here?
This will be a very tough expedition.
I'm tougher than you.
Wait for me!
Hey, walk any faster, Snuffkin.
I'm still so sleepy.
Why did we have to leave so early, moving?
To get there, back in a day, Snortmaiden.
But we aren't taking the shortcut, are we?
Yes, but it still might get dark before we're back.
I won't be able to walk back this fast, you know,
because my bucket will be full of water for the golden fish.
Well, don't be disappointed if you don't catch it.
But that's my whole reason for going!
But you heard what the Himmelin said, Snuff?
We'll be extremely lucky to even catch sight of the golden fish.
I heard him, and now's exactly the right time.
Maybe the others made too much noise.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Don't you worry, I'll catch him all right.
Where are they?
We're going sorely in the morning.
How far is the forest of witches?
I'd say about two hours.
And can you also tell us how long from one end of the forest to the other, Snuffkin?
About the same.
Are there really such things as witches?
No.
Baby, because I'm not a bit scared of them.
Aren't you?
Not the least little bit.
There used to be some, though.
What, witches?
Well, of course, Snuff.
What else do you think that they call it the forest of witches, huh?
And you're absolutely sure that there are no witches now.
I haven't heard of any coming back.
So you're not absolutely sure that there are no witches.
Where's Moomeyerner still in bed?
He was off before you woke up, Papa.
Oh, the golden fish.
Good morning, dear.
I wanted to go with them.
But you're writing your memoirs you're far too busy.
And that's very true with the sort of a fish that no one has seen.
That might have been a whole chapter.
Do you think they'll catch it?
No, I doubt it very much. It's highly unlikely.
In that case, you should have gone with them.
No, I do know a thing or two bad fishing.
Snuffkin does, too, but he's still so young.
Oh, don't worry, I'm sure Snuffkin will manage.
Oh, this is a spooky forest.
Maybe the witch is every time.
Stop it, little mind.
Listen, everybody. Don't stray away from me.
Promise you might get lost.
Oh, it's so dark in here.
Sure, isn't so thick the sun can't get through.
That's because of those clouds.
I can hear the wind.
But we need calm.
Yeah, but we also need heavy rain.
You're right, that's what the Hemiellin said.
It sure looks like rain.
Not only looks like...
Oh, it's raining.
Here.
Oh, thank you.
I gotta say this rainstorm was very sudden.
Don't worry, it won't last that long.
How do you know that?
Vagabons do.
This rain isn't that heavy.
No, it's not bad, but we better hurryer.
We won't get to the lake till noon, and that'll be too late.
I don't think we'll get very wet down here, Mum.
And so why don't we move on?
I'm excited.
What should we do, it's nothing.
Well, we could move on, couldn't we?
Yeah.
Yeah!
We really are getting too wet.
We better find some shelter quickly.
But where can we shelter?
There's nothing in this wood-except tree.
On your tree, then, I guess.
Yeah!
What is it, Snorke, Nathan?
There's a house over there.
It's falling to wreck and ruin.
Well, at least it'll keep the rain off.
Yeah!
Hello there!
Anyone home?
There's nobody here.
No one's lived here for a long time.
I wonder who could have been who lived here all alone.
I know who it was.
And so do we all.
Surely you don't mean.
The Witches, of course.
Look around for dried spices, magic herbs, brums, sticks, and a black cat.
A niren pot.
A pile.
But no, bro.
No, the Witch rode away on it.
There's someone here.
Who is it?
Let's get out of here.
Came from over there.
No, don't.
That's okay, Snorke.
We gotta get out of this place.
Oh, I can't move, Snorke, Nathan.
Stinky?
Pretty good.
I bet you were really scared.
It's very rude of sniff to faint when he hears my voice.
Where are you off to anyway?
Oh, come on, tell me.
Can't you even take a joke?
Come on, wait for me.
Okay.
That way.
Come on.
This is it isn't it yes it is where's the golden fish I really don't know I've never seen it either
with rain sunshine and calm I'm sure all the fish will come the golden fish help me catch it I just got to have that golden fish
oh it's deep down in here somewhere I can't see any fish anywhere
maybe it was a very funny joke the hamula doesn't show let's sit down and wait I'm sure the golden fish will appear for us I don't believe it do me
to say you came all this way here just to see some stupid old fish I came to catch it well that's even more stupid
they stopped making those ripples so they really got excited and walked all the way you say oh to be young again well I would have gone
with them if I hadn't over slept I didn't know that you were that young woman Papa I'm not exactly old you know
pretty interesting to see a fish that hardly anyone's ever seen sniff said that he would catch this
golden fish if it's the last thing he did oh well he had a net and a very large bucket to carry at home
and that's a good one what do you mean I guess I must have forgotten to tell you all the details there's
so much you don't know about this fish
the hamula was certainly right hardly anyone has seen this golden fish and we're not gonna see it either
maybe somebody ate him years ago stinky be quiet please did you see it where did you see it
huh I saw a fish jump but I couldn't tell if it was golden it was much too far away with the sun over
there we just see the outlines norc maiden yes we couldn't really see the color look everybody look I can see
your raft over there hey let's take it and go on to the middle of the lake but it's much too small for all of us
don't worry sniff this won't sink I'm staying you do what you like but you'll never catch any fish if
you're afraid of water stinky you can help me it's gold you know we can sell it for a lot of money
and then we'll both be very wealthy I think it was somewhere around here wasn't it or unless I
suppose hard to say well I can't see anything I did see there's certainly no sign of it now well we'll
just have to sit and wait here we've no choice I'm not going home until I've seen it I'm happy to wait
all day you won't find it by looking up at the sky you know what fish like it in places where there
are lots of wings oh the rafts in the middle of the lake and they just want to see the fish but you
wait I'm going to catch it maybe somebody's already caught it and you can get it in the tin
over there something shiny jumping see I told you now keep quiet
I hate fishing guess we better think about getting back otherwise we'll never get home before nightfall
I don't want to get lost on a raft in the dark on this lonely lake perhaps we were expecting too much
maybe your right snort maiden but I really thought we'd see it this is the most disappointing day of my
life we can come back yes
oh
it's not going to stop
now did you see a moment
oh
it's gigantic
I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do, I don't
know what I'm going to do, I don't know what I'm going to do,
I did it! I caught it!
Pardon what?
Why the golden fish, of course?
What?
I've got the golden fish in here if you want to have a look at it.
See? It's in this bucket.
Huh?
You don't really believe that is the golden fish.
Huh? Huh?
It's just another stupid fish.
I can swear that it really was golden when I caught it.
It must have been the sun making it land in the water.
It was you said it was the golden fish.
Why don't you let it go?
You know it's not the right one and he hates it in that bucket.
Huh?
There he goes. It looks so happy now.
It really was gold when I first saw it.
We believe you sniff.
Now let's go home.
Steph and Stinky never really got home together.
They believed it was actually the golden fish they had caught.
But moving in the others were in no doubt about what they had seen.
They are the emulators of Great Britain.
They believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
Snort Maiden was in a very good mood.
Because that day she was off to collect shells of the sea shore with moon.
Moonman.
Hey look, the sun's up and there's Gracie.
What's the matter Papa?
What's your moment?
What are you doing?
I heard you talking to yourself just now.
Oh.
You see this? I'm writing a play.
Writing a play.
You remember the last children?
That was a very successful play.
Just now I was repeating a line.
Hey look, another beautiful day and there goes Gracie.
It's a wonderful line, of course.
Don't you agree?
It could be improved.
I think about it.
Yeah.
Well, wait, wait, look at this.
Beautiful.
You find anything?
No, just usual old stuff.
Oh, there's another big one.
Can't you really find anything, Moonman?
I'll look somewhere else.
I still think this is the best place.
Well, I'm going over there.
You're so beautiful.
Oh.
What are you doing, Moonman?
No, that's no shell surely.
Oh, so why did you take it out?
Well, once you see it, you want to find out what it is.
A very odd thing, isn't it?
Not very interesting.
Oh no, I can see what it is.
I gave it a good wash.
I see one just like it in the fairy tales.
It's an old lamp.
Yes, you remember the story called a ladder?
He rubbed the lamp and the genie appeared.
The genie might appear for us if we do what Aladdin did.
Don't be silly, Snork Maiden.
Hmm.
But Snork Maiden, that was a fairy tale.
Don't laugh, I just want to make absolutely sure.
The tell you the truth, I've already tried it.
My hands turned green, that's all that happened to me.
Maybe you didn't do it the right way.
You can't even whip cream properly.
And I'm sure you have to say some magic words,
such as, apricot dapura, spirit, come forth,
apricot dapura, try for all your words.
You've chosen the wrong words.
You should say, come out, say something or something.
Huh?
Oh my goodness, oh my goodness!
Keep going, Snork Maiden.
Ah!
I am the spirit of the lamp.
What is your command?
Goodness, did you come out of this lamp?
You got it.
So you really are the spirit of this lamp?
Always have been.
But, but I have the book and you're not him.
I can't believe it.
I've never heard of it before.
You're not him.
I can prove it if you're quite sure you want me to.
By all means, it probably wasn't a good picture.
I'm the one and only spirit of the lamp.
Ah, then you must have the power to make any wish come true.
Is that so?
Her wish, certainly, but not yours.
But I'm the one who'll dug you out.
That's not so important, kid.
She's the one who summoned me forth from the lamp.
What are we going to do about this spirit?
Why?
Ask for something.
Ask for something you've always wanted.
Ah, let's see.
A pearl necklace.
Sorry, me.
Your wish is my command.
Hey, wait a minute.
Oh.
A pearl necklace is only one of the things I wanted.
I hadn't decided yet.
Don't worry, Snork Maiden.
I guess you can always send it back.
If I like the necklace, then it's your turn to wrap the lamp.
Then you can wish for whatever you've always wanted.
Yes.
But where exactly did you rub the lamp?
Right here, and very, very slowly.
All right.
I'll say, spirit come forth.
It sounds a little better than come out, spirit.
Oh, nice.
What was that?
Always back.
One royal necklace, Miss.
This is incredible.
Right.
I do think this is exactly what I wanted.
Oh, thank you ever so much.
All in a day's wake.
So pleased to oblige, Miss.
Are you going back into the lamp?
Yes, I am.
I'm so happy.
Now it's my turn to let you out of here.
I'd like to have a wish granted, too, please.
Now, wait a minute.
If getting in and out is a bother,
why don't you let me give you my wish right now?
Can't do it, young man.
One at a time in the face to call.
Just wanted to save time.
Impossible, young say.
But why?
Because I am only able to fulfill one wish a week.
I need my rest.
It's hard work, you know.
Oh, well, of course it's tiring.
Perhaps I expected too much from you.
Hold on.
I wouldn't like you to think that I haven't got the power.
I can do many extraordinary things.
What kind of things?
Not telling you.
Listen, moment.
We won't tell a soul about this lamp, alright?
Of course not.
No!
Names don't really matter.
Tulip Hydrangea, who cares?
No, that's not right somehow.
And uranium, a fox glove.
Oh, I'm so tired.
Oh, yeah.
Hmm.
Praise the lad and I didn't tell them I can get out at night.
I'd have no peace at all.
My leisure time would be totally ruined by these two.
Good thing also I can read their minds so I know what I'm up against.
They're up to something I know they are.
Oh, yes, dear me, dear me.
No wonder the young man is worried to death.
She was.
I better rewrite this.
Oh, Edgar, Edgar, I do wish you was somebody else.
This will certainly have to be changed.
The whole page, really.
What's going on here?
Who did this?
Mom, not you surely.
What?
Some rascals have been rewriting my play.
Who could that possibly be?
Who in need in the middle of the night while I was asleep?
It's very strange, isn't it, Papa?
It can't be you, Mom.
Of course not, Papa.
I am upset.
Who can it be?
Imagine going into your study while you were fast asleep.
It's very rude, isn't it?
I find it incredible that anyone could do such a thing.
And all the rewriting was done on those bits as I knew
weren't perfectly polished.
Listen, dear, I'm sure they were far too good for him to improve on.
No, no, you're wrong.
That's the worst thing.
I must admit he did improve them.
Then I think you should feel pleased, dear.
Yes.
No, I'm not a bit pleased.
A dramatist should write his own plays.
Looks great, Snork Maiden.
That is, if you like necklaces.
Thank you, Little Maiden.
It was given to me as a present.
Rather nice.
Would you mind if I tried it on for a minute?
Of course not.
I'm sure you'll look gorgeous.
I suppose in time one could get to like necklaces.
I could ask for a similar one for you.
Deepers, who's your rich friend?
Yes.
I searched the whole house, but I can't find it anywhere.
Someone must have stolen it.
The three Mrs. Philly Junk, I fully expect to arrest the thief any minute now.
Good afternoon, Inspector.
Hello, Snork Maiden.
Please hurry, Inspector.
The thief has almost certainly left Moomin Valley already.
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
Nothing is safe in this valley anymore.
Now calm down, Mrs. Philly Junk.
Did you just say you've had something stolen, Mrs. Philly Junk?
My pearl necklace, extraordinarily beautiful pearls, 87 of them.
Looks just like the one you're wearing, Little Maiden.
You stole it.
Did you?
Oh!
Oh, no, no!
What are you doing?
Doctor!
Arrest her!
First, believe her she's a bee, she's innocent!
Little Maiden's beauty!
The smallest character of the most cunning and generous!
Yes!
This is Snork Maiden's necklace.
No, that's very funny, Mr. Philly!
Is that the best explanation you can think of?
No one calls Little Maya Thief and gets away with it.
Is it really true that this is your necklace, Nork Maiden?
Of course, Inspector. It was a present. I swear it.
Who gave it to you?
That's a secret between me and Moomin.
A secret?
That's a lie. They stole it, Inspector.
I've never known them to lie before, Mrs. Philly John.
They're from a very bad background.
You should see their home.
Zora!
I'm going to get fucked up.
Stop the little man.
Bad background and you got ten things.
You say that.
No, there's something I want to ask you.
Little Maya.
What are you doing?
No!
Little Maya has to be a pain, you know.
This is it.
I love to know who did this.
He's sitting there going to knock with words.
What?
Huh?
Listen to this. This is a good example.
Hey, look at the sky. The sun's up and there's Gracie.
That's not great. Sounds very ordinary.
That's what I wrote, Snuffkin.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
That's all right.
Now, listen to how he rewrote it.
But soft, what light through yonder window breaks.
It is the East, and Juliet is the sun.
Arise, Verson.
And kill the envious moon who is already sick and pale
with grief.
What a sunrise.
And note how clever this writer is to change
her name from Gracie to Juliet.
Gracie's worried because her parents don't approve
of her love, Edgar.
I had it as names don't matter.
Tulip, I'd rangers, who cares?
But listen to this.
What's in a name?
That which we call a rose by any other name
would smell as sweet, much more romantic.
I got a show.
Oh, you wouldn't.
Or he'd not a Romeo called.
Oh, it's simply great.
Except maybe I wouldn't have mentioned his smell.
Don't you agree, he's an excellent playwright.
Yes, I agree.
He sounds like a very promising playwright.
And then wordy, perhaps, but really good.
Very good indeed.
Write him a note asking him to carry on.
And there might not be necessary.
You know, all the changes were made in the middle of the night
while I was fast asleep, and usually
writers are in their beds, none of their desks
when they're asleep.
Well, yes, that's the only time you're not at your desk, isn't it?
But there are people you know who walk about at night
without remembering about it the next morning.
Sleepwalk, as you mean.
Now I come to think of it.
You were rather sleepy when you woke up this morning.
You're right, Mum and Mama, even sleepier than usual.
Just so.
You mean you yourself got up at night
and then went and rewrote the play in your sleep?
Well, yes, I have been worried about some minor things
in my play.
So my subconsciousness, fairly rich and literary talent,
as we all know, comes to the rescue.
A moment, Papa.
And in my sleep, my imagination runs riot.
I have all sorts of good ideas that make me
grab a pen in the middle of the night
and rush to my room to let the real skill throw.
Got it.
I got it.
With this, I can have anything.
I can do anything.
Stop.
When I say stop, you have to stop.
He's not expecting me.
I can be a fan of him, so you already.
We've arrived when you weren't getting last.
Get lost yourself.
I don't have time for you.
The inspector's chasing me.
What, you?
Stop, little boy.
I'm the inspector.
You have to stop when I say so.
He's not chasing me, Mum.
Don't deny it.
I know why you're running.
You stole that thing, didn't you?
I know it's true.
That's from the pure business.
It's not yours.
But it must be somebody, so I'll make it my business.
Get it to me.
Or is that me?
Please stop me, I'm going to give it back to me.
Hey, that looks like the lamp we've found.
Chase him, it's better not be.
Oh, no.
Well, man, Stinky's got our magic lamp right after him.
Yes.
We can't let him get away with it.
Our terrible things might happen.
Did you hear that, Stinky?
He said magic lamp or something.
After him.
The magic lamp is mine.
Just leave me alone.
Well, you guys, Stinky.
Help me get the necklace.
No, no, no, no.
This one is taking me.
Oh, no.
Get a stick.
Oh, my dear.
He's coming.
No.
Oh.
You're the spirit of the lamp, aren't you?
Yes, my master.
What is your wish?
You his master?
Yes, me.
I'm the master.
I let him out, so he'll do what I say.
I don't believe a word of this fairy tale's untrue.
Maybe it isn't true, but it works.
I saw a snork maiden wishing for a pearl necklace, and her wish was granted.
Uh-huh, so you're responsible.
Yeah, and I brought it right away.
God, now let me see.
What do I want more than anything in the world?
Stinky, he can only make one wish a week come true.
You'll have to wait your turn.
No, that's very unfair.
Let's get back to the necklace.
Where did you steal it from, mister?
I don't steal.
Well, then tell me where you found it.
Around here somewhere.
Mrs. Philly, John's house, baby.
I don't know who lives there.
Oh, then you did steal the necklace.
Well, that's a lot easier, you know.
How about a magic key that can open anything, Boltson safes and stuff, huh?
Listen, there's something I'd like to ask you.
A sack of gold wouldn't be half as much fun as a key that opens anything.
Tell me, is it possible that you rewrote woman poppers play?
Yes, I did.
It was really awful.
Oh, come on, now I just needed some polishing.
And what's more, see this young man standing here?
Well, he was really worried about your play, you know.
I was just trying to help.
Is this true?
Yeah, safer than mercury, of course.
But then there's professional pride to think of.
I can explain, Papa.
I saw you weren't happy about your play,
and I wanted it to be a big success.
Of course, I didn't want the spirit to write it himself.
I'm going to take the key, yeah.
I've just realized, everybody, the spirit didn't write all that himself.
I've heard it before.
I thought it sounded familiar.
Really, is that so?
Yes, he stole it from a play by somebody else.
This spirit is a cheat and a liar.
Oh, dear me.
Well, I can't help being so well read.
Can I go back in the lamp now?
No, wait, don't run, yes, don't.
I want to explain this now.
Sorry, Master, can't oblige.
Have them put into an impossible situation.
See you next week.
But that's ridiculous.
Not next week, nor next month, nor even next year.
Stinky, this lamp is not yours.
Besides, I know exactly the sort of thing you'd ask for.
A master key or something.
You think you can hide that magic lamp from me, do you?
Well, there's no hiding place good enough for that.
Well, then, I really do think that lamp
is a bit too dangerous to have a rod.
I think you're right.
Snuffkin, do you have any good ideas for us?
We can pass, so we can summon the spirit again.
There's the inspector.
You do it, Snuffkin.
Call the spirit.
Oh, no, not again.
What do you want this time?
Can you bring the hobgoblin here?
I suppose so.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
But why on earth do you want the hobgoblin?
As far as I can see, there's only one safe place for the lamp
where no one can find it.
And that's on another planet, and the only one who can put it there
is the hobgoblin.
He's coming any minute.
Geez, that guy ever hard to find.
Thank you.
I've done my wake for this week.
See you next week.
Goodbye!
And some of the hobgoblin took the magic ram away
and hid it on some unknown planet.
And a good thing too, it would really be very boring
if all your wishes were granted, wouldn't it?
The day after day, the moon is.
The moon is.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
Winter was just around the corner.
And that was the time of year for movement to get restless.
Snuffkin, why?
Because this was the time of year for snuffkin to leave movement valley on his yearly trek south.
Good morning, Papa.
That bonfire looks inviting.
You're up already.
We're buried in leaves this morning after that wind last night.
Yes, winders on the way.
Oh, this is a lovely bonfire.
Yes, isn't it?
I guess we're hibernating again this winter.
Are we moving, Papa?
Well, of course.
We always hibernate in the winter.
If snuffkin says I could go with him,
couldn't I give this winter a miss and hibernate longer next year?
More.
Oh, please, moving, Papa.
Snuffkin would rather go alone, I think, movement.
But I might get him to train his mind.
That snuffkin's not really a person who likes to be pressed.
Why not?
Well, he's a very solitary person.
His winter trip is the only time he can really be alone for a while.
I know, but I was just hoping.
Snuffkin likes you very much, I know that.
And I think that's why he stays in movement valley for the rest of the year.
But at heart, he's a vagabond and he needs time away from us.
He's not a family man, so he's free to do as he wants.
And as his friend, you should try to understand.
I know you'd like to go with him, but I don't think he's such a good idea.
He'd really hate to turn you down, I know.
I guess.
But he'd have to.
Oh.
Why aren't they biting?
I haven't had a proper catch for days.
Getting too cold, is that?
When are you leaving?
You're about to leave, aren't you?
Yes.
Could I ask you something?
What?
Don't go without telling me.
But why?
I'm always sad when you leave, even though I know you'll return in the spring.
Yeah. Me too, sort of.
That's why this year I'd plan to leave without saying anything.
But it makes me even sadder if I can't see goodbye properly.
I'd like to wish you good luck and all that.
I miss you so much when you're away.
Please, Nuffkin.
Moomin, I have a better idea.
I won't leave until after you've started hibernating.
Then you won't miss me, will you?
You're right.
I'll take me right out here, Snuffkin.
Then we won't really part at all, won't we?
Nope.
Because I promised to be back here in Moomin Valley before you've even woken up.
Wonderful! What a super idea!
Hey, Moomin!
Oh, Snuff.
Moomin, come here a minute.
There's something funny caught up in a tree.
What do you mean, funny?
I don't know exactly never saw anything like it before.
Snork made a little myfounded first, but it's too high to get it down.
Okay, I'll come have a look.
Be careful.
Be careful. What is it, Moomin?
I know what it is. It's a kite.
Oh, what?
A kite is something you find in the sky.
But it has no wings.
No, you send it up against the wind on a string.
Bye!
Be careful.
Where'd it go?
Oh, through it though.
That's all right!
Oh, song!
This is what a kite looks like.
Looks broken to me.
I'm sure we can fix it and make it fly.
Let's see.
Oh, no.
The string must have broken when someone was flying it and the wind blew it down into the tree.
Well, why don't we repair it?
Yes, let's.
Looks pretty badly broken to me.
Well, I don't know.
We'll have to see.
It is a kite, isn't it?
Can we mend it?
Maybe.
A very odd kite.
It must have come from far away.
You think it can be repaired?
Of course.
Well, come on then.
Snork will help you repair it.
I can repair it without your help.
As long as you can find us some really long string.
Strong but not too thick if possible.
I think I have what you need.
Some string.
Good.
Excellent.
I'll start immediately.
Good.
Hey.
Thanks for watching.
This is a really exciting project I haven't flown a kite for years.
I do hope that string is long enough.
Snorke, is this okay?
Fine, who's gonna fly it?
I'll do it.
Okay, Sniff.
Moving, hold the kite up high.
Like this?
Hmm. All right, Sniff, are you ready?
Yeah, I'm ready. Don't let go until I say win.
Win, moment!
Ho!
Uh-oh, it's falling.
Try again, and this time start running and when the win catches the kite, you start paying out the lie.
All right, fine. Hold it up again, moment.
Right.
Ready?
Yeah, I'm ready. Let go of it!
Easy going up, kid!
No, it isn't! Stop, Sniff! You're breaking the kite!
I don't think this kite's any good for anybody!
The kite's fine. It's just that the wind is too weak.
All right, we'll have to wait for it to get stronger.
Pretty though, we certainly had a good strong wind yesterday.
Is it okay?
I think the wind is getting stronger, moment.
Oh!
There it goes!
Let me hold the string, moment.
Boy, this wind is really strong! Can I let out the string now?
Do it slowly, mind!
All right!
Let me do it, Sniff! Come on, it's my turn!
I'm afraid you can't, little lie.
Why not? Because you don't win, up to all it!
I'm very strong!
The wind is quite strong! You come up with it!
Yes, Papa?
It's difficult to hold it for a while.
Well, yes, you'd like it.
Hold it really tight, then.
All right, I could do this long before he was born.
Oops!
Oh, what's happening?
Papa, wipe it up quickly.
And I'm winding, I'm winding.
Faster, I'm winding faster!
What's going on?
That was definitely not my fault.
Of course it wasn't.
With such a strong wind up there,
I think we have to lower the centre of gravity a bit.
The kite's all right, Papa!
Hmm, maybe it would take me with it.
That's it!
I suppose that's to stop it from spinning around. Is it snorke?
Yes, that's right.
What is it?
Listen, I'm going to ride that kite.
What did you say?
I think it's going to be okay now.
If I hold on really tight,
I think I could have a wonderful ride on that kite.
Yes, maybe it'd be wonderful while you're up in the sky,
but you've seen how fast it can come down again.
But the snorke just said it won't fall down again.
Even so!
I'm going to do it, but no one must see me
or they might try to stop me if they guess what I'm up to.
Oh, please don't do it.
What are you doing?
Listen carefully.
Yes.
When we fly the kite next time,
what are you two whispering about?
We weren't snorke, Maiden.
I was just saying to Sniff that the kite wouldn't fall down again.
It won't! Snorke is fixed it.
But you can't be absolutely sure.
And you'll be holding the kite, won't you, Sniff?
Me?
Now then, do you want to do it, Moomin?
Yes, and this time I'll let out all the line.
And Sniff, you could hold it up, okay?
Yes, that's fine.
No!
I'm counting on you, Sniff.
And so am I, Sniff.
Hmm.
Are you sure you'll be all right?
Of course I will, silly.
Well, I'm not so sure.
Why don't you keep your eyes closed, then?
Good idea.
Okay, Sniff.
Let go of it when I say ready.
Bye.
Ready!
Go!
Yay!
Yay, yay!
That's it. That's all of the line. It's very high. Must be some wind up there. It's flying really well, isn't it? Certainly is.
This is getting bumpy. What's that? Let's see if there's something very strange happening on that kite.
What is it? I can't see properly from here. I saw something. Could it be a bird maybe? The kite is turned again, but it wasn't a bird.
Or a twig or something, then. Did you see the back of the kite from where you are, Sniff? No, Mom and Mama, because my eyes are closed.
Oh, I think I know who it is. Little Mai. What?
No, I haven't seen one of my four. She seems to have disappeared. Don't ask me anything. I know nothing at all about it.
Sniff, what do you mean? Well, she was dead set on riding the kite. I couldn't stop her. What?
Moment, bring it down very slowly.
Take it easy, moving. That wind is strong. It could break the line.
But that was what a friend was best streamed. It's the knot I wore in the board knot. The one between our line and the bit that was still hanging from the kite when we found it.
The line is fine, if the knot is another one.
Hang on tight little Mai.
That wind is getting stronger.
Oh, this is more scarier than I thought.
I'll just have to hang on as best as I can.
Don't move around so much. I can't help it.
It's almost down. What?
Oh.
It's not open. Come on. Sniff, get up.
All right. Sniff, play yourself together.
Yes, all right.
She's being blown away towards lonely mountains.
Mama!
Oh, I do hope little Mai really is indestructible.
Where in the world is this kite taking me?
All lonely mountains, I'm a long way from home.
Little Mai! Little Mai!
Now she's going towards the forest of witches.
She'll be all right if she fell into a tree, wouldn't she?
I can't see her. There's no sign of her.
Well, I'm almost sure she was heading this way.
What is it, Sniff?
Imagine she might have fallen somewhere. She might be lying there waiting for help.
Oh, stop imagining things, Sniff.
She's still up there. I'm sure of it.
Huh?
What is it, Papa?
I saw something up there.
Little Mai?
No, Sniff.
No, it looked more like the Hobgoblin riding his panther through the sky.
Really?
Did you see that? Did you?
You found the Mai.
No, the Hobgoblin. Then it was him.
Forget the Hobgoblin. We're looking for little Mai.
And all you can think of is the Hobgoblin.
Oh, come on, let's go out here.
Oh, come on.
Oh, no!
Stop it, you're screaming!
Let the white hair stop!
Oh, no!
Where could she be?
This is no good.
We'll never find her wondering about like this.
Moomin, over here.
You found her?
There she is.
Try to cheer up, Snork Maiden.
I'll try.
Don't worry, Snork Maiden.
Moomin Papa will find her for sure.
Eh?
Mama, Snork Maiden!
Oh, no!
I'm so glad to see you.
But I just knew you'd be alright.
Like Moomin Mama said, little lie really is indestructible.
But just possibly it served her right to have her hair pulled.
Hmm, there's still no sign of little lie?
No.
Be careful, Moomin!
Go!
Hang on, Moomin!
To me, Moomin Papa!
Finally, Lenin was rescued too.
But he only certainly had a fine worst scar than little lie.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The Moons are having fun day after day.
The Moons!
Here they are for one and all.
The Moons are about to call.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the Moons.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to Moomin Land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing the best song ever.
There were the Moons.
These days, women and snuffkin were together even more than ever.
Winter would hit Moomin Valley any day now, and then they would have to part.
Moomin, to go into hibernation and snuck into me for his trip south.
Huh? Well, why? You look sad for something upset you?
Where are you off to, Moomin? To the lonely mountains.
How come you two are always stealing off somewhere?
We're not stealing off. We're just going for a walk to lonely mountains.
Just the two of you? You're even worse than usual, never taking any of us with you.
I hadn't noticed are we really doing that?
I'm not sure, maybe we are.
No, maybe he's about it and let me tell you it's very rude.
But we were just off for a walk. I know. Well then, why are you going?
It'll start snowing any day now, little might, and then we won't be able to go anywhere, will we?
We wanted a last look at Moomin Valley from above before that happens.
A likely story.
But it's true. I'm off very soon, and I wanted to see it all to give me a picture to remember while I'm walking.
Hmm. Did you hear that, Snarkman? Sniff, come here!
Moomin, do you mind if we come along with you? Of course not.
You see, we thought you were probably plotting something secret and weren't letting any of us in on it.
Oh, come on, we don't have any secrets from you. It's just that, well, you know what I mean.
Sniff can be leaving for months and months very soon.
Never mind, off we go.
It would be fun to see it all from here in the middle of winter all white.
It must be very beautiful.
Oh, I don't think so.
With everything white and clean?
In summer, it's very beautiful.
Well, I'm coming back here in winter to see it for myself.
You can't do that, you're hibernating.
Well, maybe not. I thought that this year I'd try to keep awake all winter.
You mean just like Moomin and I did last year? Yes!
You could never do it.
What about you? Are you hibernating?
I'm not all that mad about the snow and the cold and dark, so I'll hibernate.
I'm very happy to be going home. I've seen it all now.
Well, we didn't ask you to come along a little light.
Why don't we go take a look at that beautiful lake against Sniff, the one with the golden fish?
Oh, no, that's too far away.
You're just afraid of the forest of witches, aren't you, Sniff?
Not at all, I'm not a bit scared.
Hey, look! Who's that?
Nobody I know.
Wonder what she's doing here.
Sitting down.
Don't say such silly things, Sniff.
Hello there.
What are you doing up there?
I'm waiting.
For what? For grandma.
Out here all alone.
Well, grandma told me there was a big rock by the path leading up to Lonely Mountains and to wait there.
But there are other rocks by the path, you know?
Or there?
But this is the only one I've seen so far.
Your grandma must be crazy or something making you wait in a place like this.
No, our house is in the forest and she's coming to show me the way.
In the forest?
You mean the forest of witches?
Yes, I suppose so. It's not very far from here.
That's it, definitely.
How long have you been waiting here?
About an hour.
One hour?
She's not very punctual.
Perhaps I was early.
Yes, she was an hour early.
Oh, it's grandma.
Welcome, Alicia.
Where do you find all these children, my dear?
I hear all alone and then they came along the path and waited to help.
Very kind of you, I'm sure.
Well, don't just stand there, my dear. Let's go.
Come along.
Excuse me, excuse me, ma'am, but don't you live in the forest?
Indeed I do.
In what part of it?
Let me see. It must be about right in the middle.
Interesting.
The only place I know of is an old house where they say witches used to live.
You don't say, young man.
Well, what do you know? What will he think of next?
Her grandmother is...
A witch, I think?
But surely, they don't exist.
Of course not, like dragons don't exist.
Well, she doesn't seem like a nasty one.
How can you tell, moment?
I don't think that nice girl would have a bad one for a grandma.
Perhaps not.
So tell me what makes you think she's a witch, eh?
Who else could live in that forest, Papa?
I can't think of anyone right now, but some people would like it.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
I hope you are.
I've lived in Moomin Valley for a long time and I've never once seen a witch.
So they don't exist?
Yes.
Oh, stop working now, Snorke. Dinner's ready.
Fine, coming.
No wonder it's so light. Look, the moon is up.
Snorke, Maiden, I think it would be very wise for you to stay with the Moomin's from tonight on.
Why on earth do you think that's Snorke?
I've decided not to hibernate this winter.
Why ever not?
I want to complete the blueprint for my new flying ship by next spring.
For a real inventor, sleep is an unnecessary luxury.
Science, my dear Snorke, Maiden, will not wait while inventors take a nap.
But you know, dear Snorke, how dependent you are on your sleep.
I'll stay with you.
Very well, then, this winter I will hibernate with the Moomin's.
Excellent. Shall we have dinner? I'm ready now.
Most certainly, Snorke. Snorke Maiden will be just fine here with us.
Thank you.
This is nice for Moomin, too. Now he'll have Snorke Maiden to keep him company.
Yes.
But who needs company when they're hibernating?
After all, Moomin will be fast asleep.
Never the less. Sleeping is much nicer when someone else sleeps in the same room.
When do we start hibernating, do you think?
With weather like this in another few days, I guess.
So early?
We'll have snow before the week is out.
Well, good luck with your new blueprint, Snorke.
I look forward to seeing your flying ship in the spring.
Hmm, come this time next year. I'll definitely be flying about.
Thanks again for taking Snorke Maiden.
It's not trouble at all. Good night, then.
Good night, Snorke.
See you, Snorke Maiden.
Bye.
Good luck this winter, Snorke.
Thank goodness at last I can really concentrate on my work.
Huh?
I don't believe this.
Am I hallucinating?
Hello?
Oh!
Oh, which I'm sure it was. I'm positive. I'm a broomstick.
And when the Snorke gets an idea in his head,
it's not much room for anyone or anything else, is there?
I hope you'll succeed this time.
At least in my dream that rounding really flew well.
I often dream that I fly, but I wouldn't dream of trying it out.
Snorke must have had some sort of a new idea.
It's Snorke.
What's the matter?
Oh, that's my piece of cake.
You look like you've seen a ghost.
Not a ghost. She laughed at me.
Who did? She was flying on a broom.
No engine at all.
Are you talking about the witch?
There's no point if you can do it so easily.
Pull yourself together.
You really swore?
Yes.
But where?
Right near here.
I can't see any witch up there, Snorke.
Just the moon up in the sky.
And she was really flying in the sky?
Is that what Snorke said?
Well, he should know about things that fly.
But I just can't believe it until I've seen it myself.
If she really is a witch, then what about the girl?
I mean, no one could be happy living with a witch.
I really don't know. I thought witches had to be old.
Maybe it's not her real grandmother. She could be adopted.
Well, moment, we must get to the bottom of this.
Yes, Snuffkin. We must.
Huh.
Ha, I caught you at it again, you and your secret plan.
Where are you going?
Today you can't come with us with a little fly.
And why not?
Because we're going on a dangerous mission.
We're going to the forest of witches.
Well, if you're in any danger, then I must certainly come along to look after you, Moon.
Come on.
Besides, nothing's exciting to happen to me since I went up with that kite.
This is so exciting.
Ha, sleeping only through a set of four that I must cram in one adventure first.
This is what we'll do. I grabbed the witch and while she's helpless,
you two grab the girl and whisk her away to safety.
That sounds great, but we don't know if she is a witch, little Mai.
If we grab her and she isn't a witch, it would be embarrassing and we could all be in trouble.
Maybe the witch needed an innocent maiden to try out some potions to experiment on her.
Maybe, let's find out.
How do we find out?
By snooping around, I suppose.
I hope you'll think of something a bit better than that before we get there.
Let's hide as close to the house as we can and then ask the girl as soon as she comes out.
And what if she doesn't come out, Snuffkin?
Then we'll improvise, little Mai.
So this is the famous plan by the great Snuffkin.
Look, if she doesn't come out of the house, we'll just go up and knock on the door.
Once we're inside, I'm sure we'll be able to tell what's really what.
I don't think it's a very good idea.
What if she catches us, Bell?
Little Mai will wait outside and if we don't come out, she can run back to Moomin Valley for help.
That's fine, but Moomin can wait outside and I'll search the house.
Oh no, little Mai, you can wait outside and I will search the house.
Let's do it this way.
You stay outside and if we get caught, try to free us.
And run for help as quickly as you can only if you can't.
Is that okay?
Hmm, that means if you're in trouble, your lives will be in my hands.
That's right, little Mai.
I don't like this out of this.
I'm not sure I want little Mai to be my last hope.
Well, I wouldn't now but anyone who doesn't trust me, that's for sure.
Here's that?
See what I mean?
Be quiet.
There's a house.
Look at this.
It's very quiet, do you think there's anybody home?
I don't know, let's wait a while and see.
Do we have to stay absolutely still?
But of course we do.
We'll feel extremely silly if the house is empty.
They disappeared.
They could have told us where they were going.
I'm sure I don't care.
Little Mai went too, I think.
She's betrayed us, that's just like her.
Don't worry, I've got a pretty good idea where they were heading for.
You know where they've gone?
Why didn't you tell me, where are they?
They've gone to the forest of witches.
What?
They've gone to see whether the woman we met yesterday is a real witch.
A real one?
Why don't we go there too?
I'm pretty sure I'll be able to find my way, Sniff.
What is it?
I don't know, it's my stomach, I better lie down.
Oh, it's very painful.
Oh, how much longer we can have to stay here like this.
This adventure isn't the least bit exciting.
Well, let's wait a little bit longer.
Be quiet, at least we know the girl is definitely in there.
No, we don't, she might be out, she could be anywhere.
I know that's possible, but I don't think so.
She's getting some water.
As I thought, that bitch is working her to the bone.
Hey, little boy.
She's following that girl.
You go with her, moving and find out as much as you possibly can about what's going on.
I'll watch the house.
Right.
Hey, wait for me.
Oh.
If you're looking for Alicia, she's out.
Oh, stop.
Listen.
Wait and see.
I wasn't doing anything wrong.
Why did you try to run away then?
Oh, I'll help you with that.
So will I.
How kind of you.
It is a bit heavy to carry, you know.
I think I remember your name.
Is it Alicia?
Yes, it is.
I'm so glad you remembered it.
My name is Lulman.
And I'm Lulman.
What are you doing here in the forest of witches?
Well, to be perfectly honest, we came because we were rather worried about you.
What about me? Why is that?
Is that a woman really your grandmother?
Of course.
You're quite sure?
Yes, of course.
She's my mother's mother.
Why do you ask?
Well, don't you know?
He's trying to ask.
That's cool.
Well, maybe your grandmother is a witch.
Yes, she is.
Of course.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was a bit taken aback.
You don't mind about your grandmother being a real witch?
Oh, no.
That's what she is.
I was husband.
I'm going to be one, two, and I'm grown up.
Oh, no.
You couldn't.
Well, you don't look anything like one.
Well, that's because I'm not one yet.
When you're born into a witch family, that's what you become.
But it's not that easy, you know.
Oh, this is too much.
Now, tell me.
What are you doing here in the forest of witches?
You don't sound like a witch.
Oh, really?
What do witches sound like?
Well, to be honest, you're the first one I've ever met in my whole life.
I'm sure that's just what you think, young man.
Is it true that the nice girl is really your granddaughter?
Certainly.
A very promising young girl.
Honest and hardworking, and with a lot of training, she will make an excellent witch someday.
But how can you possibly turn such a sweet girl into a witch?
The sweetest girls make the best witches.
Hello, didn't know you were back, grandma.
Thank you for getting the water, Alicia.
Oh, who's that?
I don't know.
Some naive young man ought to rescue a damsel in distress now.
I remember you, your snuffkin.
Yes.
Your friend's snuffkins in here.
Why don't you come in, too?
In the house?
Really?
He's brought friends with him, hasn't he?
Self-killed.
Whatever they don't do to you.
I'll take care of that.
Wait a second.
I'll do it for you.
I'll fix it.
Wait.
I'm gonna need you again.
Where are you going?
I don't think that snake ever got bitten before.
I'll get another.
I'm very curious.
Why are you free here, huh?
They came all the way from Moomin Valley because they were really worried about me, grandma.
Weren't about you?
Yes.
They thought you might be nasty to me.
So they came all this way to see if I needed help.
This always happens.
People treat witches as if they weren't ordinary, respectable, responsible citizens.
No, no, we're very sorry.
We realize.
She's quite okay, and she's most welcome to visit us in Moomin Valley at any time.
Isn't she snuffkin?
Yes, certainly.
What?
You said you'd visit these people?
Oh, yes.
I thought I'd go over there sometimes after I'd finished with my homework, of course.
I would never leave my studies half done.
Sorry, Alicia, but if you ever want to become a good witch, you mustn't see any ordinary mortals.
Oh, why not?
I've only just become friends with them, grandma, please.
I know.
Why don't I wait a year and study to be a witch next year?
Alicia.
This is family business.
So if you don't mind, I would appreciate it if you were to leave.
I'd like you to go immediately if you please.
It's snowing.
Well, she certainly won't be able to visit us if Moomin Valley is buried in snow, so we might never see her again.
No, that's right.
And you'll be leaving soon, won't you, snuffkin?
Winter had come once again to Moomin Valley.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The Moons are having fun day after day.
The Moons.
Here they are for one and all.
The Moons are about to call.
I wanna sit down here with me
Therefore you aren't your TV
They are the movements
So come with me, give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land
You can fly just like a bird
Sing the best song ever
There were the movements
The snow was getting thicker on the ground
and it was high time for the movements to start hibernating
I'm so glad I've come to see you today instead of leaving a town
I'm so glad I've come to see you today
Instead of leaving a town
What are you doing, my man?
Alicia!
What are you doing with these pine needles?
That's what we always eat before we hibernate
Nobody knows why
So you're gonna start hibernating
Yes tonight
Oh, that's soon?
Yes
I'm so glad I've come to see you today
Instead of leaving until tomorrow then
I must say you came on just the right day, Alicia
We usually have a small party the night we start hibernating
and you've arrived just in time
Oh, you mean I can stay for that woman, mama?
And by the way, Alicia is a matter of interest
It's the witch, sorry, your grandmother
I mean, know that you're here?
No, I'm afraid I didn't tell her
Better for grownups not to know too much
Oh, do you say you're right?
I'm afraid she's not very happy for me to come here to Moomin Valley
Oh, I have a lot my dear
I guess she's afraid that if I start coming here to play
I shall lose interest in studying hard at my witchcraft
Oh, but you've got a very long time to go before you're a witch
It takes anything between five to seven years nowadays
Are you really sure that's what you want to be, Alicia?
Study something out
But I want to be a witch
Perhaps you don't know, but witches aren't terribly popular
Yes, I do, but I won't be like that
I'll be popular
Hey, Snuffkin!
You're off to the moments?
Yes
I thought you'd gone south already
Last winter you'd gone before the snow started
Not this year, I promised Moomin
Promise
I promised not to leave Moomin Valley until he went into hibernation
Everybody seems to be here
And somebody knew
Who's that?
Half a guess
Hmm
Ah, very well then, it's Alicia, that's my guess
Ah, how did you know?
What?
I'm right?
Yes, you are, but I think you peaked and saw her earlier on
I didn't, I just named somebody I thought couldn't be here
Clever, huh?
Well, she just happened to stop by
She's with papa
Who's showing her around the house
Is the witch here, too?
No, she didn't tell the witch she was coming here
Just as well, thank goodness
Ah, it's you, Snuffkin
I finally came over, I told you I would
Hi
Remember our friend here?
He's called Sniff
Hi, how do you do Sniff?
Well, you aren't gonna use your magic to cast any spells and stuff, are you?
No
Actually, they didn't need just pine needles for dinner that evening
They had lots of other nice things, too
All cooked by Mum and Mama
Snuffkin, I'd like to say how story I am
Why?
I persuaded you to stay on here instead of going south as you'd planned
I'm leaving tomorrow
But the snow is quite deep
Don't worry, I'm used to deep snow
I'm just worried Alicia will find it hard to get home in this
Well, she could spell the night here, but of course tomorrow will be asleep for the winter, so...
Huh?
Hmm, someone's at the door
I'll see who it is
Oh, hello, how are you?
Hello indeed, my young man
My granddaughter is here, isn't she?
Who is it that moment?
Oh, my dear
You must be Mum and Papa
Now, you listen to me, Mum and Papa
I don't want my granddaughter playing with your children under any circumstances
Do I make myself quite clear?
But Alicia likes playing with us
Grandma!
We're leaving
Can't I stay a little longer?
Hello, you're most welcome to stay and have dinner with us
Don't you know I'm a witch?
I can't eat that sort of baby food
Alicia quite likes the food
The pine needles look okay, the rest is yucky
Come, Alicia
Please, let me stay, Grandma
Certainly not, young lady
I've told you before, which is never mixed with people like this
And that goes for novice, which is as well
Never
But they're nice, they're really our Grandma
And I told you, that's the trouble
They are disgustingly, signally good
You will hear a lot more about this when we get home
Come on now
It's really cold out here, and there's a lot more snow on the way
All right, I'm coming, Grandma
Coming
Oh, thank you
Mum and Papa
Yeah
We understand each other now, don't we?
I'm sure you understand me
Never mind about that
You and your whole family are never to speak to my granddaughter again
Is that understood?
But Grandma
Mind what I say over a vengeance of touch will come upon you
Or even the revenge of a serious
If you think cheap threats like that impress Mum and Papa
You're making a grave mistake
Mum and Papa is a highly educated gentleman
But I am a witch with three diplomas
Maybe so
But tell me, how can three diplomas help you to get home with all this snow
Ha, child's play to an accredited witch
Come, Alicia
I've never seen one of these before, a little pep square
Is that really a witch's broom?
Well, I never
Let's go and see
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha
I'm ready!
Cold on died, Alicia
Okay, can you both ride on that broom?
It looks pretty scrappy to me, could fall to pieces, any minute
Do drive slowly in this weather
Oh, please don't fall off, Alicia
But terrible chatterboxes you all are
Please keep quiet all of you
Are you ready, girl?
Yeah
Bet they'll never be able to take off
Huh?
Ahhh, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha
This is n!
Oh, this is new at fall
Come on!
What is it, Grandma?
Nothing!
Oh!
Ah!
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Just what I thought, they're too heavy!
Listen, I could take Alicia's place, I'm not too heavy!
Don't worry, I'm happy to walk home, Grandma!
Don't be so ridiculous, child!
You can't walk home in all this snow!
You'll never make it!
Only I had some skis!
Come on, climb aboard!
I'll try another spell!
Grandma, are you worried because all those people are watching you?
Shut up!
And help me say the magic spell!
Go ahead!
They're doing it!
Yeah, yeah!
Oh.
Where do we go?
Oh!
Hey!
Where's the magic spell?
You are in the water, good bye!
Oh, stop it, Mama!
She may have three diplomas, but I don't think she's very good, Mama.
I wish they'd sing to the ground so I could fly that room.
Guess they're all right now, Mum and Papa.
Let's go back to our dinner.
Oh, I forgot to thank them for asking me to stand at dinner.
Thank them indeed. I don't think you're cut out to be a witch.
Oh, but Grandma, I don't want to be one.
Well, I'm quite happy to help, but the path will certainly be a difficult one.
Oh? Oh.
Mama!
Oh.
With Alessia and the witch gone home to the Valley of the Witches,
Snuffkin departed for his trip south, and the Moomins went into hibernation.
They certainly would have slept till the beginning of the spring, as usual, but this year.
Quite unexpectedly, something happened.
Go away, Master!
Let's get out.
Scums!
Go away!
Oh.
G-
Huh?
There's someone at the window.
It's frozen shut.
Hey, why did you wake me up?
Well, you shouldn't be asleep.
Didn't you know Christmas is coming?
It's tomorrow, so there's not a minute to be lost.
Christmas is coming tomorrow.
But who on earth is that?
Why? Who is Christmas?
This isn't a joke moment.
I'm not in the least ready.
I've lost my mittens and Christmas is coming
and I haven't got a fir tree yet.
A fir tree, I really must get a fir tree.
How very odd.
Why a fir tree?
Hey!
Why?
Oh, what's that moment?
Well, Christmas is almost coming and we don't have a fir tree yet.
Christmas?
Hmm.
Did you say Christmas is coming?
Yes, and before that, one must have a fir tree.
What's this about a fir tree?
Well, you need one to protect ourselves against this Christmas person, Mumma.
I'm not really quite clear on that point.
But there's something awful that has to be kept away, right?
Ah, keep it up.
I better go get a fir tree.
Ha, about the time you move in, Scotta.
How are you going to see?
Pretty good fir tree, Dad.
Well, thank you, Gavsie.
But could you tell me something?
What is one supposed to do with it?
I'm really moving, Papa.
The way you can joke with such a straight face.
Joke?
Eh?
Love to stay, but I haven't even finished cooking yet.
I wasn't joking.
No one believe me, either.
Would you like a little more, young man?
No, thank you very much.
I'm really nice and warm again now.
I saw a moment, Papa, and a moment bring up a big tree.
But what is one supposed to do with it?
Don't you know?
No.
Why, you decorate it as beautifully as you can.
Really?
Christmas is coming, so I better be off.
Everyone's talking of Christmas.
I know.
I've got a long way to go.
Take care, dear.
Hello.
Bye-bye!
Goodbye.
Who was that?
I don't know.
He was in a hurry to get somewhere before Christmas.
Oh, I gave him some tea.
That was nice.
And he told us what to do with the fir tree.
What did he say?
To decorate it beautifully.
Decorate it, but why should we do that, Mama?
I guess we must decorate the tree to make sure we keep Christmas happy.
Yes, you're right.
We'd better start doing it right away.
Yes, I'm sure there's not a moment to lose.
No.
Mama?
Yes, dear.
They also say we have to cook lots of food for Christmas.
Goodness.
Well, at least he won't be eating us then.
Here.
And thank you, Snorkmaid.
Oh, the ship means rather a rock to me.
It will look fantastic on the tree, Papa.
Yes, dear.
I suppose you're right.
Oh, why don't we put this at the top?
This is Mars.
Don't worry.
Mmm, that looks beautiful.
Listen, everybody.
I just heard that you need to get lots of presents for Christmas, too.
Really?
Really, Mama?
I don't wonder what this Christmas will be like.
What if it's an awful greedy, beastly monster like the grove?
Don't worry, Snorkmaid.
We'll give him lots of presents and stuff him full of food.
Have you thought of any presents for Christmas yet?
I don't know what to give him.
Look, a seashell.
Oh, that's a beauty.
Oh, look, Mama, what I got for Christmas.
I'm going to give him a pretty lure for fishing.
I'm giving him this book.
Great presents.
I'm sure he'll be very happy with the moment family and not Thomas at all.
I think Christmas will come any moment now.
So do I.
Oh, dear.
I do hope he likes my pumpkin pie.
He will.
Imagine everyone in Moomin Valley being frightened.
Mmm.
Are you sleepy?
Yes, I am.
I can't stay this scared for much longer.
Better come before all the food freezes.
Oh.
He's coming.
I never thought Christmas could be that small.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. Is that what he is?
Well, it's just what you say.
All of my life I have dreamed of seeing all this up close, honestly.
I never really thought a Christmas tree could be this beautiful.
Brought my friends, too.
You're all very welcome.
Oh, thank you.
Hear that, everybody?
We're all very welcome.
Woo!
Man, let's get him.
There's some wonderful things here.
Yeah!
Oh, what a lot of food you've made.
Yes, all the food there is for Christmas.
And are those real presents?
They are.
All of my life, I've sort of wondered about those things called presents.
Papa, I don't think these creatures are Christmas.
Neither do I.
You look sleepy.
I am.
Must be well past midnight.
What is Christmas doing, Mama?
Aren't you sleepy, too, little ones?
Sleepy with a wonderful Christmas tree like this to look at.
Hey, Papa.
What is it?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Maybe.
Nobody can get really angry this late at night.
Surely we'll close the doors and perhaps we'll be safe inside.
I'm sure you're right.
Listen, my friends.
We'd like to give you the tree and the food and the presents.
What?
All of this?
For us?
Yes, we want to sleep.
We're far more sleepy than scared.
Snortman?
Oh, I see here yet.
No, but we decided to go back to hibernating.
Bye-bye.
I thought Christmas tree should have a star on top.
I don't think it makes any difference, you know?
A nice rose is just as good as a star.
Look at that!
And apparently it didn't make any difference at all.
Because the Moonman family slept as peacefully as ever,
all through the night, without Christmas, coming anywhere near them.
So probably he went someplace else.
They love the laughter and they love the living the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The Moons are having fun day after day.
The Moons.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
During his long winter sleep,
Moonman had a dream.
And strangely enough, he dreamt that he was sleeping.
Moonman.
Huh?
Alicia.
Wow, you can fly on the broomstick now.
Right, I'm a fully fledged witch now, Moonman.
Wait, give me a ride, Alicia.
Can't do that.
Oh, don't be mean, Alicia.
Because someone's already riding with me.
Man, it's me.
Little boy.
Would you mind if we went a little higher, Alicia?
Sure.
Oh, wow, higher, Alicia.
Keep going.
Please, listen.
Come back.
Please, give me a ride, Alicia.
Here you go.
Oh, thank you, Moonman.
Will you give me a ride now?
Come on now.
Moonman.
Moonman, Val, he's really beautiful from up here.
Yes, lovely.
Oh, Alicia, be careful.
Don't do things like that.
What are you talking about?
We're not doing anything, Moonman.
A little boy, it's you again.
No wonder the broom is shaking so much.
How do you like it?
I'm pretty good at this, aren't I?
Where did you get this broom from, little boy?
I borrowed it from the witch.
I borrowed it.
For a while.
That's the witch, isn't it?
Looks like it.
Maybe we better get out of here.
You're right.
Stop.
You two little thieves.
Give me back my broom at once.
No.
Yeah.
You have your own broom.
You witches should learn how to share.
But there's no one who's just a spare.
I want my veil from back right now.
Find yours, keepers.
It's my broom.
Cut that a broom.
Huh.
Why don't you take a closer look at it?
That's not a broom.
What do you mean?
This is not a broom.
Oh.
Hey.
I must have been dreaming.
You were yelling out loud.
Oh.
I'm so sorry.
I didn't mean to wake you up, Snorkman.
Can you see anything?
Only snow.
Everything's so light.
Yes.
The morning's up.
Oh.
What an airy light.
Yes.
Spring hasn't arrived yet.
Has it?
Yes.
Everybody else is still asleep then?
Most of them anyway.
Wonder if my brother's still up.
Well, he did say before we started hyprinating, he wanted to finish his blueprints before spring
if he could.
I hope he'll succeed this time.
When he go out.
Huh?
Outside just to see what the snow looks like.
Oh, no.
I don't really feel like it.
It's nice and warm here.
Why don't we sleep till spring like the others?
Spring is still a long way off.
I guess you're right.
It is nice and warm in here.
It's delicious.
Chocolate cakes, my favorite.
Did you say something, snorkeweider?
I'm so very hungry, moment.
Your mother's raspberry juice is really the best.
It is, isn't it?
Everybody said that last winter, too.
Hey, moment.
Yeah?
I have a funny feeling.
Someone is watching us and I don't like you.
One little bit.
Moment, Papa, could explain it.
I'm sure.
Of course, someone's watching.
What?
But who?
And how do you know?
Too thick.
He told me all about it last winter, snort maiden.
She doesn't hibernate, you know?
She lives in our bathhouse and watches over us in the winter.
She said that many things are too shy to show themselves.
Oh, have you seen them yourself?
Sort of.
Except they were invisible, of course.
Like under the sink.
Or in the clock, maybe.
In the empty fireplace and other dark corners of the room.
Did you actually look anywhere for them?
Oh, no.
They'd be very upset.
It's better not to let them know we know where they are.
I wonder what these things look like.
Some of them look very much like us, too, Tiki said.
Old ancestors of ours from way back, she thinks.
Some of them look like us, she said.
Well, I've never seen them for myself.
I wonder if there is good looking as we are.
Wouldn't it be a good idea to stay up and wait for the sunrise?
A great idea.
Now, don't say anything to scare them.
But this is one of the movement's ancestors from way back.
Is it morning already?
Are you sure?
I think so.
There are no clouds, so why can't we see the sun?
I guess maybe the sun doesn't come up at all this time of the year.
Mom and I don't like this.
I don't like you one little bit.
You silly little girl.
What do you need this for?
Please, grandma.
I won't be long.
I promise.
What are you talking about?
Is if you could fly a broom.
Get back back to me at once.
No, I won't give it back.
Now give me back that broom.
And don't be silly.
How many times from sight tell you you can't go visiting Moomin Valley.
But it's so boring here.
I want some company, grandma.
Come on, broom fly off.
Take me to Moomin Valley.
Help me up, grandma.
Please.
All right, my girl.
I'll help you up, shall I?
I don't believe it.
I'm floating.
Oh.
How far?
This is great.
Wait.
Oh.
I'm falling.
How about that of these?
I don't find them far around here.
Oh.
Oh, don't bury things again.
How about this?
I don't find them far around here.
Oh.
Oh, don't bury things again.
How about this?
Oh, no.
Stop the broom, grandma.
Please.
Oh.
Come on.
You wanted to ride on the broom, didn't you?
You first saw the bike.
Well, here it is.
Oh.
Oh, mom.
Please, don't.
Oh.
If you want to learn to fly on this broom, Alicia,
then forget all about those dreaded movements and really start studying.
It's hard work, you know, young woman.
You must learn concentrate.
Hey, you up there.
Are you making fun of me, too?
Oh, I can't climb down there.
Of course you can.
Even if you fall, you can't hurt yourself on this soft snow.
Don't shake the ladder, Moment.
This is scary.
Slowly does it.
Take it easy and don't look down.
Maybe going out wasn't such a good idea after all.
We can always change our minds and go back to sleep, you know.
See, you've made it.
It's very cold out here, woman, but I rather like it.
Oh.
This is the roof over the front door, isn't it?
Yes, and everything will be snowed up now to spring.
Oh, no.
What's happened to our firewood?
What's the matter?
There's not much wood left in here.
Someone else must be burning it.
Yes, but who and for what I wonder?
I can feel it.
We're not alone in this forest.
I'm sure someone's watching us.
All those winter creatures.
No, I don't think it's them.
The grog.
Goodness me.
Look how big she gets in the wintertime.
Move in.
I'm scared.
It'll be all right.
Grow.
Stop.
Right there.
Don't come any closer if you please.
You're much, much too cold for us, you see.
You could freeze a stiff, you know.
Oh.
Is it possible that you get cold?
Is it possible that you get lonely all by yourself?
I don't think there's anything we can do to help you know.
Not without fur coats and earmuffs and warm gloves anyway.
We must go.
Oh.
Someone's been stealing our firewood.
I wonder what they're doing with it.
Something bad, there's no doubt about that.
Must've been several people did this.
Oh.
We had a lot of fun here in the summer.
Remember?
Well, the she is still here round the ice.
I hope.
Two, Tiki.
There's no one here.
Are you sure?
Look for yourself.
I know they're invisible, but I'm a shroom ice in here.
Hard to tell.
Well, things you can't see.
Oh.
What is it?
It felt like something scampering on my back.
That's all right.
It must be one of the shroom ice.
Moman.
Oh, where could he have gone?
My goodness.
I've never seen anything quite like this before.
Hi, it's good to see you.
You're right.
She's fishing.
Hi, two, Tiki.
Hello, two, Tiki.
So this winter's not made in woke up, too, huh?
I walk her up by mistake.
You know that spring is still a long way off, don't you?
I thought it might be seeing there's no sun at all.
But the sun is going to come back tomorrow, Moman.
Tomorrow?
Snork maiden was so worried about the sun not showing.
The sun will rise tomorrow, Moman, but it'll go down very soon.
Two Tiki, you know, I think there must be records in Moonwind Valley.
Records in winter?
There's an enormous pile of firewood up on the hillside.
Oh, I know.
It took a long time to collect that wood.
But some of it belongs to us.
Hmm.
That doesn't really surprise me, though, Moman.
I'm afraid the winner creatures unfairly careful about ownership.
They need a lot, so if they see it, they take it.
It's for their big winner bonfire.
A bonfire?
Yes, and now your firewood can take part in the big celebration.
They light it every winter to make sure the sun comes back, you know.
Oh, you mean otherwise the sun wouldn't come back to Tiki?
Well, since they always light it on this day, you don't really know, do you?
Tonight you might see the winner creatures.
Oh, can we come along as well to Tiki?
Yes, you can.
If you sit quietly and don't scare them in any way.
Wonderful.
You're coming along, too, aren't you?
Of course.
Stop!
Help me!
Someone shouting for help?
Who could it be?
Go away!
Get away from me!
I didn't do it on purpose!
I didn't mean any harm!
If you don't leave me alone, Grandma will turn you into a toad!
Oh, that's so cold!
Go away, please!
Ah!
Grow!
Leave her alone!
What are you doing, Grog?
Move it!
Alicia!
No, listen, Grog.
Why can't you be nice to her?
Alicia is one of my friends.
She was just standing there looking at nothing when I came down on my skis.
I nearly bumped into her, but I didn't touch her.
That's all right, Alicia.
Tell me, Grog.
Alicia!
Now listen, Grog.
Why can't you be nice to her?
Alicia is one of my friends.
She was just standing there looking at nothing when I came down on my skis.
I nearly bumped into her, but I didn't touch her.
Tell me, Grog.
What's gotten into you?
Why are you so nasty to such a sweet little girl?
It isn't like you at all.
I must have startled her, I guess.
And I did apologize at all, but it made no difference.
This is really, very odd.
Then I asked if she had seen you, and that's when she started to get mad at me.
And she doesn't even know me.
It's a mystery.
Whatever's the matter with you, Grog.
Oh, I was so scared.
I'm so glad you've come to see us.
So am I, women.
Somehow I felt certain you hadn't gone into hibernation yet.
But what did your grandmother say?
Nothing because I didn't tell her I was coming.
Thank you for chasing off that terrible monster.
The Grog hasn't actually ever attacked anyone.
Well, maybe she doesn't like the look of Alicia.
Snork maiden.
It's really a mystery to me why the Grog was here at all.
She was here looking for a moment no doubt.
Was she?
He suddenly become very popular.
Huh?
You don't mean...
What's the matter with you?
I think the Grog may have fallen in love with you, woman.
What?
Oh, you can't mean that.
Please tell me you're not serious.
It's out of the question.
It's her ridiculous idea.
Don't be so silly.
Where's all that drumming noise coming from?
From the invisible shroom ice.
How long before everybody arrives?
Oh, they're here already, moving all around us.
They are?
Where?
I can't see them.
Are they really invisible?
I can't see them either, but I can feel their presence all around me.
But she's been studying witchcraft, hasn't she?
I'm sure you and moving will be able to feel their presence quite soon.
Oh.
I can see some of them looking all over there.
I think I see them too, you guys.
What the hell?
Food, you tell me, why can't we see all of them?
Well, we can never see them all.
I don't understand how did you know earlier all the shroom ice was playing the drums.
I just know because they sometimes play them in the batch house as well.
What a wonderful celebration.
Isn't it lucky I came over here if I had not have missed a most memorable evening?
What's going on here?
The grog.
What?
What's she going?
She must be looking for a movement again, I guess.
No, I think she just wants to warm herself by the fire.
But what's she doing?
Well, that's the end of the mid-winter bonfire.
Poor grog, she freezes everything she touches.
Whatever she sits on, even the hottest bonfire, turns freezing cold in a matter of seconds.
Well, at least she's managed to save some of our wood.
Oh, no.
Hold on tight now, Snorkemaid, and I'll be careful.
I can't wait to get into bed.
I wanted to stay up until the sun came up again.
But I don't know if I could keep awake till then.
So long till spring, man, man.
Goodbye.
And take care, Alicia.
I will move in. The moon will light my way back.
This time the movements have gone too far.
Something must be done. I'll teach them a lesson they'll never forget.
They won't get the battle with me.
Now, what does the witch mean by teach them a lesson?
That sounds very ominous.
Let's hope at least that she lets them sleep till next spring.
They love the laughter and they love the living the movements.
They're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
They're up down here with me.
They're up for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
heh heh heh, heh heh, heh heh heh heh heh, heh heh, heh heh, heh heh.. The witch has come to Murman Valley..
Could you be up to this time?
Eldritch Cabalazum!
Oh, it's snowing again.
I must get a covered brown.
The great thaw had come at last.
The movement valley.
I think I can smell spring.
Oh, I've never seen anything like this one before.
Hello there, Mr. Hemielun.
Hello, Sniff. You're up early this year?
Yes. I think I've even beat Momen to it.
Is that so? Why are the moments so late this year?
Momen, wake up! Spring is here! It's time to wake up!
Maybe Snork Maiden's easier to wake up.
Snork Maiden!
And I thought I was difficult to wake up. I must get closer.
What are you doing, Sniff?
What am I doing? You can see, can't you?
Of course I can, but why are you climbing up that?
Momen and Snork Maiden are still asleep.
I have to wake them up.
Why don't you go this way? It's easier.
What do I do now?
Funny, even Momen still asleep.
Wrong room.
Come on, wake up, lazy bones.
Momen, spring has come.
Well, look at that. Wake up, you sleepyhead.
Oh, you really are impossible.
Momen, Momen, Momen! This is odd, even for Momen.
Open the window, little Mai!
Oh, was I scared?
Oh, I haven't you opened them up.
I've tried, but they won't.
You're kidding.
No one can resist this little Mai.
Wake up, old man. I know you're ticklish.
Momen, Momen!
I told you so.
Momen, come on!
Ah, ah, ah, ah, ah!
Ah, ah, ah!
Oh, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah, ah!
How strange!
How sad!
Eh? What do you mean?
I think...
Well, you don't think...
You don't think that...
It's hard to tell.
I was listening for his heartbeat.
He's still breathing.
And snort-baited?
Wake up, you slug-up ass!
Snort-baited!
They won't wake up.
This is strange.
Why don't we go and try the other?
Yes, why not?
I hate it when others are asleep while I'm up.
But then I don't like it much the other way around either.
Do I sniff?
Moment pop up, please wake up!
We've tried to wake up moment, but he won't!
Wakey-moomin' mama breakfast time!
Come on, moment pop up!
Wake up!
This is no use!
Goodness, it seems the moomin's are still hibernating.
And so it's snort-baiting.
That's odd, she always wakes up even before me.
Oh, moment two, but this year it seems to be different!
I'll go back home, and I'll come over again in a little while
when the moomin' family will have woken up.
If they ever do.
Huh?
We've tried everything to wake them up short of buckets of water
and there's no moving them.
We've shouted and shook and pinched and tickled and stopped!
Oh, dear!
It's not just strange, it's ominous!
Oh, my, surely not.
Hello, everybody!
How is everyone?
What is it?
You all look very scared.
Huh?
Still hibernating?
It's all very strange, have you lint?
Moment!
See?
Yes, indeed!
How we can really do is wait and see.
I suppose you're right.
Don't worry, the days are getting longer all the time now.
So the moomin's can't sleep much longer.
And snort-baiting?
Cheat-tool, of course.
Bet you anything, moment wakes up when Snuffkin returns.
I think you're right, Sniff.
And then, one day about a week later,
Snuffkin did come back from his yearly trip south.
Snuffkin!
Where's the moomin'?
He's in bad.
Moomin' still asleep.
A sleep?
They won't wake up no matter what you do.
What do you think, Snuffkin?
I think they're very sick.
That's a possibility.
Sleeping sickness, perhaps?
It's very difficult to say.
To me, though, if you want my honest opinion,
I think somebody has cast a very nasty spell on them.
A spell?
But who would do that?
I think I know.
Huh?
Are you mean the witch?
Alice is grandmother, but why?
To tell you the truth, I haven't the biggest idea.
How do we find out?
I'll go to the forest and see her.
And if she did cast a spell, do you think she'd tell you?
I really don't know, but we have to do something.
We can't just leave them sleeping here forever.
I'll go with you.
I guess I'd better stay here to take care of things.
Well, if they suddenly wake up, somebody needs to be here.
Snuffkin...
Huh?
That's him!
At last!
Moomin'!
He's dreaming.
Just looking at him makes me feel sleepy.
Moomin'!
I promise to get this horrible spell cast off for you.
Hush!
Where are you going?
I've done all the chores, even washed out your old potion jars.
So, where are you going?
Spring is here, Grandma.
I thought I'd take some time off to celebrate.
But what about your work?
I'm just going out for the day, Grandma.
And I know where.
I only want to know where you're going.
I only want to see the Moomin's.
They're still hibernating.
No, they're not. It isn't winter anymore.
Winter or spring, I happen to know the Moomin's are still asleep.
How could you know what the Moomin's are up to, Grandma?
Hm.
Oh, which is no everything, my dear girl.
Really?
Well, I'll go and see.
Come here!
I have to admit that I can't help being worried about the Moomin's.
Their windows are open for the spring.
So they can smell the first spring flowers.
Well, I suppose I'd miss beginning on.
Why didn't you tell them about the witch in the spell?
Well, after all, that was just an idea, I got.
Ideas can be embarrassing if you were wrong,
so don't tell anyone for the time being.
All right.
I'm going.
And I'm leaving, too.
Okay.
There's Alicia.
Hi, everyone. It's me.
Why do you get a teller?
I can't live the truth, I guess.
The best thing would be for me to talk to her first.
Yes, I agree.
She's unbelievable. How could she?
I can hardly believe you could be so mean, Grandma.
Calm down, my dear.
Why, I did it all for you, Alicia.
You did it for me.
The moments are asleep. Why should you go there?
Do them a world of good, too, along sleep.
How ridiculous, Grandma!
Alicia, you've done quite well in your studies, and if you keep at it,
I see no reason why you shouldn't be a fully fledged witch before 30.
And if I do see the moments, I won't be a witch till I'm 31.
Is that what you mean?
Now, the moments are very bad, and the ones on you.
They are so disgustingly good, and if you want to be a witch,
you mustn't see them.
Hmm.
And if I promise never to go near Moomin Valley again,
will you lift the spell, Grandma?
Good girl, that's exactly what I wanted here.
You promise me, Dan, Alicia?
I promise, Grandma.
Right. The spell should be lifted.
Snuff guard.
What do you want?
There are two different ways of lifting the spell I cast on the moments.
Uh-huh.
The first one is that I go to Moomin Valley myself and chant the magic words
outside their bedroom window.
Oh, Grandma, that's not a good idea.
Oh, oh, you mean people might be upset about me casting a spell on the moments?
You may be right.
So therefore, Snuff Kid, I have no choice but to ask you to perform the task.
Oh, but why me?
You do have your harmonica with you?
Of course.
Let me have it, please.
Eldridge Cabalasum.
If you don't stop staring at me, my witchcraft won't be effective.
Alicia, get me the next potion now.
Oh.
All right, grandmother.
Eldridge Cabalasum.
So she can't do it if we look at her, huh?
Now, listen, Inspector.
You must do something.
You are the police, aren't you?
Well, I have to tell you, waking people up is not really part of our job.
But you're our last hope, Inspector.
You must do something.
Perhaps if you could possibly use your whistle to wake them up.
Uh-huh.
It's very shrill indoors.
Good frighten them.
And fire your revolver.
I'm sure that would do it, Inspector.
Oh, I don't carry guns.
They're dangerous.
Oh, no.
Hey, Snuffkin!
Little Y!
He sounds worried.
I bet they're still fast asleep.
Hmm.
Right, Snuffkin?
Get on with it.
No.
Hmm.
It's not working, is it?
Get my chance, Snuff.
No.
Snuffkin!
Snorkemaedun!
Wake up!
Sprang is here!
Here, come on!
Ah!
Hmm.
Oh, spring is here already.
Good morning, Papa Deer.
Hmm.
Good morning.
I have a feeling we've over-slaped.
I wonder whether the others are up yet.
Hmm.
Oh, she's made a fool of you, Snuffkin.
I'm shot up, Snuff!
Maybe she forgot how to cast off the spell.
Hi, Snuffkin!
Hi!
Ah!
Morning!
Morning, everybody!
Hi, Snuffkin!
I'm so glad you've arrived back already, Snuffkin.
Yes.
You woke up early, too.
Did you hear that?
It's you that woke up late, Booman.
Who me?
Hmm.
Ah.
Now I say, Moomans are ready up and about!
What?
I snored!
Oh, it's you, you're awake.
I'm glad I didn't blow my whistle.
But we did have a reason to be worried, Inspector.
He's right.
What about Moom and Mama?
And Moom and Papa?
Oh, there, everybody.
Is anything the matter?
Nothing at all.
They're awake.
Oh, there.
I don't understand.
You don't understand words.
We were very worried because you just wouldn't wake up.
Oh, really?
You do know we always have a night, don't you?
We sleep all winter and we always wake up in this room.
Of course, of course, but this year, start your telling.
Right.
Well, we did have a bit of a problem.
You see, Moom and Papa, we couldn't snuffkin.
You're back already, yes?
Why don't you listen to us, Moom and Papa?
Very well.
Why don't you all come in and we'll have a nice cup of tea.
And we can discuss your problem properly.
But it's your problem, I'm afraid, not ours.
What does he mean?
We don't have a problem, do we?
Please do come in anyway, everybody.
Please.
You too.
All of you, come in.
Come in, everybody.
I'm on the side.
I'm in Georgia.
Whatever happened to us this year.
Hey, snuffkin.
Alicia!
Oh, my man!
We've come to see you, Alicia.
That was nice of you.
Your grandmother isn't home, is she?
No.
Then we can play hide and seek.
I can't.
I promised grandma there.
Yes, I know.
Snuffkin told me.
That was a really great thing to do.
But you didn't promise not to see us.
You just promised not to go to Moom and Valley, didn't you?
Yeah.
And listen, you never promised not to play with us either, did you?
No.
So, if we came here to see you instead of you to us, then it's all right.
And you don't have to break your promise.
Oh, I suppose so.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Well, let's play.
Yeah.
13, 4, 3, 5, 8.
Oh!
That afternoon, they all had the most wonderful time playing hide and seek in the woods.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Hi!
Jule!
Three!
Your teeth are!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Ha ha ha ha!
Nine!
Ten!
Eleven!
One!
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
We're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
Here they are for one and all.
The movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me.
They're here for you on your TV.
They are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand.
I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird.
Sing that song ever.
There were the movements.
What?
Big explosions could be heard in Woman Valley almost every night.
And women couldn't sleep a wink.
Usually there was just one, but sometimes even two.
You heard it too, Mom and Papa.
Yes, those loud bangs are keeping me awake.
I wonder if there'll be another one.
They seem to be coming from the north.
Hmm, he starts out.
Or they could be coming from lonely mountains.
If you ask me, I believe they're the work of the witch.
The witch?
But witches don't make a lot of noise.
You never know. They're sneaky characters.
Tomorrow I'll have a few words with the inspector.
It's up to him to put a stop to it.
Papa, why would the witch want to make explosions?
Why not?
The first bang wakes me up and then I lie awake waiting for the second one,
which might not come at all.
The bangs might not come from Woman Valley at all,
and they might be just an echo of the mountains.
You think so?
Yes, I do.
Well, at least that's what Snuffkin thinks.
Explosions might come from the sea.
That's what Snuffkin figured.
He thought it might be pirates or something making the noises.
He's already had pirates and they went a long time ago.
I'm plumping for the witch. There's no doubt in my mouth.
Goodness, what are you doing out here?
We're waiting for another explosion, Mama.
You'll wait in vain, dear.
You know that moment, Mama.
Well, we had two explosions last night,
and we've never had double explosions for two nights in a row.
Until now, that is.
You heard that. It clearly came from over there.
Over there?
Oh, no. It certainly came from over there.
You couldn't mistake it. I'm sure of it.
Good morning, Moomin, lovely day.
Good morning, Snuffkin.
You look very sleepy.
So would you be opposed to explosions that kept you awake for most of the night?
Those explosions are really very odd, aren't they?
They certainly are. Would you come with me and have a word with the witch?
Moomin, Papa's convinced that she's the one who's making the bangs.
I think he's wrong there.
That's what I thought, but there's nothing I could say to convince him.
So now I'm going to find out for myself.
You can certainly ask her, but do you really trust a witch to tell you the truth?
Do you, Moomin?
But witches don't have to lie, Shirley.
Is that you, Little My?
And where are you two going?
Little My.
Are you tailing me full-time or what?
Yes, whenever you're sneaking off somewhere.
I'm not sneaking. I'm just walking.
Well, I've never seen anyone walking in such a sneaky way.
Last time the witch tried to keep you from waking up, didn't she?
So, so you think now she's trying to keep you from sleeping?
Well, if she makes the explosions, it's always possible that someone else is the target.
We know very little about witches, and those bangs are probably nothing to do with the movements.
I think you guessed right, but try telling that to the movements.
We don't think it's like that at all.
Wonder if she's at home.
If she isn't, we can visit Alicia instead.
Better ask Alicia than the witch.
Anyway, she's more likely to tell us the truth.
Yes, you're right.
Uh-oh!
Look, you don't seem to realize this is a witch's house.
What do you mean by that?
I'll tell you what I mean. What I mean is, I don't want to be seen talking with goody-goodies like the moments.
You think they'll ruin your reputation, is that why you're so worried?
Uh, there's just something very important we wanted to ask you.
And then we'll leave straight away.
That room upstairs, is that Alicia's?
It is.
Is Alicia there now?
No, she isn't.
Where did she go?
She went to get some wolf's bang.
When will she be coming back?
You're not going to stop her studying.
No, we wanted to ask her something about that loud noise we hear every night.
Ah, that one!
Hey, are you the one making the bangs?
I don't make explosions.
Who is it then?
I really don't know.
But why did you say that one then?
Because the explosions bother me, too.
You think they're coming from near here?
I think they're coming from far away from the sea, maybe.
That's what snuffkin' things, too.
Any sound from the sea echoes off lonely mountain.
So you think that's where it comes from?
Why, as young man, a few days ago, I went all the way over to the beach to see what was happening.
After a whole day's witching and casting magic spells, one needs one sleep, you know.
So, what did you find them?
Nothing at all.
There was only one explosion that night, so when I got there on my brun, there was nothing more to see.
Then we still have no idea who makes the bangs.
No, and I really upset you thought it was me.
When a witch creates an explosion, it doesn't sound anything like a camel cough, I can tell you.
Camel cough, I like that!
Thank you very much, Snork Maiden.
This year I want to grow some black tulips.
Is there really such a thing as a black tulip?
There's such a dark red, they look black.
Oh, I see.
Although it wouldn't really surprise me, Snork Maiden, if there really were black ones somewhere.
We must ask the hamulaneel now.
Oh, yes.
I know it's embarrassing, but I'm so excited I can't go to sleep at night.
Oh, I have no problem going to sleep at night, but that noise wakes me up, Pamulane.
What noise is that?
I told you that noise.
Oh, I see, you're talking about the explosion.
You know anything about it, Mr. Himulane?
No, nothing at all.
No, those bangs are not what keeps me awake, moment papa.
No, I'm waiting for reply from the botanist federation.
reply?
Yes.
Don't you remember a few months ago?
Power strange.
I thought I told you about it.
Well, I certainly told everyone else I know.
I sent them a brand new species.
New species.
I'd never seen anything like it in my whole life.
A new wild orchid.
I'm so excited I can hardly speak.
Really?
A new wild orchid?
How very interesting.
Yes, isn't it?
Oh, it would be such a great honor for me and for everyone else.
They call it orchidaca amulensis or amuliformis.
No, I'm sure they will.
So now you understand why I've had so many sleepless nights.
Yes, indeed.
Trouble is they should have answered by now.
Maybe they're still trying to decide what to call it.
Maybe they can't decide between orchidaca amulensis
and orchidaca amuliformis.
Mmm.
Oh.
What is it?
Now I see, at last I understand.
I am getting no reply from the botanist federation
because it is not a new species.
Oh, of course.
Somebody's already found it.
Oh.
This is too much money.
No, no.
Stupid I am.
This is the end of me as a scientist, of course.
Calm down, don't upset yourself, Mr. Himmel.
Everybody will laugh at me and call me Mr. Amulensis.
Now listen, Mr. Himmel.
The reply is a long time coming because they must examine
your plant most carefully before making a decision.
They must read all the books first to be sure.
You really think so, Mum and Patna?
Could it really take so long, do you think?
Of course, these things take time.
When did you send it off?
A month ago.
There you are, that's no time at all.
You have to learn to be patient, Himmel.
You think so?
Oh, I feel better already.
Oh, I'm so glad you feel happier, Mr. Himmel.
Don't you worry, my friend.
Mama, great news dear.
Mr. Himmelens discovered a completely new plant
and is going to be called Himmelensis.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Congratulations, Mr. Himmel.
Oh, well, it isn't official yet.
No, they're just thinking about the name still.
Give them time.
We should have a party for Mr. Himmel and shouldn't we, Papa?
What?
Oh, yes, indeed.
When, Papa, tonight?
Let me think.
We should wait just a little bit longer, perhaps.
Oh, why do you say that?
Mr. Himmelens, you know that rare plant you found?
Does it have any flowers?
But, of course.
Are they pretty?
Very pretty.
Yes, just like you, Snork Maiden.
Oh, Mr. Himmelens.
Hey, look, Snork Maiden.
Why don't we go and find out about those explosions tonight, huh?
All right.
You'll need me to find the way.
You want to come along?
You bet.
They come later tonight.
I won't go to sleep, bad.
What do you think, Snork Maiden?
I'm not sure.
Isn't there anything you can do to change your mind, Moomin?
I don't know.
Listen, little Maiden.
You have to be careful.
This could be good.
I'm not sure, isn't there anything you can do to change your mind, Moomin?
You have to be careful.
This could be dangerous.
Obviously, or I wouldn't come.
Would I spoil my sleep?
Well, stick close to us then.
Yes, do that.
I also went down to the beach late last night to try and find out what was happening.
And while I was there, I saw the witch flying around on her broomstick.
Oh, really?
Why didn't you tell me so I could have come along?
I could hide better than you.
You're so white.
See, Moomin?
I'm not big in white like you.
Oh, there's someone coming.
Who?
It's Alicia.
Hi, Alicia.
Oh, Moomin.
Hello, Alicia.
How are you?
Have you three come here to play with me?
No, I'm afraid we have, but it's good to see you.
Yes, Alicia.
Yes?
Has your grandmother been kind to you since your last visit to us?
Very kind.
She's been treating me very well.
Ever since I stopped coming to see you?
Oh, good.
But we don't miss you, Alicia.
Oh, I miss you, too.
But I must keep my promise to her.
She'd be upset if I broke it.
What are these wings?
They're herbs.
Herbs are very important for a witch.
And frogs, bellies, and lizard's tails, they're important, too, of course.
I think that's licorice.
That's right.
Very clever, Snuffkin.
We use that for heartburn and coughs.
The taste smells quite nice.
And it also stops cows from giving their milk.
I see.
That's interesting.
Oh, keeps my promise.
I love you, thanks.
Oh, it's a ride.
Hello, Mr Hail.
Mr. Ann Hehman.
Splendid days.
Hello, Mr. Ann Bellin.
I work so hard.
Yeah, I guess I do with that.
Wait, stop.
What is it, Mr. Hemuellen?
My letter. I just want my letter.
There isn't one.
But why not?
You didn't have any yesterday or the day before.
Yeah, I know that. Nobody's written to you. That's why.
Well, somebody should have written.
Are you quite, quite sure that you've gone through your bag properly?
Don't you know I'm expecting an important letter from an important scientist.
It must be in your bag.
Ah, alright then. Go ahead.
What?
Well, you don't seem to trust me to do my job properly, Mr. Hemuellen.
Go ahead and have a look for yourself then.
Oh, but of course I trust you. Sorry.
No, no. You better have a look.
What do you think I do?
Steam them open and read them at night?
No.
Oh, you seem to have a lot of letters today.
Oh, I really think I should ask for a higher salary.
I deserve it.
I'm just starving.
I might have to go over and visit the moments in a minute.
I'm sleepy too. I could go on sleeping.
Oh!
What do you think you're doing?
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't see you there.
Hmm? There's nothing else out here and you didn't see me?
I'm sorry.
Oh dear. What does this matter with you?
Is this place called Moomin Valley?
Yes. That's right.
At last, I found it. I never thought I'd really make it.
Excuse me. Are you alright?
Doctor me, miss.
No, tell me what's bothering you.
Oh, she's ill. She's got a fever.
Please leave me alone.
But you can lie here. You should be in bed, young lady.
Do you know a man called Hamilton?
Yes. Have you walked all the way to Moomin Valley to visit him?
So I have come to the right place. He does live here.
Oh, yes. He lives very close to here.
I'm so glad I must see him immediately.
Oh, what shall I do? I must do something.
Come here, someone. Someone help me.
Oh, my goodness.
Help! Anyone help! Help me somebody!
Papa! Papa!
He's up in the guest room. If you want him, mom is there as well.
What for?
I just rescued a girl, you know.
A girl?
Did you sniff?
That's right. Very pretty, too. She's ill and I put her to bed myself.
I'm going to see her.
Me, too.
I want another look as well.
First, we must bring her fever down.
I think you're right.
Yes?
Sniff just told us about her.
Oh, dear. Is she unconscious?
Yes.
Where'd she come from?
We don't know a little, Maya, but Sniff said she'd come here to visit the hemeland.
That's right. Snort Maidens gone to get him.
She's pretty, isn't she?
You're right. Very.
By the way, Moomin, what did the witch say?
Oh, dear. I thought I'd really run like this.
She's missing her young girl.
Well, if she's sick, why don't you give her some medicine?
I don't know any young girls apart from her.
Don't. Just keep running.
I told you. I do not know this person.
Maybe she's changed.
I've already told you.
I have never known any young girls.
Then why do you think she'd want to come to visit you, Hamilton?
She's a botanist.
And obviously, she's heard of me and wants to come and see the famous hemeland for herself.
Oh, dear. She can tell us when she wakes up.
We must leave her now so that grandma's medicine can work.
I think I'll be getting home.
Oh, we couldn't let you go just like that.
Please, stay and have some tea with us.
Thank you, but no, I have some plans to press.
And you're sure you're quite sure you don't know this girl?
Absolutely certain.
I really must go.
I'd forgotten all about the bangs.
Well, we haven't snuffed Ken and I.
I'm going to look for them tonight.
I'd like to come too, but I can't.
I'm going with them.
Are you snort maiden?
You'll be hiding on the beach in the middle of the night?
Yes. And then we'll rush off to where the bangs are coming from as soon as we hear them.
That's the plan.
Oh, I'd really love to come.
I'd rather go to bed.
I'd be a bit scared of the beach in the middle of the night.
After all, it's my duty to stay here with movement mama.
Are you coming, sniff?
Certainly not. Not me.
It just occurred to me that's why she's here.
Oh.
Here, you better take this movement.
You might get very hungry.
Oh, thank you, mama.
A midnight snack. I really envy you.
Well, then, Papa. Why don't you come with us?
Oh, there's nothing I'd love more, but I'd better not tonight. Right, mama?
Oh, definitely not.
What would I do if something happened to the girl while you were away?
Exactly.
All right, Papa. We'll find out about the bangs for you.
Thank you, mama.
Mmm.
Mmm. Good.
I think we should save this food for a while.
We might have to wait a long time for the explosions.
And they might not come tonight.
Stop stuffing yourself, Moon, and the rest is for a snuck in and me.
But you can't eat anymore?
Yes, I can. We must share it in equal parts, otherwise it's not fair.
I think it should be shared in proportion to how big one is.
Mmm.
Uh, where are the fingerprints?
to see. Keep a sharp look out. Look over there. What is it?
That's what I call fireworks.
Come on. Somebody must be out there in a boat.
There's a boat.
The fireworks must have come from there. Hey, come ashore!
Is that the hemuline you think? No, I don't think so. It looks like him, but he was much younger.
And so as a result of their excursion to the beach, they finally learned that the big bangs that had been waking everyone up were fireworks.
They also learned that the fireworks were coming from a boat far out to sea.
But the man who had sent them up disappeared into the night.
The Moons are having fun day after day. The Moons. The Moons. The Moons.