Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements,
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
la la la la la, la la la, la la
Oh, um...
At last!
It's spring!
Wake up, everyone!
It's spring time!
Oh, little mind, you're up!
It's hard to stay asleep with you yelling!
I can't help it if I'm happy!
So yeah, woke me!
I was having a lovely dream about living in a watermelon!
But it's beautiful outside!
Oh, gee, isn't it?
Is it really moving?
Yes, it's all fresh!
The flowers are out, and the sun is shining!
So, I like being asleep!
I can't help it if I'm happy!
But it's spring!
You said you wanted me to wake you as soon as spring was here!
Oh, boy, did I?
Yes, you did, little mind!
You said you wanted to be a welcome as soon as spring was here!
Really?
Yes, you did!
Hmm, did I say something like that?
You can go back to bed if you want to!
Nobody's making you get up, little mind!
No, there's really no point movement!
I'm not sleepy anymore!
Well, there you are then!
You are then!
Mama!
Good spring, movement!
Movement, mama!
I'm starving! Have you got any watermelon?
No, but there's lots of other things!
We'll all have a nice big breakfast!
I can hear a snuffkin!
Wouldn't it be quicker to use the stairs?
More fun this way!
Are you going home now?
Yes, thanks very much for letting me spend the winter here!
Don't think your sister will be back yet, though!
I'll go anyway!
Snuffkin!
Oh, hello, movement!
It's really good to see you, Snuffkin!
And you too!
You're back, Arlie!
Aren't you having a good time?
Yes, I was!
But I didn't want to miss springtime in movement valley!
What did you do?
I'll tell you later.
Let's go wake up, Sniff, and think of something exciting to do!
I don't think I'll like it!
He's still snoring, movement!
I'll do it again!
Well, that's done it!
Come on, Sniff! It's spring! Snuffkin's here!
Please go away, you two!
We're going to do something really exciting!
Like what, moment?
I can think of more exciting things to do than this!
Well, let's imagine that we're the first ever to climb this mountain!
It's such a clear day!
We'll be able to see all of movement valley when we get to the top and the sea!
Good morning, Mr. Emulets!
Morning, moment!
Are your father and mother up?
Yes!
Mama was when I came out!
I'll never understand how you can sleep for months on end!
Why do they always have to do something exciting?
What a gorgeous view!
It really is!
Hey, look!
They're small coming from moment house!
We should have stayed at home!
My bet, moment, mama's cooking something good!
Look!
What is it?
We're not the first here after all!
Look over there!
A top hat!
Hmm, a rather large one!
I wonder who's had it is!
Hmm, I don't know, but I know papa would like it!
Hmm, it's much too big!
Look!
Oh dear, what's that?
Oh, I can really get inside it!
You see, I cover it for my old one!
Oh, I can't moment it!
Stuck, moment!
No, that's enough nonsense!
I think I'll take it off now!
What's the matter?
I can't move it! It's stuck, moment!
I'll give you a hand!
Oh, that's better!
Thank you!
What's all this noise?
Papa's head got stuck in the hat, mama!
Oh, yes, and where did that come from?
Oh, moment, mama!
The children found it when they were out and brought it back for me!
It's very smart!
What shall we do with it, papa?
There is something strange about it!
Shall I throw it away then?
Oh no!
It's too good for that!
Do we know anyone with a very big head?
No, move in, papa!
I know what we can do with it!
Ah!
It's a...
A waste paper basket, move a mama!
That's right! Well done, Snuffkin!
That was easy!
Come on, Snuffkin!
Come and have some breakfast with us!
Thank you!
Mmm, beautiful!
Yes!
Sorry to disturb you, but I'm going to see a moment!
Uh-huh!
Do you want to come with me, Snork?
Or would you rather stay here?
Uh-huh!
Well, are you coming or not?
Snork!
Well, you know my flying ship is almost finished!
It'll be ready this year!
You'll see!
Whoa!
Oh, dear!
Perhaps it needs a little more work!
I wonder if you really can make a flying ship!
Don't be silly, of course you can't!
A little, my Snorks always dreamed about doing it!
Dreams are all right!
Yes, as long as they're not impossible!
I suppose so!
Mmm!
Snuff, you're not still feeding your face, are you?
Do you ever dream, Snuff?
Only nightmares about having no food at all, little my!
Mmm, I wonder who dropped this!
Now where can I put it?
Oh!
There you are!
Just the thing!
Oh!
Wow!
Golly, what are they?
They're clouds!
Be careful!
Don't touch it! It might be poisonous!
It feels like cotton!
Well, ee!
This is great! I'm floating!
Wonderful!
Can I try?
Are you ready, Snork Maiden?
Here we go!
Yeah!
What if you go too high?
My phone!
Wait for me!
Hey, wait for me!
Whoa!
Let me get on!
Hey!
Help! I'm falling!
Moomin Papa is in his study trying to write his memoirs.
A lot has happened to him over the years.
An awful lot.
And he's trying to remember it.
Huh?
What was that?
Moomin!
Hi, Papa!
What are you doing out there?
We're flying!
The clouds just came out of the house!
Yeah, try and get nearer so I can reach you!
Oh!
No, I'm alright!
Why don't you come for a ride?
Stop! Wait a minute!
It's great!
You feel it!
It's great! You feel like a bird!
Moomin!
Oh!
Come on, Papa! Jump or you'll fall!
I hate it!
Moomin! Mama! Quickly!
What's the matter?
Have you seen what the children are doing?
Yes!
Look at them! They're flying about on clouds!
It can't be safe!
Papa, it's alright!
I told them to be careful!
Come on, snappy!
Come on!
I won! I won!
Whoa!
Hey, wait a minute, little cloud!
Wait for me! Don't go away!
Oh, I got you!
That is tree cotton!
I'm going to climb right up here!
And I'm going to get you right there!
I'm going to take you with me!
Hey, come on! You just keep coming back!
Yeah, I got you now!
You are going to get away from me!
Here I go! Come on!
All of that ledge!
Stop!
Oh, boy! What's happening?
My cloud's starting to go!
Oh, whoa, whoa! That was fun!
Yeah, it was, but I wasn't ready to stop!
Look, there's movement in Snork Maiden!
Hey!
Why have they still got clouds snuffed in?
There's a starting to go as well!
I think they'd better get off!
Hey!
Right, I'll start counting!
One, two, three!
Do you want something little more?
Yes! A place to hide!
Five!
Six!
Seven!
Boy, I don't think there's any place to hide, and here is there!
Nine!
Oh, it's too dirty in here!
Oh, it's too dirty in there!
Nine and a half!
I know! I'll hide in the head!
One, two, one, two, one!
Huh?
Gotcha!
Snort made, huh?
Boom!
Moomin must be around here somewhere!
Well, last time I saw him, he was hiding in the fireplace!
Have you found him yet?
No!
Have you looked in the cellar?
Yes, I have!
Wait a minute, did you hear someone laughing?
Where'd it come from?
Chi, I better go home!
Oh, is there anything wrong?
Yes, I can't find Moomin anywhere!
Well, he's too fat to be most places!
Hahaha!
He's coming from under the hat!
Well, here I am, sniff!
Oh, on earth are you!
Hahaha!
I one land didn't I?
You looked everywhere in the house,
and you couldn't find me, could you?
So I won!
Who'd want to find you anyway?
Well, you were trying hard enough, weren't you?
What is this, a new game?
My name's Snork Maiden!
What's yours?
I'm the King of Moomin Valley!
My pretty one!
You're too ugly to be the King of anything!
Well, now!
That's not a very nice thing to say to your friend!
Is it Papa?
Now you'd better tell me what you have done with Moomin, huh?
But I'm here!
Where?
Are you? And where is Moomin?
Oh...
Papa!
I'm certainly not your Papa!
Yes you are! Come on! I'm Moomin!
I don't know who you are!
But you're not Moomin!
He's nice and handsome and nothing like you!
Have you looked at yourself in a mirror?
Ah!
Where's my nose gone?
Oh, there's nothing there anymore!
Oh no! My tail's all pushed!
Ah!
Oh!
This is terrible!
Who are you?
What have you done with me?
It must be a nightmare!
I want to come back!
Go away, you're horrible!
Dear me, what's all this noise?
What's happened?
Mama!
What earth is this?
He says he's Moomin, but just look at him!
You don't look like I'm Moomin!
I am!
Please believe me, Mama!
I am Moomin!
Well, I don't know. I'm sure!
Something's happened to me!
Why do I look so different?
Now then calm down!
This won't help at all!
We don't need all this noise!
If you really are Moomin,
then everything will be alright!
Just give me a minute or two and I'll know!
Mama, call me Moomin!
Please!
I don't know what's happened, but I am me!
Honestly, I am!
Mama, please believe me!
I am Moomin!
Oh, Mama, you do know it's me!
You must!
You can't forget your little Moomin!
Please, Mama! Please, Mama!
Hush now, hush now!
Mama!
Shh!
Yes, you're my little Moomin alright!
Oh, Mama!
Oh!
Oh, Moomin!
Papa!
Oh, Moomin, my boy!
Where were you hiding?
In there!
In the hat?
Let's hope it's the last we'll see of it.
Moomin Papa decided that although it was a fine hat,
it was too dangerous to keep.
So Moomin threw it in the river and it floated away.
He wasn't too sure about it though,
because it was a rather special hat.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living,
the Moomin's.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the Moomin's.
They're always happy and always at play.
The Moomin's are having fun day after day,
the Moomin's.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living,
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the Moomin's.
They're always happy and always at play.
The Moomin's are having fun day after day,
the Moomin's.
The Moomin's.