here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the moments they are the moments so come
with me give me your hand I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just
like a bird sing that song ever there were the moments there were the
moments there were the moments there was the moments
Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba,
All is peaceful in moving valley.
Mama waters the flowers
while Papa relaxes in the shade on the porch.
Look, Mama, Moomin Papa is sleeping again.
Hmm.
You had a long nap yesterday.
I think it must be the weather.
It's too hot and sunny for me.
I wonder if he's worried about anything.
Hmm.
You don't sleep if you're worried you do something about it.
But Moomin Papa does have something on his mind,
although it doesn't keep him awake.
He's having a nice dream as well.
Oh, a lighthouse.
Oh, that's it.
Oh, that's it, a lighthouse.
What about a lighthouse, Papa?
We're going to visit one.
When?
Right now.
Well, as soon as I find one anyway.
That should stop you being bored, Mama.
Oh, I'm not really dear, but it would be nice.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm really excited.
Just think I'm letting lovely water.
Yeah, I'll write an exciting, epic novel of the sea.
I'm sure it will be a great success.
If he puts some action in it, misses out the romantic stuff.
Stop it!
Tell me.
Does Moomin Papa want all of you to go away to this lighthouse?
Oh, yes.
It'll be great fun.
Just think of all the ships we'll be able to see.
Yes, that will be good.
Papa says he wants to write an exciting story about the sea,
with ships and storms and stuff.
Probably pirates too.
Oh, he's stuck writing his memoirs again, is he?
Well, I guess that might have something to do with it,
but I think he just wants another adventure.
Well, it sounds a bit odd to me, Moomin.
No, it's not.
We're going to live in a real lighthouse and save ships
from the rocks and being wrecked in terrible storms.
Oh, I see.
What do you think the lighthouse keeper might say about you moving in?
Oh, he won't mind at all.
It'll be company for it, and I'm sure he'd like someone to talk to,
looking after lighthouses a very lonely job.
Ah, but if you thought Moomin, that might be exactly why he chooses to do it.
You mean that he might want to be on his own all the time?
Well, some people like it like that.
Sometimes I like being on my own.
Not for long, though.
It'll be a lot of fun.
Snuffkin, why don't you come with us?
What to a lonely lighthouse?
Yes.
Oh, no, which one is it?
There, that's the one.
Where?
So small, you can hardly see it.
How long would it take us to get their Moomin, Papa?
A day or two, I should say.
It depending on the window.
But it looks so tiny.
Oh, I don't know.
Well, I think so.
How we know which one is which.
Oh, don't you worry about that.
I've got an old compass somewhere, and we've got the map,
then at night we'll be able to see the light itself.
Anyway, an old sailor.
An old sailor?
Well, I'm not really that young.
And you're no sailor.
Is this mutiny?
Don't be stupid.
How long do you think you'll want to stay, Papa?
About a month.
Oh, we all need to take lots and lots of food, then.
Well, bless me.
I think that'll be enough, Mama.
Surely there'll be somebody living there already.
Don't be stupid.
Of course there is.
A lighthouse must have a keeper.
Yes, a man dedicated to the sea,
suffering loneliness and hardship,
countless lives with no regard for his own.
Huh?
Is that you, Sniff?
Yes, hi, Mr. Hamilton.
I thought you'd be busy packing for the trip to the lighthouse.
No, well, I'm not going with them this time.
I've decided to stay here.
Oh, dear me, really?
Sniffkin said he was going.
Well, I have something very important to do.
Important?
Sniff is just a big whip, that's all.
Oh, shut up, little mind.
Ah, don't tell me to shut up.
I don't listen to whims.
Hmm, now, now children, no squabbling.
It wouldn't be fair to the others.
I'm not a very good swimmer.
You mean if you fell and then we're drowning,
we'd have to jump in and save you.
Don't fall in, then.
Anyway, you can hang on to an or something.
What if it got swept away?
We'll put a life jacket on you stupid.
Don't worry.
What about the sharks?
They might take a fancy to me.
Wait a minute.
I've not as aologist, but I don't think there are any sharks around here.
I'm sure I would have heard if there were.
Well, it's a real fine day for sailing.
We're a mama and the others.
Don't worry, Mum. There's no hurry.
Are you sure that isn't too heavy for you, Sniff?
No, not at all, mama.
It's a shame that you're not coming with us,
but if you've got something important to do, you must do it.
It won't be the same without you, though.
We'll miss you, Sniff.
Thank you.
Oh, dear, I left a jar of strawberry jam
and a whole batch of pancakes on the kitchen table.
Do you think you could manage to eat them?
Leave it to me.
Hi, y'all be lucky if there's any food left in the lard or mama.
He's a my.
Off we go, then.
Ike is away.
You won't have to road too hard.
The wind will pick us up soon.
Goodbye, I have a good time, everyone.
Goodbye, Sniff.
Now, don't forget to shut all the windows if it rains.
Will you?
No.
I'm on it.
Hey! Wait for me.
I want to have a good time too.
It's my way.
Huh?
Look, Sniff is still waving.
He's a sweet boy.
Let's keep waving, Moon.
Tell her we're out of sight.
Bye, Sniff.
Bye, bye.
Bye.
No, I'm not waving good bye.
I want to go too.
Don't eat on the road, Mary Tabo.
We're gone.
It's no good shouting, little my.
He can't hear you.
He's giving us a great send-off, though.
For Sniff, he should have come with us.
Nancy, I'm going off and leaving me here on my own.
Sniff.
Sniff can, if you wouldn't mind,
I think we need some music to send us on our way.
What do you say?
Sniff.
Are you sure we're on the right course with the island, Papa?
Yes, the winds with us and the sails are fine.
I bet if we keep this speed up, we'll be there by tomorrow.
Well, if the wind stays like this, you could be right.
The wind's not dying down at all.
I'm surprised. I never thought we'd keep up this speed.
Now, make sure you're allergic to them.
Of course we will be, Papa.
If we carry on like this, perhaps we'll see the light from the lighthouse
while it's still dark.
Well, we don't want to hit anything at this speed.
Don't worry. We're watching.
We're watching.
Ah, this is the life.
Papa, the wind's dropped.
Well, that's strange.
It shouldn't happen that quickly.
Do you want us to start rowing, Moomin, Papa?
No, Snuffkin. I think we'd all better get some sleep.
Stupid wind. I really wanted to see the lighthouse at night.
It's getting foggy too.
I can't even see the stars anymore.
Right, Snuffkin. Wake me in two hours, and I'll take over.
Okay, Moomin, Papa.
What's the matter, Little My?
I thought I heard something.
Oh.
It's coming from over there somewhere.
Can you see anything?
No, but I can hear it.
It's so good I, and it's getting closer.
Little.
Moomin, Papa. Get up, Moomin.
Stop it, Little My. What's the matter with you?
You too, Moomin, quickly, before it's too late.
What's the matter, Little My?
I can hear her ship. I can't see it, but it's very close, and getting closer.
A ship? Where?
Over there, and she's bearing down on us.
Quickly, we don't have much time.
Yes, by the boobalier right.
We must let them know we're here, a signal.
Right? All hands on deck.
Maybe if we all shout as loud as we can.
Look.
Too late for shouting.
It's huge.
Look out, it's gonna hit us.
I think Moomin's right. What can we do?
It's too late for anything. Just brace ourselves and be ready to swim for it.
Huh?
Quick, get down, Little My.
I don't believe it.
Little My.
Huh?
That's hard. The ship didn't hit us.
Oh, yes, he did.
What?
It went straight into our rudder when nothing happened.
It went right through us.
Right through us. That's impossible she couldn't have.
I wonder if there was anyone on board that ship.
I can't see any lights.
I know, Snuffkin. I think it's a ghost ship.
A ghost ship?
Well, there's no wash and no damage to us.
It's the only explanation. I think she's right.
A ghost ship. We've actually seen one.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear. I need to sit down. All this excitement's too much.
Papa, don't they say that if you see a ghost ship, something terrible is gonna happen to you?
What happened in the first place to make it become a ghost ship? That's what I wanna know.
Well, that's just some old sailor's tail, Moomin. If it had been a real ship, we'd probably be sinking now.
Don't you think so, Snuffkin?
Yeah, I suppose that's one way of looking at it.
Come on, cheer up you guys. At least it was fun.
What's the matter? Has something happened? What are you laughing at?
It's so funny. Are you going to tell us?
Why didn't you wake me up, Moomin?
Well, I think it would be very rude.
Oh, what a beautiful sky. Just look at it.
Oh, the fog is lifting.
Oh, I said, don't stop.
Another beautiful day, not a ghost ship in sight.
The lighthouse.
Hey, wake up everybody. The lighthouse. I can see the lighthouse. We're there.
Oh, the sun shining. We must have slept for hours.
Oh, there it is.
This is ridiculous. We've been next to it all night. We could have gone and slept there.
I can't wait to go ashore.
All right, everyone. Jump to it. Manly old.
There's something strange going on here.
What is it, Snuffkin?
I'm not sure. Moomin Papa. Our boat didn't move at all last night. Did it?
No, it doesn't seem to have moved at all.
So why couldn't we see the light from the lighthouse, even when the fog cleared?
I can't work it out.
Yes, you're right, Snuffkin. It seems very odd. We should have seen it.
Well, perhaps the lighthouse keeper forgot to put it on, Moomin Papa.
I don't think so, little Mai. You can't forget a thing like that.
I suppose it could be broken.
There could be lots of reasons for it. Why don't we hurry up and get ashore, and then we can ask the keeper.
Look, there's someone in a boat.
Hmm.
It looks like he's fishing.
He knows about the lighthouse. He probably lives on the island.
Let's get closer. Easy now.
Hi there, good morning.
Any luck?
Not yet, but it's still early.
Hmm, yes, quite. I'll ask him straight out.
Do you know if the lighthouse was working last night?
I don't know. Sorry, I didn't catch that.
He said, no, it wasn't.
What did I tell you? He forgot to light it.
Oh, it wasn't only last night. You'll never see a light in that lighthouse, not even on stormy nights.
Never. So what does the keeper do then?
Nothing. There isn't a lighthouse keeper.
Why?
I'm sorry. I'm afraid I don't know. All I can say is I haven't seen one.
Do you live on the island?
Hey, mister. You're asking too many questions. Who are you?
I'm Moment Papa from Moment Valley, and this is my family.
We've come a long way in order to do some important work here.
No work on this island. No, you better go back home.
You see, I've come here to research an epic novel about the sea.
Just turn around and go back. You're too far from home.
Oh, please, wait!
Shh, dear. Don't shout. We mustn't scare the fish away.
Let's go ashore and have some breakfast. I expect we're all hungry.
Bonnie, pair. The old ones lost his marbles.
Look, Moment Papa. There's a path there leading to the lighthouse.
We'll leave this stuff here and we'll go and explore it first.
Right. To the lighthouse, everyone. Up.
Oh!
Come on!
What's wrong? Why do you always get so upset when somebody mentions the lighthouse?
It's not your call, sir. Business boy doesn't concern you at all.
You were like that when I asked you about it before. Maybe if you were to tell me,
I might be able to understand. I could try anyway.
Either talk about something else or keep quiet. Do you understand that?
It's so very rocky. I don't think it would work. What?
A garden.
Hello there. Is there anybody at home?
There's nobody here. That boy was right. It's been empty for ages, I think.
Oh, the door was left unlocked. I know we do it, but most people don't.
Something terrible's happened. Something terrible. Please, little my. You know I hate things like that.
Don't worry, snorke may done. Little my is just trying to scare you.
I don't like hearing about anything horrible.
Flag your ears and snorke made, because I haven't finished yet, and the next bit's really horrible.
Oh, well, where have you been finished there?
Well, the lighthouse keeper is still up there. He got scurvy and had to be able to move for months.
And nobody's heard his cries for help, and with no food, he's almost a skeleton.
If he isn't dead already, he'll be at the top of the stairs, crawling towards his fingers,
lading and ripped up ribbons and flowers, mouth, garbage, that was tearless mouth.
Shut up, little my.
Reminds right, that's enough.
It's a good imagination, though.
I'll let you use it in your book, if you like.
Oh, come on. Tell me what did she say, Moonman?
Oh, nothing, really. Nothing at all.
Tell me, Moonman, but leave out the bits I wouldn't like.
Where are you going, Papa?
Well, listen, everyone.
First, I'm going to get the lamp working.
Then we'll give the place a good clean, and then we'll move in.
We'll be the new lighthouse keepers, and once again, the seas around this island
will be safe for ships to navigate in troubled water.
Good old Papa!
Great!
Careful, everyone.
Take anything, that's dangerous.
Oh!
Will Moonman Papa be able to get the light working again?
Where is the lighthouse keeper?
And what could have made him go without locking the door,
leaving the ships in peril and the seas with no one to guide them away from the rocks?
And who is the mysterious fisherman?
They love the laughter and they love the living, the Moonman's
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moonman's
They're always happy and always at play
The Moonman's are having fun day after day, the Moonman's
They love the laughter and they love the living, the Moonman's
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moonman's
They're always happy and always at play
The Moonman's are having fun day after day, the Moonman's
The Moonman's