here they are for one and all the moments are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the moments they are the moments so come
with me give me your hand I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just
like a bird sing that song ever there were the moments there were the moments
there were the moments there were the moments there were the moments
there you are
oops
we weren't looking where we were going that's all right thank you think of me are you going out
yes for a walk we'll have fun
it seems that thingamy and bob are well and truly part of movement house now
luckily they don't eat a lot and are small enough to find the pencils that fall
between the floorboards in the porch
hey this looks like a great hiding place nobody would ever find it here
come on bob let's go get the suitcase man are you sure it's not safe for an
arm what would you say someone went in when we went there you wouldn't like it would
you I think the movements are much too nice to do anything like that it's not
them it's the guess I'm thinking about you know the movements let anybody stay
snorke maiden you lied to me little my homie
moment still has the shell that I gave him but you said that he didn't impossible
movement mama gave it to the grove I was there when she did it look I saw it he showed it to me
are you really sure was it the same one of course it was I'm not stupid you know
that's very odd I saw her do it with my own eyes well I'll go and ask moving right now
little my it's a bit awkward but if I'm going to be honest snorke maiden what well
I've decided that from now on I'm only going to tell the truth oh yes and I found
something you might be interested in what is it mumble and I were down on the beach
yesterday and you remember all those things we found washed up by the storm do you
mean on the hatty fatter's island that we sailed to yes and do you remember the
figurehead that movement like best of all you know the lady made of wood and
painted she was really lovely wasn't she yes I remember movement wanted to keep it
so what about it well it's here on the beach it was still the same as beautiful
as ever we said the same one yes I remember her pretty face don't legs though
she's just a silly wooden doll oh I know that but she's got those gorgeous eyes and
lovely long hair little my why all this fuss about this silly figurehead
trust him only someone as stupid as movement could fall in love with a figurehead
it's probably still dreaming about her every night do you think it's still there
Jars snorke maiden if no one else has found her already do you think the ocean
might come and wash her away again why all these silly questions snorke maiden
woman would go and rescue her if he knew so that would be terrible I couldn't
bear it at all I really couldn't how pathetic he'll probably take her home
and keep her in his room forever my expect she's too big to go through the door
he'll just sit and stare at her with that lovesick look on his face I know he will
oh where are you going now I thought you were going to move in house I was but
there's something more important I have to do
okay it's clear
hey you two you're not leaving are you no we're just uh we're going
why have you got the suitcase them look woman would you help us with something
of course thank you very much woman oh that's okay it's a bit too big for you to
carry we can take it from here it's all right it's not very heavy
oh silly me it wouldn't be a very secret place if I'd seen it would it I'll see you
later don't be too long now of course I won't
hey what are you doing up there little my I'm coming down what does it look like
you're much too small to do that the rungs are too far apart for you to reach
just you watch me
movement I have a problem do you mind if I ask you something go ahead did
movement mama give snorke means heart shape shell to the grove yes she did so
you and the grove can't both have it can you that's just where you're wrong but
that's simply impossible you can't have the grove simply got another one that's not true
all right but it would only upset snorke made an if she knew so I'm not going to
tell her you rotten thing why don't you just tell me the truth because it's a
secret but I want to know movement look movement now why don't you tell me your
secret and then I'll tell you mine what is it really very top secret go on then tell me
tell me yours first no you tell me first I know let's say them together all right
ready one two three after we go and I went to the beach yesterday I'm out there we'll
make you like it what did you say the figure head by the
K wait a minute you didn't finish telling me your secret I'll tell you later that's
not there you've got to tell me now
what do you think moments to let I don't know maybe he's looking for shells again
I don't think so he looks a bit worried to me maybe he's lost something important
how much further do we have to go as far as you can road where a long way out
already I know I want to make sure that the lady will never turn up again we must go
further out we must be far enough by now I'm tired no the currents could still drag her
in from here keep going
he looks very unhappy we've got to cheer him up but how is only one way Bob yet you're
right thing to me
hello look so sad moment that we thought we try make you happy again
you don't mind do you know but you don't have to I'm all right really
how about this then moment we're going to show you what's in our suitcase
would you like that moment it's very interesting oh my gosh will you
do you need some help in there no I think we can manage
now we'll open it yes now one two three oh gosh by my tail
do you like it oh boy do I like it then you're not sad anymore then oh no
that's good isn't it it was such a beautiful ruby how it changed color from soft red
to sapphire blue and then to pink one minute it was like a flame leaping out of the
center then suddenly it was like a blood tulip it was perhaps that's the king's
ruby it was just beautiful that's the one the hob goblin the searching for oh
no however far away is he'll come back on his black panther looking for it and he's
sure to find it because he'll know that thing of me and Bob have it first the
groke and allow the hob goblin what are we going to do no more than a week
later and like a bolt from the blue a real catastrophe hit mumen valley no it's not
in the bedroom either that's very odd where did you see it last I'm sure it was
here somewhere pop up well perhaps it's in the garden no I haven't been out
here all day mumen mama's handbag is missing full of useful things like socks and
sweets and string what's the matter mama I can't find my handbag and I'm lost
without it we've looked everywhere will I get a reward if I find it mumen mama yes
we'll have a big party for everyone with cakes jelly and everything and it's a
special treat no one has to wash or go to bed early I'll find it mama no I will
mumen mama I've checked the seller it's not there oh dear where can it be I haven't
been in the seller for days so I didn't think it would be there but thank you dear
snorke
word got round mumen valley of the missing handbag and soon everyone was helping
to look for it
what a lot of people I would do what they're looking for
what's everybody looking for my handbag thing of me the one with the two
nice little pockets yes that's the one it's been missing for days will you
to help us look
it makes such a lovely place to sleep and don't you think
mumen mama looks very sad perhaps we better give it back
oh you found it look everybody think of me and Bob have found it
oh thank you where on earth did you find it in the bush under the white
birch tree let's have a party tonight to celebrate the return of mama's
handbag as you all know this party is in honor of thing of me and Bob finding
mumen mama's handbag and to thank everyone who took part in the big search
let's raise our glasses to our heroes is to think of me and Bob who found
mumen mama's handbag without which mumen valley would never be the same again
cheers
now I think moment would like to say a few words
we're very pleased mumen's handbag is back again and thank you to our northern friends
think of me and Bob you're seeing as how this is a very special occasion
and also as a thank you for the party they have decided to show us what is in
their suitcase and I'm sure you'll all be astounded by what you see
come closer everyone now think of me and Bob are you ready
everyone ready everyone what do you think how wonderful I don't know how the
growth could swap that for an old seashell my my that must be the king's
ruby the king's ruby I found it
yes this is it the ruby I've sworn to find
don't touch it it's ours go away you nasty hub goblin but that king's ruby
belongs only to me no it doesn't the growth gave it to sing a me and Bob in fair
exchange for a heart shaped show mr. hub goblin did he say a heart shaped
shell I think so anyway I saw her give it to them with my own eyes show
it belongs to them not you I've spent 300 years day and night searching
everywhere for this ruby well that's very sad but it still is now then let's
see would you exchange the ruby for say two diamond mines no I can't do it I
can't take it by force it's been so long what can I do
would you like some punch it's very nice that's very kind of you woman mama I
haven't had any for 85 years
ah quince that's part of it mr. hub goblin have some more please no thank you hub
goblins don't really drink very much well this is a splendid punch and a splendid
party in return I shall show you a little magic I will give out three presents now
what I can do is grant three wishes so I want three of you to come forward and make
a wish you're not afraid are you how you look old enough not to be frightened
mr. amulet just let me think oh yes mr. hub goblin I broke the spade I borrowed
from woman papa no mr. amulet never make a proper wish I would like a new
spade if you please very well here you are oh thank you thank you very much
mr. hub goblin here you are a moment papa right who's next excuse me yes and what
can I do for you young lady well I'm afraid it might be a little difficult for me
is that really what you want please alright then close your eyes your wish has
now come true young lady oh snorke me snorke me done I wanted eyes like that
wouldn't later you think it's so beautiful do you think I'm beautiful now
moment well I will give me a mirror someone they're quite nice really
horrible horrible please mr. hub goblin please give me my eyes back I'm sorry but I can only
grant one wish per person oh that's really me no please mr. hub goblin can I make a wish now
certainly a golden chariot a rock crystal goblet anything at all a sack full of gold coins
you can be rich movement really rich I'm sorry but movements is the last wish I know why don't you
ask for two sacks of gold movement then we can have one each what do you think no sniff I know
what I'm going to wish oh man mr. hub goblin please change snorke made in size back to
her own never mind her she can see alright get the gold coins the wishes made and fulfilled
there you are have a look now next time think before you make a wish moment mr. hub goblin yes
really if you regret wishes like that why don't you make a wish for yourself I'm afraid my magic
only works for other people mr. hub goblin can we make a wish for you then please say we can't please I suppose so
please it's important very well as it is not for you we wish for a movie just like yours you shall have it
this is for you hub goblin oh thank you thank you
and so that was how after three hundred years the hub goblin search came to an end and
movement valley had never had such a celebration everyone was happy except possibly sniff
who would have quite like a sack full of gold coins
always happy and always a play the moments are having fun day after day the movies
the movies they love the laughter and they love the living the movements
the living and sharing and caring and giving the movements they're always happy and goes
it played the moments are having fun day after day the movies the movies the movies the movies
the movies the movies the movies the movies the movies the movies the movies