Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me, they're here for you on your TV, they are the movements,
they are the movements, so come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement
land, you can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there
were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements,
that's the invisible child, I wonder what she really looks like,
oh well good morning everybody, morning lazy bones, we've been up for hours and hours,
we're going to play hide and seek in the woods, great, nanny are you all right, yes thanks,
this is dumb if I could see your face I wouldn't have to ask, doesn't help with you sniff you
all with ask silly questions it's a bit big for hide and seek isn't it but that's
so good about it okay this is a good place to start but we've got a new rule for the game once
you found somewhere to hide you've got to stay in the same place no moving about anyone do you
understand nanny right you're to go first sniff why isn't always me first we'll have a practice
for nanny's sake show her what to do I didn't seek as an easy game not for nanny it isn't she's
never played it before what never ever no and not just hide and seek she hasn't played any games at all
not even when she was visible no nothing oh that's terrible so will you go first no I won't
oh okay I'll go first then I'll count to 10 slowly so you'll have plenty of time to find
somewhere one two three go on nanny hurry up for five I can still see you six
seven
hello nanny don't be frightened why don't you hide in that bush over there he'll never find you
I'm coming thank you
oh my damn god you sniff
c'mon
yes
MMM?
HMM?
FHHHHH?!
MMM?
HMM?
Got you, Little Mike!
No! I'd like to know where Ninny's hiding!
Oh, look!
Oh!
That! Come out, Nanny. I've got you. That was a good place. But I saw your ribbon.
Oh! Now for snorkemaiden. She's always easy to find.
Ha! That's only because she wants to be found!
Found you snorkemaiden!
Waaaaaannnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn,
Two, three, don't wait, nanny, this is my boy.
Four.
Hey, nanny, I'll show you a good place.
Just come with your uncle stinky.
Now don't worry, no one will find you there, it opens up once you're inside.
Come on, it's a bit steep, I'll help you.
Oh, stop!
Right, that should keep you quiet.
You're a bit too visible at the moment.
Oh, let me out.
But I'm sure if you stay here until tomorrow, no one will see it all.
Please don't leave me here, please.
No, it's...
That's it, now tomorrow we'll hit the bank.
Let me out.
Please let me out.
I'm very glad I thought of bringing nanny here.
It's nice to have her here too, Tiki.
She's no trouble at all.
You're all pretty eccentric, and it might be just what she needs to make her want to be seen again.
Oh, and you're very kind, of course.
Well, thank you, I think I suppose we should be flattered, shouldn't we?
Oh, yes, definitely.
She started to talk, but her voice is very weak.
You have to listen very carefully.
Has it always been like that, or just since she was invisible?
I'm not sure, I don't think it was like that before.
Lots of people manage very well without using their heads, so I'm certain nanny will be all right.
Yes, and I'm glad she's got movement in the others to play with.
She's never had anybody before, you know.
I think she'd find it a bit difficult to Tiki.
Well, Mum and Mama, I think that all she needs is something to shock her out of it.
Huh, got you a little, my.
Oh, that bush was too prickly anyway.
I expect I'm the last one, hey.
No, I haven't found nanny yet.
Nanny?
I didn't think nanny would hide so well.
Any luck, Sniff?
There's nowhere else to look, Mum and.
Perhaps she's lost or fallen or hurt herself.
I've looked absolutely everywhere.
I bet she's invisible again.
That's why I can't find her.
I bet Sniff hasn't looked everywhere.
She can't be far.
Do you know where she is, Mum?
No, I haven't seen her at all.
Not since we started.
Nanny!
Come on, we're going home.
We've finished playing.
Nanny!
Oh, my goodness, where could she be?
It's your turn, Sniff, so you've got to find her.
Nanny!
Not once the game's over, I haven't.
Never mind.
We'll all look.
We must find her.
We are supposed to be looking after her, you know?
Oh, come on, Nanny!
The game's over, we've finished!
Nanny!
Hurry up!
We're going home for cookies and lemonade!
Nanny!
Can you hear us?
We weren't supposed to come this far, Snort Maiden.
She might be really lost or frightened or anything.
Nanny!
Where are you, Nanny?
Can you hear me?
Nanny!
Help!
I'm over here!
Did you hear something?
I'm not sure.
Help!
I'm here!
That's her!
She's not far away!
Nanny!
Where are you?
Here!
Behind this rock!
Where's her voice coming from?
That way, I think.
Nanny!
I can't hear what you're saying!
Try and shout a bit louder!
I'm over here!
Over here!
Behind the rock!
I still can't hear her properly!
Louder, Nanny!
Louder!
Behind the rock!
Which rock?
Over here!
The big rock!
Over there!
I've never shouted so much in my life!
Nanny!
Nanny, are you behind this rock, Nanny?
Yes!
Stinky block the cave with it!
Don't worry, we'll get you out!
Hang on!
Are you alright, Nanny?
Thank you, Mum!
Oh, thank you!
Your voice seems to be...
Oh, what?
Oh, nothing!
Try and hold on to me, and I'll call you out!
Oh, thank you!
Hey!
What's happened?
Where's your finder?
In the cave!
Wow!
What a brilliant hiding place had you find it!
What's wrong?
Did I say something funny?
Now, that was very mean of Stinky's.
A clever idea, though, of interuser for a van robbery.
Oh, Papa!
Oh, I know Stinky shouldn't have done it,
and it must have been a nasty shopping trapped in the dark in that cave,
but no real harm came to her, and she didn't disappear,
and her voice got much stronger.
You're so loud!
Oh, goodness! Did you, dear?
Yes, Mum and Mama!
Mum told me to yell loudly, so he'd know where I was!
And it was loud, too!
Good for you, Nanny.
It's surprising the things you can do if you have to,
and you ought to remember that people who speak loudly are usually very noticeable.
Go on, yo! I want to see it!
That's a good idea, Nanny.
If shouting brought back your voice,
you never know it might be just what's needed to make the rest of you.
Try and get angry, as well.
Yeah, that's easy. Just think about Stinky.
Yeah, and how horrible he is!
That should make you angry. Very angry!
Just your white Stinky!
I can't help faster than me!
Stinky, wait! We want to talk to you!
I don't want to talk to you!
Help! Help!
Are you all right, Sniff?
You can't get away, Stinky.
The forest is my home ground! You won't catch me in here!
Hold it.
You can't do this to me!
We're only doing what you did to Nanny.
Now look, I needed her to help me. I did, I tell ya.
But she didn't want to, huh?
That's why I put her down this hole to change her mind.
And scare her so much that she'd become totally invisible again.
She had to be invisible for my plan. Now get me out of here!
It's all right, Stinky. See you tomorrow!
No! No!
You crushed few things!
I had such a wonderful plan!
Ah, you're spiteful!
Let's hear them my next job!
But despite all that had happened, Nanny's face was still not to be seen.
Then, about ten days later.
This weather seems to push the nails out.
I haven't seen anyone stare at the sea like Nanny does.
Well, maybe she's never seen it before.
Oh, she's crying now!
What's the matter?
It's the sea! It's far too big!
You don't have to go on it, you know.
Mama! Mama! What's up?
What's the matter with her?
Nothing to worry about. She's never seen the sea before and she's just surprised at how big it is.
Well, there's an awful lot of water, that's for sure.
Nanny's lucky. I wish there was something to surprise or excite me.
Nothing's happened for weeks. Anything would be nice.
Mama must be bored.
I think you're right.
But she never gets bored.
Well, she is now. She needs something to happen.
I think we should do something to surprise her.
Like what?
Well, I know what we can do.
Well, tell me!
We'll creep up behind her and just give her a little push.
What, Papa? Push her into the sea?
Oh, Papa, you can't. Mama wouldn't like it.
Just watch me.
But the water's freezing. A mama will get all wet.
We never found the water too cold when we were your age.
You young people today have no sense of fun.
Did you really used to do things like that?
All the time.
Papa?
Yes, Mumann.
Oh, nothing.
Don't worry, Mumann.
It's always a prank. She'll find it very funny. I promise.
Oh.
I know you don't!
No!
Don't you dare push her into that big horrible sea.
Let me explain to you.
There's nothing to explain.
You're a big bully. She'd have gone all wet.
What a nasty trick.
You could never...
Nihini.
There's her face! Hurry!
That must be the sea.
What on earth happened? Were you up to something?
Oh, nothing much. You know that child has got the sharpest teeth with her without her head.
Oh, Mumann. Mumann, at last I'm visible again.
For always you won't disappear again.
Never, never.
Brave girl.
And with a good strong set of healthy teeth too.
Oh, I'm so happy, Nihini.
Mimi dear.
Mumann mother.
I'm very glad too.
Oh.
Oh, you.
Stop laughing, you horrible child. You used Sartuth monster.
What's so funny, huh?
Oh.
Really, Nihini laughed.
Well, she certainly changed, Mumann, Mama.
All she needed was to get angry and she did.
I hope Mumann Papa's forgiven, Nihini.
Thank you all for taking such good care of her.
I hate to say it, but she sounds almost as bad as it'll mine out.
Tiki! Nihini!
And so Nihini left Mumann house with Tiki.
Now that she was completely visible and far from Timid,
she was ready for anything.
That is except seeing her aunt, she said.
Boom!
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.