Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you on your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there was the movements, there was the movements, there was the movements, there was the movements,
When the Hennian first told Mumen about the golden fish, Mumen thought to himself that
But it must look something like this.
My grandpa told me that his mother had actually seen it.
So you never saw it yourself, Mr. Hemion?
No, I'm a batonist.
It comes to the surface only under very special conditions.
It's very rarely seen.
Conditions?
Yes.
First of all, it must be right between summer and autumn.
But that's now.
Yes.
It has to be in the afternoon sunshine after heavy rain.
Yes, that does narrow it down.
And there must be no wind.
Grandpa said not even a ripple on the water.
Oh dear.
And there are some other conditions that he really didn't know about anyway to see it.
You must be extremely lucky.
Hmm.
Just getting to the lake itself isn't too easy.
It's way beyond lonely mountains.
Going over lonely mountains and back would take at least two days.
Not really, because I know a shortcut movement.
I could take you there and back in one day.
Oh, could you do that?
Yes.
Have you already been there, Snuffkin?
Just once.
Oh, will you show me the way?
You really want to go?
Yes.
I must see that golden fish with my own eyes and maybe capture it.
It won't be easy to capture.
Why not?
From what I've heard, the golden fish is far too clever to get caught.
I know, but it would be so much fun.
You going alone?
Well, Snorkmaiden said she wanted to come along.
She gets these ideas, you know.
Just Snorkmaiden?
Uh, maybe a little my.
What about Sniff?
I think he wants to come along, too.
What about you?
In that case, we'd better go across the mountains.
Why is that? Why can't we take the shortcut?
The path is rather steep and dangerous, you know, Moomin.
Especially in the forest of witches.
Hide the witches?
Not now, maybe.
Oh, so it's safe then.
But it's a very deep forest dark and scary even in daytime.
That's okay, we'll take the shortcut.
Hmm.
Oh, dear.
Come on.
Good morning, Snuffkin.
Oh.
Sorry, Snuffkin, guess I overslept.
Snorkmaiden a little my, aren't here yet.
You're very early.
Hmm, I dreamt I caught the golden fish,
and then, of course, I couldn't go back to sleep.
Well, let's go.
Shouldn't we wait for Snorkmaiden a little my?
Oh, they're not really great walkers, are they?
And anyway, didn't we decide that we wouldn't wait for anybody?
So it might be better this way.
What's better this way, Moomin?
Oh, little my.
Why don't you stay here?
This will be a very tough expedition.
I'm tougher than you.
Wait for me.
Hey, walk any faster, Snuffkin.
I'm still so sleepy.
Why did we have to leave so early, Moomin?
To get there back in a day, Snorkmaiden.
But we aren't taking the shortcut, are we?
Yes, but it still might get dark before we're back.
I won't be able to walk back this fast, you know,
because my bucket will be full of water for the golden fish.
Well, don't be disappointed if you don't catch it.
But that's my whole reason for going.
But you heard what the Himmelin said, Snuff?
We'll be extremely lucky to even catch sight of the golden fish.
I heard him and now's exactly the right time.
Maybe the others made too much noise.
We'll just have to wait and see.
Don't you worry, I'll catch him all right.
Where are they going sorely in the morning?
How far is the forest of witches?
I'd say about two hours.
And can you also tell us how long from one end of the forest to the other, Snuffkin?
About the same.
Are there really such things as witches?
No.
Baby, because I'm not a bit scared of them.
Aren't you?
Not the least little bit.
There used to be some, though.
What witches?
Well, of course, sniff.
What helps do you think that they call it the forest of witches, huh?
And you're absolutely sure that there are no witches now.
I haven't heard of any coming back.
Mm-hmm.
So you're not absolutely sure that there are no witches?
Where's Moominer still in bed?
He was off before you woke up, Papa.
Mm.
Oh, the golden fish.
Good morning, dear.
I wanted to go with him.
Are you writing your memoirs you're far too busy?
Mm-hmm.
That's very true with the thought of a fish that no one has seen.
That might have been a whole chapter.
Do you think they'll catch it?
No, I doubt it very much. It's highly unlikely.
In that case, you should have gone with them.
No, I do know a thing or two about fishing.
Snuffkin does, too, but he's still so young.
Oh, don't worry. I'm sure Snuffkin will manage.
Oh, this is a spooky forest.
Maybe the witch is every time.
Stop it, little lion.
Listen, everybody. Don't stray away from me.
Promise you might get lost.
Oh!
It's so dark in here.
Sure is, and so thick the sun can't get through.
That's because of those clouds.
I can hear the wind, but we need calm.
Yes, but we also need heavy rain.
You're right. That's what the Hemiellin said.
It sure looks like rain.
Not only looks like...
Oh, it's raining.
Here.
Thank you.
I gotta say, this rainstorm was very sudden.
Don't worry. It won't last that long.
How do you know that?
Vagabons do.
This rain isn't that heavy.
No, it's not bad, but we better hurryer.
We won't get to lake till noon, and that'll be too late.
I don't think we'll get very wet down here, Mum.
And so why don't we move on?
You're so excited.
What should we do with Snuffkin?
Well, we could move on, couldn't we?
We really aren't getting too wet.
We better find some shelter quickly.
But where can we shelter?
There's nothing in this wood-exec tree.
I'm gonna eat tree then, I guess.
Yeah!
What is it, Snuffkin?
There's a house over there.
It's fallen to rock and ruin.
Well, at least it'll keep the rain off.
Hello there, anyone home?
There's nobody here.
No one's lived here for a long time.
I wonder who could have been who lived here all alone.
I know who it was, and so do we all, don't we?
Surely you don't mean.
The winches, of course.
Look around for dried spices, magic herbs, broomsticks, and a black cat, an iron pot.
Appile.
But no broom.
No, the witch rode away on it.
There's someone here.
Who is it?
Let's get out of here.
Came from over there.
No, that's okay, Snuffkin.
We gotta get out of this place.
I can't move, Snuffkin.
Stinky?
Pretty good.
I bet you were really scared.
I wasn't a bit scared, Stinky.
It's very rude of snip to faint when he hears my voice.
Where are you off to anyway?
Oh, come on, tell me.
Can't seem to take a joke.
Come on, wait for me.
That way.
Okay.
Come on.
This is it, isn't it?
Yes it is.
Where's the golden fish?
I really don't know.
I've never seen it either.
With rain, sunshine, and calm, I'm sure the fish will come.
The golden fish?
Help me catch it.
I just gotta have that golden fish.
Oh.
It's deep down in here somewhere.
I can't see any fish anywhere.
Maybe it was Hemiellin's idea of a very funny joke.
The Hemiellin doesn't joke.
Let's sit down and wait.
I'm sure the golden fish will appear for us.
I don't believe it.
Do you mean to say you came all this way here just to see some stupid old fish?
I came to catch it.
Well, that's even more stupid.
Hey, stop making those ripples.
So they really got excited and walked all the way, you say?
Oh, to be young again.
Well, I would have gone with them if I hadn't over slept.
I didn't know that you were that young woman, Papa.
Oh, I'm not exactly old, you know.
Pretty interesting to see a fish that hardly anyone's ever seen.
Snip said that he would catch this golden fish if it's the last thing he did.
Oh, how?
Well, he had a net and a very large bucket to carry at home, then.
That's a good one.
What do you mean?
I guess I must have forgotten to tell you all the details.
There's so much you don't know about this fish.
Can't see it from up here.
Oh, the hemulin was certainly right.
Hardly anyone has seen this golden fish and we're not going to see it either.
Maybe somebody ate him years ago.
Stinky, be quiet, please.
Did you see it?
Where did you see it?
Huh?
I saw a fish jump, but I couldn't tell if it was golden.
It was much too far away.
With the sun over there, we'd just see the outlines, Nork Maiden.
Yes, we couldn't really see the color.
Look, everybody, look!
I can see a raft over there!
Hey, let's take it and go out to the middle of the lake.
But it's much too small for all of us.
Don't worry, Snip. This won't sink.
I'm staying.
You do what you like, but you'll never catch any fish if you're afraid of water.
Stinky, you can help me. It's gold, you know.
We can sell it for a lot of money and then we'll both be very wealthy.
I think it was somewhere around here, wasn't it?
We're less, I suppose, hard to say.
Well, I can't see anything.
I can't see!
There's certainly no sign of it now.
Well, we'll just have to sit and wait here.
We have no choice.
And I'm not going home until I've seen it. I'm happy to wait all day.
You won't find it by looking up at the sky.
You know what? Fish like it in places where there are lots of wings.
Oh, the rafts in the middle of the lake.
And they just want to see the fish, but you wait, I'm going to catch it.
Maybe somebody's already caught it and you can get it in a tin.
What did you see?
Over there, something shiny jumping!
What did you see? Ditorger, now keep quiet.
I hate fishing.
Guess we better think about getting back otherwise we'll never get home before nightfall.
I don't want to get lost on a raft in the dark on this lonely lake.
Perhaps we were expecting too much.
Maybe your right's not made in, but I really thought we'd see it.
This is the most disappointing day of my life.
We can come back.
Yes.
It's not gonna stop.
Did you see a moment?
It's gigantic.
Oh!
We've seen!
Oh, that was right!
I really saw it!
I saw it!
I did it, I caught it!
God, what?
Why the golden fish, of course?
What?
I've got the golden fish in here if you want to have a look at it.
See, it's in this bucket.
You don't really believe that is the golden fish.
It's just another stupid fish.
I can swear that it really was golden when I caught it.
It must have been the sun making it land in the water.
It was you said it was the golden fish.
Why don't you let it go?
You know it's not the right one and he hates it in that bucket.
There he goes.
It looks so happy now.
It really was golden when I first saw it.
We believe you, Sniff.
Now let's go home.
Sniff and Stinky never really got over their belief.
It was actually the golden fish they had caught.
But moving in the others were in no doubt about what they had seen.
They and the emulators were great friends.
They were great friends.