Here they are for one and all. The movements are about to come. Come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you on your TV they are the movements. They are the movements.
So come with me give me your hand. I'll take you up to a moment land. You can fly just like a bird. Sing the best song ever.
There were the movements. There were the movements. There were the movements.
There were the movements. There were the movements.
It was the end of summer but still every day seemed hotter than the last.
Movement Valley had had no rain for weeks and finally the river had dried up.
Papa says this weather is a catastrophe.
Oh not really.
But it is. He says movement Valley will turn into a desert if it carries on.
I don't think that will happen movement.
Papa can't ever remember it so hot even the river has dried up.
No that does worry me. I can't fish anymore.
In all my travels I found that droughts like this are always followed by a real heavy downpour.
Well it's too hot for me anyway.
Oh it's so hot I can't think.
I can I can always think of something.
Well well even the weeds are wilting.
The sea never dries up does it?
Of course not stupid wherever the fish go.
I'm going swimming.
Here you are.
Watch this.
Ah!
Ouch that hurt.
What's this stupid box doing here?
I think it's floated from foreign lands.
What's it got in it?
Perhaps it's full of priceless jewels.
No it wouldn't float so high in the water if it was.
A tiara packed in wood shavings.
I can use a new comb too.
What have you found you too?
I treasure it.
No we don't think so. It's not heavy enough.
But you never know snork maiden.
Let's open it and see.
Come on Slays push me a shore.
Perhaps it's gold nuggets in here.
Are diamonds or something to eat?
What is this?
Well seeds maybe.
What sort of seeds?
Well at first glance I'd say they might be tropical plants.
Really?
What plants are tropical?
Well species like banana or mango.
Banana and mango.
Well I haven't done a lot of research on tropical plants so I can't be sure but they do look like it.
I know mama. Why don't we plant them?
Good idea woman.
The thing is we don't have a tropical climate.
I'm afraid they wouldn't grow here at all.
Let's plant them shall we?
They won't bear any fruit so don't get too excited.
Oh well it seems tropical enough to me Mr. Hanuman.
At least we can try can't we?
I want to see what papaya looks like and ugly fruit.
I want mangoes growing all around my banjo window.
Let's plant them shall we?
I tell you they're strictly tropical they won't take root at all.
It certainly seems that mama is enjoying herself Mr. Hanuman.
I don't think it'll be much use.
Well perhaps not but it's still worth the fun in trying.
Imagine woman valley a tropical jungle.
Huh huh.
Oh Mr. Hanuman.
Do you think these seeds will grow into real fruit trees?
Let me see.
What have you got here little my?
I could very well be mistaken but I think this one is a mango seed.
Thanks.
And why do you want to know a little my?
Because I'm only growing fruit trees.
Hmm thanks.
And why do you want to know a little my?
Because I'm only growing fruit.
I want to be sure I'm not planning stupid orchids or passion flowers or something.
Mr. Hemuman.
Can you tell me which one of these is banana?
Yeah I'm not really too sure but I think it's this one.
You want to grow an orchid too snorke maiden?
I just want to plant a banana tree in a really special place.
It's Moon's favorite fruit.
I think she'll be disappointed bananas won't grow here.
This weather doesn't belong here either.
If it gets any hotter I'll melt.
I can't wait for dusk so it'll cool down a bit.
Hmm.
Isn't it wonderful to go to sleep looking at the stars?
And it's not so hot anymore.
I'll sleep like a log tonight.
You always do don't you little my?
Well sleep like an extra heavy log then.
Snorke maiden, why don't you sleep under that tree with moon men and little my?
Because I can't see the stars from there and it makes me feel romantic looking at them.
But you're going to get very wet if it starts raining in the night.
You're joking surely mama.
Not at all.
But it hasn't rained for ages and there aren't any clouds or anything.
Just stars.
All the toothpicks fell on the floor and that's a sure sign of rain.
Snorke maiden won't mind if she gets all wet.
Moon Mama, that should be happy.
Who, why is that?
Because then she'll know that the special tree will start growing and that's very important to her.
That's true.
Good night everyone.
I hope you sleep well.
Good night everybody.
Good night woman.
Good night, don't snorke.
It's too hot to sleep.
Why don't you sleep outside like the children?
I think I will.
A thunderstorm.
I told you the toothpicks are never wrong.
Hey it's raining movement.
Wake up movement.
Oh is it morning?
The sun's really bright.
No it's raining.
Rainy?
Look at that.
You look I'm getting wet I'm going inside.
So mama was right about the rain.
Hey snorke maiden.
Doesn't she look sweet?
Snorke maiden.
Is it raining?
That's very clever.
Your mother knows everything doesn't she?
She does.
Not yet.
I want to feel the rain on my face.
It's been so long.
You want to feel it much longer?
It's raining.
Mangoes.
That's impossible.
Gosh.
By my tail a jungle that's a tropical jungle.
Wake up, wake up you two.
There's a jungle outside.
We've planted a jungle.
A jungle.
You're right moment.
Those seeds have not only sprouted.
I know they're big trees.
I've never known trees to grow like that.
That's bad.
I know.
I've never known trees to grow like that.
That's...
It's...
I think I'll go and play Tarzan.
I wish my lettuce seeds would do that move in papa.
There's magic here somewhere mama.
Let's go and explore.
That's rain drumming on the campus.
It must be.
Snuffkin?
What a nurse all this.
Well, we found a crate of tropical seeds
and planted them last night.
And this morning while you can see it's like magic.
It's fantastic.
I know.
We can go on a safari.
I've seen nothing like it.
What kind of flower is this?
It looks like an orchid to me.
This is a real tropical jungle isn't it Snuffkin?
Not quite.
What do you mean?
Well, Moomin, a real jungle would have wild animals in it, wouldn't it?
Oh yeah, like tigers and snakes.
This is more of a tropical botanical garden, I suppose.
That's Moomin's little mind.
He can have the peel.
This is a life.
Stop, little mind.
Well, well.
What are you looking for dear?
My solar toady.
You what?
My sun helmet, I can't go into the jungle without it.
I didn't know you had one.
I used it for a fancy dress party once I know.
I put it in a box somewhere.
Oh, here it is.
Very dashing dear.
I thought so too.
Oh, I know.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Splendid protection is hat.
Papa, what in earth are you doing?
I want to get into the cellar.
What for?
To get my gun.
Your gun?
Only fools venture into the jungle without a proper gun.
I don't think you need a gun, Papa.
And why not?
Because there aren't any wild animals.
Well, one of the seas might have been an egg or something.
Look at these, for instance, they look very animal.
Very odd animals.
More of an odd plant, I think.
I'd stay away from them.
They could be very dangerous.
But they've got eyes.
Careful.
I think they're man-eating plants.
Man-eating.
Stop that.
Help.
Oh, they're trying to eat me.
They want to feed me to their young.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, help me.
Oh, help.
They're tearing my tail.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, no, oh, dear.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Help.
Oh!
Oh, no, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Well done, my little maya.
Just saved my life.
Well, I saved your tail, anyway.
Oh.
Oh, oh.
Oh! It's something to jam this door shut!
Come on! Hurry!
Oh! Oh! Oh, no! We... you can't hold on much longer!
Hmm.
Huh?
That should keep them in now, shouldn't it?
Well, I don't think they could push their way through that lot.
Hmm. They had a very strong grip on my tail.
He mustn't underestimate them.
Anything wrong?
You bet! The seller's full of man-eating plants tried to gobble up moment papa!
Oh!
Oh my goodness!
What's the matter?
You can get straight from the seller into the kitchen.
What? Oh no, mama!
Oh my gosh!
Oh, hello!
Cue, we got here just in time!
What ever's the matter with you? Are you all playing Tarzan?
Oh no, mama!
I'm making grandmas if you ever get a tropical fruit recipe.
And perhaps now it's rained I can wash this dirty floor.
Ah! Ah! By the great bumble I don't believe this a tropical rainforest!
Ah! Ah!
Ah! Ah! Transcendentia megaloids!
And yes, a dispensia florian wonder!
Goodness me, I can collect a whole tropical hermoreum right here in Moomin Valley!
Ah, Trowel, that's what I need. I'll get one from the Moomins!
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Yeah.
Must say they're not the tiniest family.
I'll have to move this.
Oh, this old furniture.
Yeah.
Huh.
Oh, here we go.
Me get out with Ormysik.
Huh.
Help!
I've got many things planned after this.
What?
They must have got out.
Huh.
They were in the cellar.
Did you open the door, Mr. Hamilin?
Well, yes.
I wanted to borrow a trowel.
Mr. Hamilin, you know all about plants.
Do you have any idea how we can get rid of them?
They're man-eaters, you know?
Can't rid of them.
Huh.
Well, let's see.
We are in a bit of a fix.
I have heard that they have reacted to music.
Music.
Snoopkin, you could play your harmonica.
Hmm.
Look, they've started dancing.
Keep it up, Snoopkin.
What will they do if he stops playing?
I really don't know.
Oh, what's this?
Oh.
They're rather sweet when they don't try to eat you.
And that was how a tropical jungle grew
and surrounded movement house in one night.
Is it going to stay?
And for how long?
And what will the man-eating plants do
if Snoopkin stops playing?
They love the laughter
and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring
and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter
and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring
and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They're taking the movements.