Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you on your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh,
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh-oh, oh, oh-oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh-hhhhhh...
The witch has come to Moomin Valley.
What could she be up to this time?
Eldris Cabalasum!
Oh!
Oh, it's snowing again.
I must get a covered brown.
Oh!
The great thaw had come at last.
The Moomin Valley.
I think I can smell spring!
Oh, I've never seen anything like this one before.
Hello there, Mr. Hamilton.
Hello, Sniff.
You're up early this year?
Yes.
I think I've even beat Moomin to it.
Is that so?
Why are the Moomin so late this year?
Moomin, wake up!
Spring is here!
It's time to wake up!
Moomin!
Maybe Snork Maiden's easier to wake up.
Snork Maiden!
And I thought I was difficult to wake up.
I must get closer.
What are you doing, Sniff?
What am I doing?
You can see, can't you?
Of course I can, but why are you climbing up that?
Moomin and Snork Maiden are still asleep.
I have to wake them up.
Why don't you go this way?
It's easier!
What are you doing?
Funny, even Moomin Mama's still asleep.
Wrong room.
Come on!
Wake up, lazy bones!
Moomin, spring has come!
We'll look at that!
Wake up, you sleepyhead!
Oh, you really are impossible!
Moomin, Moomin, Moomin!
This is odd, even for Moomin!
Open the window, little mind!
Oh, was I scared?
Oh, I haven't you opened them up!
I've tried, but they won't!
You're kidding!
No one can resist this little mind!
Wake up, Moomin!
I know you're ticklish!
Hmm?
Moomin!
I told you so!
Hmm?
Moomin!
Come on!
Eww!
I give up!
How strange!
How sad!
What do you mean?
I think...
You don't think...
It's hard to tell.
I was listening for his heartbeat.
He's still breathing.
And snort baited?
Wake up, you slug of it!
Snort baited!
They won't wake up!
This is strange!
Why don't we go and try the other?
Why not?
I hate it when others are asleep while I'm up.
But then I don't like it much the other way around either.
Do I snap?
Moomin!
Pop up!
Please wake up!
We've tried to wake up Moomin, but he won't!
Wakey!
Moomin!
Mama breakfast time!
Come on, Moomin!
Pop up!
Wake up!
This is no use!
Goodness!
This seems the Moomins are still hibernating.
And so is Snort Maiden.
That's odd.
She always wakes up even before me.
Oh, Moomin, too!
But this year it seems to be different!
I'll go back home, and I'll come over again in a little while
when the Moomin family will have woken up.
If they ever do.
Huh?
We've tried everything to wake them up short of buckets of water
and there's no moving them.
We've shouted and shook and pinched and tickled and stopped!
Oh, dear!
It's not just strange, it's ominous!
Oh, my, surely not.
Hello, everybody!
How is everyone?
What is it?
You all look very scared.
Huh?
Still hibernating?
It's all very strange, Hamilton.
Moomin!
See?
Yes, indeed.
How we can really do is wait and see.
I suppose you're right.
Don't worry.
The days are getting longer all the time now.
So the Moomins can't sleep much longer.
And Snort Maiden?
Cheat too, of course.
Bet you anything Moomin wakes up when Snuffkin returns.
I think you're right, Sniff.
And then, one day about a week later,
Snuffkin did come back from his yearly trip south.
Snuffkin!
Where's Moomin?
He's in bad.
Moomin's still asleep.
A sleep.
They won't wake up no matter what you do.
What do you think, Snuffkin?
I think they're very sick.
That's a possibility.
Sleeping sickness, perhaps?
It's very difficult to say.
To me, though, if you want my honest opinion,
I think somebody has cast a very nasty spell on them.
A spell?
But who would do that?
I think I know.
Huh?
You mean the witch?
Alice is grandmother.
Why?
To tell you the truth, I haven't the biggest idea.
How do we find out?
I'll go to the forest and see her.
And if she did cast a spell, do you think she'd tell you?
I really don't know, but we have to do something.
We can't just leave them sleeping here forever.
I'll go with you.
I guess I better stay here to take care of things.
Well, if they suddenly wake up, somebody needs to be here.
Snuffkin.
Huh?
That's him.
At last.
Moomin.
He's dreaming.
Just looking at him makes me feel sleepy.
Moomin, I promise to get this horrible spell cast off for you.
Uh-oh.
Oh, shit.
Where are you going?
I've done all the chores, even washed out your old push-in jars.
So where are you going?
It's here, Grandma.
I thought I'd take some time off to celebrate.
But what about your work?
I'm just going out for the day, Grandma.
And I know where.
I only want to see the Moomin's.
They're still hibernating.
No, they're not. It isn't winter anymore.
Winter or spring, I happen to know the Moomin's are still asleep.
How could you know what the Moomin's are up to, Grandma?
Hm.
Oh, which is no everything, my dear girl.
Really?
Well, I'll go and see.
Come here.
I have to admit that I can't help being worried about the Moomin's.
Their windows are open for the spring.
So they can smell the first spring flowers?
Well, I suppose I'd be getting on.
Why didn't you tell them about the witch in the spell?
Well, after all, that was just an idea, I got.
Ideas can be embarrassing if you were wrong,
so don't tell anyone for the time being.
All right.
I'm going.
And I'm leaving, too.
Okay.
There's Alicia.
Hi, everyone. It's me.
Why do you get a teller?
We better tell of the truth, I guess.
The best thing would be for me to talk to her first.
Yes, I agree.
She's unbelievable. How could she?
I can hardly believe you could be so mean, Grandma.
Calm down, my dear.
Why, I did it all for you, Alicia.
You did it for me.
If the moments are asleep, why should you go there?
Do them a world of good, too, along sleep.
How ridiculous, grandmother.
Alicia, you've done quite well in your studies,
and if you keep at it, I see no reason why you shouldn't be a fully-fledged witch before 30.
And if I do see the moments, I won't be a witch till I'm 31, is that what you mean?
Now, the moments are very bad, and the ones on you.
They are so disgustingly good, and if you want to be a witch, you mustn't see them.
And if I promise never to go near Moomin Valley again, will you lift the spell, Grandma?
Good girl, that's exactly what I wanted here.
You promise me, Dan, Alicia?
I promise, Grandma.
Right, the spell should be lifted.
Snuff guard.
What do you want?
There are two different ways of lifting the spell I cast on the moments.
Uh-huh.
The first one is that I go to Moomin Valley myself and chant the magic words outside their bedroom window.
Oh, Grandma, that's not a good idea.
Oh, oh, you mean people who might be upset about me casting a spell on the moments?
You may be right.
So therefore, Snuff Kid, I have no choice but to ask you to perform the task.
Oh, but why me?
You do have your harmonica with you?
Of course.
Let me have it, please.
Eldris Cabalasome.
If you don't stop staring at me, my witchcraft won't be effective.
Alicia, get me the next potion now.
Oh.
All right, grandmother.
Eldris Cabalasome.
Oh, she can't do it if we look at her, huh?
Now, listen, Inspector.
You must do something.
You are the police, aren't you?
Well, I have to tell you, waking people up is not really part of our job.
But you're our last hope, Inspector.
You must do something.
Perhaps if you could possibly use your whistle to wake them up.
Uh-huh.
It's very shrill indoors. Good frighten them.
And fire your revolver.
I'm sure that would do it, Inspector.
I don't carry guns, they're dangerous.
Oh, dear.
Hey, Snuffkin!
Little Y!
He sounds worried, I bet they're still fast asleep.
Hmm.
Right, Snuffkin?
Get on with it.
Hmm.
It's not working, is it?
Give me a chance, Snuff.
Hmm.
Snuffkin!
Wake up, spring is here.
Come on.
Hmm.
Oh, spring is here already.
Good morning, Papa, dear.
Hmm.
Good morning.
I have a feeling we've over slept.
I wonder whether the others are up yet.
Snuffkin?
Oh, shut up, Snuff.
Maybe she forgot how to cast off the spell.
Hi, Snuffkin!
Hi!
Ah!
Morning!
Morning, everybody!
Hi, Snuffkin!
I'm so glad you were right back already, Snuffkin.
Yes.
You woke up early, too.
Did you hear that?
It's you that woke up late, woman.
Ah, who we?
Hmm.
Ah.
Now I say, movement's all ready up and about.
What?
Ah, hi, Snuff!
Oh, it's you, you're awake.
I'm glad I didn't blow my whistle.
But we did have a reason to be worried, Inspector.
He's right.
What about, moment, Mama?
And, moment, Papa?
Oh, there, everybody.
Is anything the matter?
Nothing at all.
There are weak.
Oh, dear, I don't understand.
You don't understand words.
We were very worried because you just wouldn't wake up.
Oh, really?
You do know we always have a night, don't you?
We sleep all winter, and we always wake up in the spring.
Of course, of course, but this year, start your turn.
Right, well, we did have a bit of a problem.
You see, moment, Papa, we couldn't swim.
Snuffkin.
You're back already.
Yes.
Why don't you listen to us, moment, Papa?
Very well.
Why don't you come in and we'll have a nice cup of tea,
and then we can discuss your problem properly.
But it's your problem, I'm afraid, not ours.
What does he mean?
We don't have a problem, do we?
Please do come in anyway, everybody.
Please.
You too.
All of you, come in.
Come in, everybody.
I'm on the side.
I'm in Georgia.
Whatever happened was this year.
Hey, Snuffkin.
Alicia!
Oh, man!
We've come to see you, Alicia.
That was nice of you.
Your grandmother isn't home, is she?
No.
Then we can play hide and seek.
I can't.
I promise grandma there.
Yes, I know. Snuffkin told me.
That was a really great thing to do.
But you didn't promise not to see us.
You just promised not to go to Mom and Valley, didn't you?
Yeah.
And listen, you never promised not to play with us either, did you?
No.
So, if we came here to see you instead of you to us,
then it's all right, and you don't have to break your promise.
Oh, I suppose so.
Yes, I suppose you're right.
Well, let's play.
Yay!
13, 4, 3, 5, 8!
That afternoon, they all had the most wonderful time playing hide and seek in the woods.
Ha-ha-ha!
One, two, three,
your tiniest hour.
Five, six, seven,
ha-ha-ha-ha!
Mine, ten, eleven.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements,
believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and goes at play.
The movements are having fun day after day, the movements.
The movements, the movements.