here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the movements they are the movements so come with me give me your hand
I'll take you up to a movement land you can fly just like a bird sing that song ever there with the movements
there were the movements there were the movements there were the movements there were the movements
the sun is shining and movement valley is enjoying its usual
peace and tranquility wait a minute who's this wait for me moment
are they ready are what ready the pancakes not yet this hot goblin wood doesn't seem to burn very well
are they cooking they won't be long have some lemonade while you're waiting mama are the pancakes ready yet
oh well everything seems normal in the movement house I'm a dumbo I'm a no good me good boop nini
no you're not snork you're very clever I'm a failure of flap of frightful fraud and a misfit
but your land ship was a success wasn't it kid stuff look if you can make a ship that runs on land
then I'm sure you can make one that flies I believe in you fat lot of good that does me snort and maiden
you know last night I thought I've done it a fly ship then I looked at it again no good no good
it was all wrong wouldn't couldn't fly at all oh how could someone so intelligent be such an idiot
oh dear oh dear well they're ready go and tell the others little my all right
movement mama where's movement and snork maiden snork maiden's ball and again come on snork maiden cheer up
I'm sure snork will get over it inventors always feel down in the dumps when something doesn't work
this moment Papa do you think he invents stories doesn't he movement well there was really
snork maiden do you want some pancakes oh yes please movement mama
movement go and get papa I have a feeling his writing has got stuck again
okay mama now what's the matter snork maiden
the sun returned to the eastern sky when morning came and everything started to get lighter and
loud dear everybody knows that even the stupidest guitar really I have absolutely no literary
I'm an ignorant son a literate dilettant nor an illiterate idiot it's high time I gave up writing
oh yes papa yeah what is it moment mama said to tell you the pancakes are ready
well I can't stop now I'm being creative I'll eat later oh really yes anything else
yeah no I thought you said something
moment wait I'm coming
that was really good moment mama I'm going out I'm coming
no you can't snuffkin and I are going on an adventure and it could be dangerous
hi snuffkin hello movement didn't think you were coming sorry I'm late what's that
a leaf boat look it sails on the river just like a real one
I bet it goes all the way down to the sea and maybe even to some foreign lands
gosh snuffkin I'd like to do that one day let's go then shall we little my wanted to come
but I told you it was too dangerous hmm perhaps it wasn't the best thing to say look
I'm not climbing up there well I am wouldn't you like to keep me company instead look
there's a cave just a little bit further along this path why don't you two girls wait for a
sec we won't be long but if you can walk to it why on earth climb to it difficult for a girl to
understand well I think boys are difficult to understand we're not sure we can reach it from above
well we'll soon find out are you coming with a sniff oh I think I'll guard the rear protect the
cave from below oh yeah well someone has to look after the girls someone responsible
oh my goodness it's dark in there let's go in then I don't like the look of it we'd better
stay out here you never know who might live in there don't be silly no one lives in there that's
what I don't like yes exactly a place with no one living in it is really scary I think we must be
right above the cave here maybe I can't find a hole though let's look a bit more over that way moving
wow I've never seen a shell like this before look at that one they must be worth a fortune come
over here and look little mine where's little my snorke made and she went into the cave sniff oh no she
can't do that it might be dangerous little my little my come out no you come in scared he can't you
can't just go in like that you can so tell me how would you go in then mr. know it all stay where you
are we'll rescue you uh you're coming too aren't you snorke maiden you can't stay here alone I suppose so
let's go shall I hold your hand in case you get frightened little my where are you stop it please
you're frightening snorke maiden oh really I thought I was frightening you your voice is so shaky
oh wait I sound normally hey be quiet no I can hear something
me too perhaps it's the wind no snorke maiden it sounds like someone moaning
you can't scare me like that no one lives here who want to live here anyway it's dark and cold
it's moment and snuffkin they've climbed out and we can hear their voices in the distance
so we needn't worry why would they be moaning no it's not them I'm gonna go and investigate
don't little my please please stop it
oh
pull hard movement will this do right who's going first me okay but please be careful I will
oh take it easy movement there's no hurry
hey are you all right movement yes of course
oh
movement what's happened talk to me movement are you all right oh I don't know I think so
my bottom's a little bit sore though I'm sure I heard somebody scream just now well the
hamilin was down here having a nap the hamilin if this is another of your games movement I don't like
Mr. Hamilin we were climbing down from the top we didn't know you were asleep that's not quite right
I wasn't asleep I wasn't at all comfortable you know well what were you doing here then well
to tell you the truth I really haven't been quite myself lately you haven't lost any more rare
stabs have you Mr. Hamilin on the contrary movement I have them all even the rarest every single one
then what's wrong that's good isn't it I mean my collection is complete I know one in the
world has a better stamp collection than you have Mr. Hamilin no of course not mine is perfect there
isn't a stamp I haven't got rare ones old ones misprinted ones I have them all I still don't
understand there's no challenge nothing to search for you're too young and you don't collect stamps
oh dear me dear me I'm beginning to understand he's not a collector anymore he's got all the stamps
he could ever want that's the trouble it's not half as much fun that's why you're sad isn't it Mr.
Hamilin yes it is no fun no fun at all now I understand I can see why you're upset and me falling
on top of you like that didn't really help did it not exactly moment look who was taking a
nap in the cave oh it's you Mr. Hamilin so it must have been his snoring that we heard what a noise
he was making I'd never ever snore you certainly do
Robbys look if you promise not to tell anyone I'll take you to see something very special what is it
I think it could be repaired of course it could easy but you know you can't always tell the keel
doesn't look too good yes we could take it out to see a no time the sales got holes in it hey I
can't find any owners you can paddle all steer look out friends it's going over
hey hang on everybody
I've lost my confidence and it makes me feel very unhappy well it can happen to anyone you know
even to you well not much of course lucky you I just don't know what to do how can I get it back
there must be a way it's hard to say everybody's different but with me it just happens
I don't think I'll ever invent anything again perhaps I'll have a break from my memoirs too
tea time oh dear what's the matter with you too you look a bit down in the dance you know I might
have been a bit overconfident me too I think there's no need to yell we can hear you watch
the matter sniff we found a boat on the beach coming have a look a shipwreck washed up on the
shore it's not a wreck and it's got a white sail oh we're going to repair it and then it'll be ours
all right I'm coming come on snort let's take a look at this boat it could be just the thing
to cheer us both up so it's got a sail a white sail you say that could be extremely interesting
hmm it's a sturdy little craft is nicely built well designed she's abandoned so does that we can keep her
well it seems to be in pretty good condition except for the hole in the bottom you know maybe
that's why she was abandoned here you could be right stuff can finders keepers you guys of course it
makes it our boat you'd have to wait to see if anyone claims it first little mine what shall we do
then papa well first things first we must repair the hole and then tire up securely in case there's a
storm absolutely then if the owner comes we are to give her back to him mine you might know she's here
so what are we going to do when we've repaired her oh it's bad for boats not to be yours don't we
could sail the seven seas I'd be happy just to explore around here don't worry snort maiden if we
get big waves we can sail between them isn't that right moment papa well in a way now come on let's
get to work how about you snort will you help us yes of course can I do anything for you moment papa
yes if you'd like to Mr. Himmelon well I'm afraid I'm not much of a builder but if there is
something I could do well let's get her out of the water first shall we and we'll need some
big logs to go under her I think ten should be enough I'll be so let's go prime she'll need to
be safe to work on so we'll want something strong to keep her upright as well and lots of tools
now go home and get some and I think we'll need a bucket and a shovel or I'll come with you
help you choose yes you go I'll stay and keep guard in case the owner comes back
sleep well man the top cells what
are they all in bed my dear yes dear sleeping like logs I'm not surprised they all work very very
hard today I can't wait until the boat's ready and we can sail off somewhere my dear will go anywhere
in the world you like anywhere at all you've only got to say enough will jolly will go it doesn't
have to be far dear let's get to bed too we've got an early start the morning oh intellectuals
like me aren't used to this artwork oh I'm tired out and I can hardly move mama I better put
these tired legs tonight dear movement papa this will be good for him I think
oh dear oh dear
a perfect fit if I may say so yeah well now for the rest of her right
look at me movement I'm doing the tarring I know little my I'm only doing where you can't
reach oh all right then sniff you lazy land lever bring me some or tar I won't get it yourself
you lazy thing you wanted to do it I didn't want to carry tar though and anyway I'm the painter come on
hurry up moment mama should I cut it all out yes please snook me
hey feeling all right mr. hemmylin yes thank you you're fixing the boat very quickly yeah we sure
are should be finished very soon yes I'm sure it will that's what I was afraid of what shall I do
then snuff can well maybe you can start collecting something else what you think something else like
what well I don't know anything really how about butterflies no my second cousin does that and
he's a complete idiot it has to be something interesting ornaments ornaments yeah you could
collect those forever not scientific well it's up to you but I think you really ought to collect
something mr. hemmylin uh mama mama quick hurry up we're gonna launch the new boat all right wait
for me I'm coming the sail you men it is perfect mama come on how you ready everybody I'll count
to three then pushes hot as you can one two three
and so with their new boat finally repaired and uncleaned
movement and the others began to get very excited about their trip from the world
even snork and mr. hemmylin were in unusually high spirits all aboard for a trial run
I've decided what I'm going to collect flowers look here's my first sample it's a sweet
fryer Rosa Robeganosa that's great good for you snork maiden I've just had a new idea for my
flying ship I'm certain it'll work this time of course it will snork good luck I better get on
all right start paddling everyone we'll be back soon my dear moment mama take as long as you like
papa I'll prepare something cold for when you get back one two one two way away to the deep blue yana
one two one two
they love the laughter and they love the living the movements believing in sharing and caring and giving the
movements they're always happy and always at play the movements are having fun day after day the movements
the movements they love the laughter and they love the living the movements
believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements they're always happy and goes at play the
the movements are having fun day after day the movements the movements the movements