Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
There were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements.
Clap Clap Clap Clap
Clap Clap, and then clap
Pap dap dap dap bap bap
Pap dap dap, tap dap bap bap bap
Have you ever heard of Moon & Valley...
In winter, deep white snow covers the whole valley, and everyone goes to sleep so that they
keep warm.
Look, there's a woman house.
There's a woman, our hero.
A woman, Papa, and a woman, Mama.
And this little bundle must be little my.
I think before our story starts, we better wake everyone up with some spring sunshine.
At last, it's spring.
Wake up everyone, it's spring time.
Oh, little my, you're up.
It's hard to stay asleep with you yelling, I can't help it if I'm happy.
So yeah woke me, I was having a lovely dream about living in a watermelon, but it's beautiful
outside.
Oh gee, isn't it, is it really moving?
Yes, it's all fresh, the flowers are out and the sun is shining.
So, I like being asleep.
But it's spring.
You said you wanted me to wake you as soon as spring was here.
Oh boy, did I?
Yes, you did, little my.
You said you wanted to be a welcome as soon as spring was here.
Really?
Yes, you did.
Did I say something like that?
I can go back to bed if you want to.
Nobody's making you get up, little my.
No, there's really no point, movement.
I'm not sleepy anymore.
Well, there you are then.
Mama!
Good spring, movement.
Movement, mama.
I'm starving.
Have you got any watermelon?
No, but there's lots of other things.
We'll all have a nice big breakfast.
I can hear a snuff gun.
Wouldn't it be quicker to use the stairs?
More fun this way.
Are you going home now?
Yes.
Thanks very much for letting me spend the winter here.
Don't think your sister will be back yet, though.
I'll go anyway.
Snuff gun!
Oh, hello, movement.
It's really good to see you, snuff gun.
And you too?
You're back, Arlie.
Won't you have a good time?
Yes, I was.
But I didn't want to miss springtime and movement valley.
What did you do?
I'll tell you later.
Let's go wake up, Snuff, and think of something exciting to do.
I don't think I'll like it.
He's still snoring, movement.
I'll do it again.
Well, that's done it.
Come on, Snuff, it's spring.
Snuff gun's here.
Please go away, you two.
We're going to do something really exciting.
Like what, moment?
I can think of more exciting things to do than this.
Well, let's imagine that we're the first ever to climb this mountain.
It's such a clear day.
We'll be able to see all the movement valley when we get to the top and the sea.
Good morning, Mr. Hemiolens.
Morning, moment.
Are your father and mother up?
Yes.
Mama was when I came out.
Good.
I'll never understand how you can sleep for months on end.
We like it.
Oh, yes.
Why do they always have to do something exciting?
What a gorgeous view.
It really is.
Hey, look, they're smoke coming from moment house.
We should have stayed at home.
My bet moment, Mama's cooking something good.
Look.
What is it?
We're not the first here after all.
Look over there.
A top hat.
Hmm, a rather large one.
I wonder who's how it is.
I don't know, but I know papa would like it.
Hmm, it's much too big.
Look.
Oh dear, what's that?
I can really get inside it.
You see, I cover for my old one.
Oh, oh, oh.
Oh, I can't woman it.
Stuck, woman.
No, that's enough nonsense.
I think I'll take it off now.
Oh, damn.
What's the matter?
I can't move it. It's stuck, woman.
I'll give you a hand.
It's harder.
Oh, oh.
Oh, that's better.
Thank you.
What's all this noise?
Papa's head got stuck in the hat, Mama.
Oh, yes, and where did that come from?
Oh, a moment, Mama.
The children found it when they were out and brought it back for me.
It's very smart.
What shall we do with it, Papa?
There is something strange about it.
Shall I throw it away then?
Oh, no. It's too good for that.
Do we know anyone with a very big hand?
No, woman, Papa.
I know what we can do with it.
Oh, it's a...
A waste paper basket, Mama, Mama.
That's right. Well done, Snuffkin.
That was easy.
Come on, Snuffkin.
Come and have some breakfast with us.
Hmm, beautiful.
Yes.
Sorry to disturb you, but I'm going to see women.
Uh-huh.
Do you want to come with me, Snork?
Or would you rather stay here?
Uh-huh.
Well, are you coming or not?
Not coming, man?
Uh-huh.
Snork?
Well, you know my flying ship is almost finished.
It'll be ready this year. You'll see.
This isn't his target moment.
Whoa!
Oh, dear.
Perhaps it needs a little more work.
I wonder if you really can make a flying ship.
Don't be silly, of course you can't.
A little, my Snorks always dreamed about doing it.
Dreams are all right.
Yes, as long as they're not impossible.
I suppose so.
Hmm.
Sniff, you're not still feeding your face, are you?
Do you ever dream, Sniff?
Only nightmares about having no food at all, little my.
Hmm. I wonder who dropped this.
Now where can I put it?
Oh.
There you are. Just a thing.
Wow.
Golly, what are they?
They're clouds.
Be careful. Don't touch it. It might be poisonous.
It feels like cotton.
Well, ee!
This is great. I'm floating. Wonderful.
Can I try?
Are you ready, Snork Maiden?
Here we go.
What if you go too high?
My phone.
Wait for me.
Hey, wait for me.
Whoa.
Let me get on.
Ow. Ow. I'm falling.
Ow.
Woman Papa is in his study trying to write his memoirs.
A lot has happened to him over the years.
An awful lot.
And he's trying to remember it.
What was that?
Woman.
Hi, Papa.
What are you doing out there?
We're flying.
The clouds just came out of the house.
Try and get nearer so I can reach you.
No, I'm alright.
Why don't you come for a ride?
Stop. Wait a minute.
It's great. You feel like a bird.
Woman.
Come on, Papa. Jump or you'll fall.
It's alright.
Oh.
What?
Woman, Mama, quickly.
What's the matter?
Have you seen what the children are doing?
Yes.
Look at them. They're flying about on clouds.
It can't be safe.
Don't worry, Papa. It's alright.
I told them to be careful.
Come on, Snapping.
To go out.
I won, I won.
Whoa. Hey, wait a minute.
Little cloud. Wait for me.
Don't go away.
Oh, I got you.
That is tree cotton.
I'm going to climb right up here.
And I'm going to get you right there.
This branch. Come on.
Come on, little cloud.
I'm going to take you with me.
Here, come on.
You just keep coming back here.
Yeah.
I got you now.
You are going to get away from me.
Here I go.
Come on.
All of that ledge.
Stop.
I want you to play.
Oh.
Oh, boy. What's happening?
My cloud's starting to go.
Oh.
Whoa. Whoa.
That was fun.
Yeah, it was.
But I wasn't ready to stop.
Look.
There's movement in Snork Maiden.
Hey.
Why have they still got cloud snuffed in?
There's a starting to go as well.
I think they'd better get off.
Hey.
Right.
I'll start counting.
One, two, three.
Do you want something little mind?
Oh, yes.
A place to hide.
Boy, I don't think there's any place to hide.
And here is there.
No.
Oh, it's too dirty in there.
I'm going to have.
I know.
I'll hide in the head.
Oh.
One, two, one, two, one.
Hey.
Huh?
Gotcha.
Snork Maiden.
Hey.
Baaah!
Movement must be around here somewhere.
Well, last time I saw him, he was hiding in the fireplace.
Have you found him yet?
No.
Have you looked in the cellar?
Yes, I have.
Wait a minute.
Did you hear someone laughing?
Where'd it come from?
Gee, I better go home.
Oh, is there anything wrong?
Yes.
I can't find moment anywhere.
Well, he's too fat to be most places.
He's coming from under the hat.
Well, here I am, sniff.
Who on earth are you?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
I won, and didn't I?
You looked everywhere in the house,
and you couldn't find me, couldn't you?
So I won.
Who'd want to find you anyway?
Well, you were trying hard enough, weren't you?
What is this, a new game?
My name's Snork Maiden.
What's yours?
I'm the king of Movement Valley.
My pretty one.
You're too ugly to be the king of anything.
Well, now.
That's not a very nice thing to say to your friend.
Is it, Papa?
Now, you'd better tell me what you have done with Movement.
But I'm here.
Where?
Right here.
Who are you?
And where is Movement?
Papa.
I'm certainly not your Papa.
Yes, you are.
Come on.
I'm Movement.
I don't know who you are.
I'm not Movement.
He's nice and handsome and nothing like you.
Have you looked at yourself in a mirror?
Ah!
But where's my nose gone?
Oh, there's nothing there anymore.
Ah!
Oh no!
My tail's all pushy!
Ah!
Oh!
This is terrible!
Who are you?
What have you done with me?
It must be a nightmare!
I want to come back!
Go away, you're horrible!
Dear me, what's all this noise?
What's happened?
Mama!
What earth is this?
This is Movement, but just look at him.
You don't look like I'm Movement.
I am, I am.
Please believe me, Mama.
I am Movement.
Well, I don't know.
I'm sure.
Something's happened to me.
Why do I look so different?
Now then calm down.
This won't help at all.
We don't need all this noise.
If you really are Movement, then everything will be alright.
Just give me a minute or two and I'll know.
Mama, call me Movement, please.
I don't know what's happened, but I am me.
Honestly, I am.
Mama, please believe me.
I am Movement.
Let me see.
Oh, Mama, you do know it's me.
You must.
You can forget your little movement.
Please, Mama, please, Mama.
Oh, hush now, hush now.
Mama!
Yes, you're my little movement alright.
Oh, Mama!
Oh.
Oh, Movement.
Papa.
Oh, Movement, my boy.
Where were you hiding?
In there.
In the hat?
Let's hope it's the last we'll see of it.
Movement, Papa, decided that although it was a fine hat,
it was too dangerous to keep.
So, Movement threw it in the river and it floated away.
He wasn't too sure about it though,
because it was a rather special hat.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.