here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the movements they are the movements so come
with me give me your hand I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just
like a bird sing that song ever there were the movements there were the
movements there were the movements there was the movements there was the movements
The rain was falling on Moomin Valley as though the heavens had decided to empty
themselves. It was the wettest weather that anyone could remember.
Mama, can I borrow all this?
Of course, dear.
And this one too?
Yes, dear, but what do you need them for?
It's a secret. A secret?
Yeah, sure.
I'll want to see a back moment, but you can keep the jar if you like.
Thanks.
Oh, dear, oh, there are puddles everywhere.
Oh, dear, Mr. Hemmielen, what a mess.
Hello, Mr. Hemmielen.
Oh, good morning, Moomin.
Oh, it's all misty now.
What are you doing, Moomin?
Observing very closely.
Oh, splendid, my boy. I'm glad you find botany so exciting.
Oh, what exactly is it you're observing?
I'm sure I saw a beautiful crayfish in there.
Crayfish? Excuse me, young man, but that is the wallets.
Is he quite the most un-interesting field?
Oh, there it is.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Ahahahaha. I got him, I got him. I got him.
Oh, dragon.
Mm-hmm.
Papa!
Oh, what have you got?
I don't know.
Papa!
Oh, what have you got?
I don't know.
Oh, what have you got there?
Oh, oh, nothing, Papa.
Everything's so fresh after the rain.
Oh, woman.
Yes, it is.
I've got to show this to Snuffkin before anybody else sees it.
Mm-hmm.
Oh.
Boom, woman.
What have you got there, woman?
Oh, nothing. Nothing at all, little lie.
Oh, yes, you have, I saw it.
Lie to me.
It's just one of Mama's old jars.
Liar, liar, I know there's something.
I don't think there's nothing.
Then why are you hiding it?
Oh, why did a little mice see me?
It's not fair.
Dragon.
Oh, yeah, I was right.
It must be a baby dragon.
Probably the very last one on Earth and washed up by the rain.
A dragon of my own.
Well, that's wonderful.
Oh, I hope I didn't frighten you.
I know what I'll do.
I'll take the lid off the jar so you can get some fresh hair, little dragon.
See? That's better, isn't it?
Come on, little fella.
We'll give you a car to make you feel better.
Oh, that burnt me.
What a fierce little dragon you are.
Don't worry. I'll look after you.
I'll take good care of you.
And when your bigger and start to like me,
I'll take you swimming in the sea.
Oh, I'm sorry. You must be starring.
I'll get you something from my nighttime emergency food box.
I've got lots of things in there.
Bound to be something you like.
Go on. Take anything you want.
Oh.
Gosh, that's really clever, little dragon.
Move in. Lunch is ready.
Coming!
Now you stay here. Don't worry.
I'll be back in no time at all.
Remember, you're my own little dragon.
Oh.
Where's Sniff? I thought he was here as well.
He's collecting worms for fishing.
He'll be here soon.
We'll start without him then.
You know, Mama, certain people keep secrets in glass jars.
Secrets?
Oh, yes, a little secret that hisses.
Moment, Mama, I found this near the big puddle.
Thank you, Sniff.
Moment, I told you I wanted it back.
It's my very best one.
Sorry, Mama. I was so excited.
I must have left it when I found...
I mean, when I was...
And I'm sure you know who I mean by certain people.
Did you catch anything with the sieve, Moment?
Yes, he did.
Something that's now hidden in his room.
Big mouth.
If it's a secret little my.
Perhaps he doesn't want to tell anyone.
Yeah, probably because his new pet bites.
Well, it hasn't bitten you yet, hasn't it?
Huh. If it did, I'd bite it back.
Is it true? Does your secret really bite people?
Well, it couldn't bite very hard.
If it was small enough to go in a jar, could it, Papa?
I suppose certain people might keep other small things in jars,
beetles and spiders, mosquitoes, scorpions, or poisonous centipedes,
horrible things that multiply and multiply every week
and grow and grow until the jars are too small.
See? Like that.
And there'll be so many of them, thousands and thousands
and they'll take over moving valley and eat us all.
Oh, well, I haven't got a centipede.
Hmm. I wonder if centipedes come from out of space.
But this is the Earth's deer.
The rain could have brought them down from space, Mama, couldn't it?
Well, you could be right.
It was raining very hard yesterday.
And it wasn't like ordinary rain.
I saw a puddle as big as a lake.
What's the matter, Moomin?
It isn't a centipede.
Huh. We're on the right track, though.
Well, I'm glad it's not a poisonous centipede.
I shouldn't have liked that.
Oh, you're asleep. Moomin's little dragon.
Is it okay if I go see Snuffkin, Mama?
Have you finished already?
Yes, I have.
Tell them they mustn't go into my room.
Or they'll have to take the consequence, sis.
All right, Moomin. I'll make sure no one goes in there.
I promise.
Oh, but he's going to tell Snuffkin the secret.
I should think he is.
Best friends always come first, little Mai.
Hey, Snuffkin!
Hi.
Fishing again?
Yep. The cards told me that if I caught five minutes, one right after the other, I'd be traveling south.
South?
You're joking.
Not at all. I believe in the cards.
But Snuffkin, winter's not here yet.
I know that. But the cards tell you things for a reason, Moomin.
Do they really?
But it would be awfully few anyway, Snuffkin.
It's just awful. I mean, I'd be very lonely.
And anyway, who would I talk to, or tell my secrets to?
Oh, Snuffkin, quickly. You must come up to Moomin House.
Now?
Yeah.
Well, I suppose I could fish later.
No, no. There's no point.
But I have to catch five minutes.
Oh.
The fish won't bite after all is rain. You'd catch nothing.
It'll be better to wait until it stops flowing so fast.
Well, perhaps you're right.
So what's this big secret all about?
Hey, Moomin.
Have you ever seen a dragon Snuffkin?
No, of course not.
They all disappeared off the face of the earth many hundreds of years ago.
But perhaps they didn't all disappear.
What if there was one alive somewhere?
That's impossible.
It could be so small that it would go in a glass jar Snuffkin.
Are you sure you're not daydreaming Moomin?
But still, anything is possible, I suppose.
But you know me.
I have to see it right in front of me before I believe it.
Oh, where is it?
Mama promised me that she wouldn't let anyone in.
It's not here either.
Well, you were right, Moomin.
What?
Ah, there he is.
I think you've found a real dragon.
How do you get up there?
He mustn't fall. He might lose his tail.
Don't move, little dragon.
And Snuffkin, keep quiet.
He might get frightened and do something silly.
Don't worry. I'll soon have you down.
This will do. I'll lay it on the floor here.
Jump, little dragon. Don't be afraid.
Come on. Hold on to this.
It will bring you down slowly.
Don't panic.
I don't think it's a very good idea, Moomin.
You'll only scare him away.
Why don't you just leave him alone?
He'll come down when he's ready.
Dragons aren't helpless, you know, even little baby ones.
But he's so small.
Come to Moomin.
Come on. Don't you understand?
Hold onto that and I'll listen to that.
Ah!
Look at him.
My dragon can fly. He's flying. He's flying.
Come down, little dragon.
You might question or something. Come down.
Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
Be careful, Snuffkin. He might bite.
I don't think so. He's a very unusual pet.
I think he'll like you more than me.
Ah!
What a charming little creature movements.
I think he'll like you more than me.
What a charming little creature, Moomin.
He's lovely. What's his name?
He's called Little Dragon.
Huh. I don't think he's lovely at all.
Small but savage, if you ask my opinion.
That sounds just like you, little mind.
You think so?
Ow!
No, oh, oh, oh.
Whoa!
Ow!
Now look here.
Ah!
He seems to have a thing about ears, doesn't he?
Steps Snuffkins, why doesn't he bite him?
Go on, Dragon.
Go on, Vitamy's really tasty, go on!
Good news, I think he's trying to heat up Snuffkins coffee.
He must really like him.
Clever little thing.
Well, I hope he's careful with that hot breath.
We don't want to start a fire.
All right, that's enough.
He might be useful.
When he's bigger, we can put him in the cellar
and he'll be able to heat the whole house just like a furnace.
No, we will not.
Huh?
Go away! You passed!
Ow!
And you!
He only thought you were trying to get his flood.
I'll get him if he bites me again.
Just you watch me do it.
Come on, little dragon.
I'm sure that'll keep him quiet.
I'd better go.
Thanks for the coffee, Mumma.
Oh no, it'll suffocate him.
He only seems to like Snuffkin.
Well, we all like Snuffkin.
Stupid old dragon.
No, he isn't.
Mum and dear, why don't you take him to your room?
He'll be happier there.
This will be best for him.
Oh, I wonder if he'll come back to visit us.
Why did you do that?
He was cute and we could have always worn earmuffs.
You can visit him in Snuffkin's tent.
I expect little dragons already sitting on his shoulder.
It doesn't matter anyway.
Snuffkin's going south soup.
They'll be able to go together.
Oh, my dear, Mumma.
Never mind.
Well, you're a bit of a problem.
I don't want you here, little dragon.
Go on, go away. Go to Mumma.
Don't do that.
Oh, come on, please go to Mumma.
Look, you're very nice and it'll be fun to have you along.
But there's Mumma.
And he'd know you were here and you'd be upset.
Oh, there's another one.
That's the fifth.
Oh, dear.
Hmm?
Any luck?
Not bad.
Are you going far?
Oh, I'm fair away.
Would you like some fresh fish?
I'm sure you'll get hungry.
Yeah, what do you want in return?
A small favor.
Take this as far as you can.
Open the lid and just leave it.
What? Just leave it?
Yes, in a nice quiet place.
With lots and lots of flies.
Flies? What's in there?
A dragon.
A dragon, does it bite?
Well, it might.
This is a big favor.
I don't even like minnows.
Oh, they're not too bad if you roast them.
Keep the lid on.
But make sure you open it up later so it can catch the flies.
All right, as long as it doesn't try to bite me.
Don't worry, it won't.
Hello.
Hi.
Oh, well, where is he?
Who is that?
My dragon.
He must have come here, Snuffkin.
Oh, really?
I thought he was home with you, sleeping in your room.
No, I let him out.
Ah, well, dragons are very fickle.
All they really care about is big fat flies.
It's best to forget about a moment.
Did you catch your five minnows?
No, you were right.
The water is too fast.
Oh, really?
So I won't go soft until winter comes.
You'll stay here then?
Well, I'm sure it wouldn't do to go against the cards.
Now what a moment, my friend.
Oh, that's great.
You're staying, Snuffkin.
That's fantastic.
That's really, really good.
Ah, perhaps I shouldn't have painted the float bright red.
It might have scared those little minnows right away.
Okay, let's go.
Yeah.
That dragon was sort of stupid.
Baby dragons are.
They make the world's worst pets.
They never want to settle in one place.
Yeah, you're right.
It was very funny, though, when it bit little mice here.
I think it gave her a taste of her own medicine.
The woman was very happy that Snuffkin was staying in Moomin Valley
and not going south until winter.
And as for the dragon, well, who wants to be loved by a silly old dragon?
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.