here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the movements they are the movements so come with me give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just like a bird sing that song ever there with the
movements there were the movements there were the movements
during his long winter sleep movement had a dream and strangely enough he dreamt that he was
sleeping
Alicia Alicia wow you can fly on the broomstick now that's right I'm a fully fledged witch now
movement wait give me a ride Alicia can't do that oh don't be mean Alicia because someone's
already riding with me oh man it's me a little boy would you mind if we went a little higher
Alicia sure oh please listen come back please give me a ride
oh well you give me a ride now come on
and
woman valley is really beautiful from up here yes lovely oh at least you'd be careful don't do
things like that what are you talking about we're not doing anything woman a little boy it's you
again no wonder the broom is shaking so much how do you like it I'm pretty good at this aren't I
where did you get this broom from little my I've brought it from the wind bottled it for a while
that's the witch isn't it looks like it maybe we better get out of here you're right stop you two little
thieves give me back my bro that was no yeah you have your own from you witches should learn
out of share but there's no one is just a spare I want my veil from back right now finders keepers
it's my broom come out of brown huh why don't you take a closer look at it that's not a
what do you mean this is not a broom
movement you're right little my little my isn't here movement oh oh I must have been dreaming
you were yelling out loud oh I'm so sorry I didn't mean to wake you up snorkemen
can you see anything only snow everything so light yes the morning's up oh what an
airy light yes spring hasn't arrived yet has it not yet everybody else is still asleep then yes
most of them anyway wonder if my brother's still up well he did say before we started
hibernating he wanted to finish his blueprints before spring if he could I hope you'll succeed
this time when you go out outside just to see what the snow looks like oh no I don't really feel
like it it's nice and warm here why don't we sleep does spring like the others spring is still a
long way off guess you're right it is nice and warm in here
oh
damn it's delicious chocolate cakes my favorite yes I did you say something snorkemen
I'm so very hungry movement your mother's raspberry juice is really the best it is isn't it
everybody said that last winter too he moment yeah I have a funny feeling someone is watching us
and I don't like it one little bit moment poppacate explain it I'm sure of course someone's watching
what but who and how do you know to take you told me all about it last winter snort maiden she
doesn't hibernate you know she lives in our bathhouse and watches over us in the winter she said
that many things are too shy to show themselves oh have you seen them yourself short of except they
were invisible of course like under the sink or in the clock maybe in the empty fireplace and other
dark corners of the room I can feel it did you actually look anywhere for them oh no they'd be
very upset it's better not to let them know we know where they are I wonder what these things look
like some of them look very much like us two tiki said old ancestors of ours from way back she
thinks some of them look like as she said well I've never seen them for myself I wonder if there is
good looking as we are wouldn't it be a good idea to stay up and wait for the sunrise a great idea
now don't say anything to scare them but this is one of the movement's ancestors from way back
is it morning already are you sure I think so there are no clouds so why can't we see the sun I guess
maybe the sun doesn't come up at all this time of the year mom and I don't like this I don't like
you one little bit you silly little girl what do you need this for please grandma I will be
long I promise what are you talking about is if you could fly a broom get back back to me at once
no I won't give it back now give me back bram and don't be silly how many times from
I tell you you can't go visiting Moomin Valley but it's so boring here I want some company grandma
come on bram fly off take me to Moomin Valley
oh help me up grandma please all right my girl I'll help you up shall I
I don't believe it I'm floating
oh
oh this is great
wait oh
I'm falling
oh
how about that of these
I'll find the bird around here
oh
to bury things a bit how about this
oh no
stop the bram grandma
oh
you wanted to ride on the brum didn't you first so look like well
if you want to learn to fly on this bram Alicia then forget all about those
dreaded movements and really start studying it's hard work you know young woman you
let's learn concentrate
hey you up there are you making fun of me too
oh I can't climb down there of course you can even if you fall you can't hurt yourself on this soft snow
don't shake the ladder Moomin this is scary slowly does it take it easy as
you can don't look down maybe going out wasn't such a good idea after all
we can always change our mind to go back to sleep you know
see you've made it it's very cold out here Moomin but I'd rather like it
this is the roof over the front door isn't it yes and everything will be snowed up now to spring oh no
what's happened to our firewood
what's the matter there's not much wood left in here someone else must be burning it
yes but who and for what I wonder I can feel it we're not alone in this forest I'm sure
someone's watching us all those winter creatures no I don't think it's them
the grog
goodness me look how big she gets in the winter time
Moomin I'm scared it'll be all right
grog stop right there
don't come any closer if you please you're much much too cold for us you see
you could freeze a stiff you know oh is it possible that you get lonely all by yourself
I don't think there's anything we can do to help you know not without fur coats and earmuffs and
more gloves anyway we must go
someone's been stealing our firewood I wonder what they're doing with it
something bad there's no doubt about that must have been several people did this
we had a lot of fun here in the summer remember well the she is still here
round of the ice I hope too ticky too ticky there's no one here are you sure look for yourself
I know they're invisible but I'm a shrewmice in here hard to tell with things you can't see
oh what is it it felt like something scampering on my back that's all right it must be one of the shrewmice
oh my god my goodness I've never seen anything quite like this before hi it's good to see you
you're right she's fishing hi to ticky hello to ticky so this winter's not meant to walk up to huh
uh uh I walk her up by mistake you know that spring is still a long way off don't you I thought it
might be seeing there's no sun at all but the sun is going to come back tomorrow woman tomorrow
snorkemaiden was so worried about the sun not showing the sun will rise tomorrow woman but it'll
go down very soon to ticky you know I think there must be records in moving valley records in winter
there's an enormous pile of firewood up on the hillside I know it took a long time to collect that
wood but some of it belongs to us that doesn't really surprise me though woman I'm afraid the
winner creatures unfair careful about ownership they need a lot so if they see it they take it it's
for their big winner bonfire a bonfire yes and now your firewood can take part in the big celebration
they light it every winter to make sure the sun comes back you know oh you mean otherwise the sun
wouldn't come back to ticky well since they always light it on this day you don't really know do you
tonight you might see the winner creatures okay we come along as well to ticky yes you can if you
sit quietly and don't scare them in any way wonderful you're coming along too aren't you
it of course stop happy someone shouting for help who could it be
go away get away from me I didn't do it on purpose I didn't mean any harm if you don't leave
me alone grandma will turn you into a towed oh it's so cold go away please
oh
grow leave her alone what are you doing Grog
movement Alicia now listen Grog why can't you be nice to her Alicia's one of my friends she was
just standing there looking at nothing when I came down on my skis I nearly bumped into her but
I didn't touch her that's all right Alicia tell me Grog what's gotten into you why you so nasty
to such a sweet little girl it isn't like you at all I must have startled her I guess and I did
apologize and all but it made no difference this is really very odd then I asked if she had seen
you and that's when she started to get mad at me but she doesn't even know me it's a mystery
whatever's the matter with you Grog
oh it was so scared I'm so glad you've come to see us so am I moment somehow I felt certain you
hadn't gone into hibernation yet but what did your grandmother say nothing because I
didn't tell her I was coming thank you for chasing off that terrible monster the Grog hasn't
actually ever attacked anyone well maybe she doesn't like the look of Alicia snork maiden oh it's
really a mystery to me why the Grog was here at all she was here looking for a moment no doubt was
she he suddenly become very popular you don't mean
what's the matter with you I think the Grog may have fallen in love with you movement what oh you
can't mean that please tell me you're not serious it's out of the question it's a ridiculous idea don't
be so silly
oh
where's all that drumming noise coming from from the invisible shroom ice how long before everybody
oh they're here already movement all around us they are where I can't see them
are they really invisible I can't see them either but I can feel their presence all around me
but she's been studying witchcraft hasn't she I'm sure you and movement will be able to feel
their presence quite soon
oh
I can see some of them look they're over there
I see them too you guys
do you think you tell me why can't we see all of them well we can never see them all
I don't understand how did you know earlier on the shroom ice were playing the drums
I just know because they sometimes play them in the batch house as well
what a wonderful celebration isn't it lucky I came over here if I had not
had missed a most memorable evening
what's going on here the grog what
what's she doing she must be looking for movement again I guess no I think she just wants to warm
this up by the fire
what's she doing
oh that's the end of the midwinter bonfire pull grog she freezes everything she touches
whatever she sits on even the hottest bonfire turns freezing cold in a matter of seconds
well at least she's managed to save some of our wood
oh hold on tight now snorke made in and be careful I can't wait to get into bed
I wanted to stay up until the sun came up again but I don't know if I could keep awake till then
so long till spring man room man goodbye and take care Alicia I will move in the moon will light my way back
this time the movements of God too far something must be done I'll teach them a lesson they'll never forget
they won't get the better at me now what does the witch mean by teach them a lesson
that sounds very ominous let's hope at least that she lets them sleep till next spring
they love the laughter and they love the living the movements
we're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements
they're always happy and goes at play the moments are having fun day after day the
moments the moments, the moments
The Moons