here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me therefore you are your TV they are the movements they are the movements so
come with me give me your hand I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly
just like a bird sing that song ever there were the movements there were the
movements there were the movements there were the movements
all over moving down bits of paper were fluttering down
they were even falling over the lake
what's this oh litter there's some writing on that piece of paper I think it's a
message hmm let's see moment theater presents written by moment papa
moment papa the last children of moment Valley starring moment papa
moment mama and sniff and introducing Emma Emma I'm sure that's my ad she works
in a theater admission fee anything edible they're putting on a play so they can't
be lost I haven't seen a play since I was a kid it was wonderful the best play
ever all about a princess she fell asleep in a rose bush she was so lovely I've
got to see that one again but who will guard my prisoners I wonder I'm a good
idea officer you could take the three of us with you to the theater to see the play
good idea we love the theater so we won't try to run away officer I promise
not possible I won't let you out of this jail until you write out it's forbidden to burn
signs five thousand times each that's the punishment for vandals well in that case you won't be
able to see the play who cares although yes I must see it I must go so you'll take us with you
no you stay right here well then you can't go either officer right you're upsetting me
no no this isn't good enough it's not true drama please woman papa I don't want to be just a
lion's ugly behind but sniff I did give you another part I don't want to be a baby either
and she said you wanted parts with that lines it could you do the dusting a bit later Emma please
he's script should be ready now we have to start practicing for the opening night tomorrow morning
don't worry Emma it's coming along I'm only half done I shall never get ready in time
moment mama you're right to worry for the curtain will rise tomorrow no matter what
women papa will remember to give Emma lots and lots of lines she's really looking forward to
her first performance all right now leave me I must be left alone to concentrate the writer needs
peace and quiet there are some things I don't like about this script I'll discuss it with you
after the performance sniff after if it's a story about lost children why do you have to have a
stupid lion I'm too good an actor to be cast as a lion keep them out of my hair when indeed he's
giving me a headache you come with me sniff we'll practice our parts this could be a wonderful
play if you'd only skip the lions behind I've heard enough about this behind remember we have
a lion's head too dying to show his acting skills on the stage this is my play and I refuse
to write out the lion's part I refuse here's the key I want you to keep a keen eye on them until
I come back do you understand me cousin are they very dangerous yes they certainly are they bite
if you let them out okay we certainly wouldn't bite anyone obviously I've had enough of your
lies don't listen to my dear cousin they do well then now I'm up to the theater to see the play
take good care of them while I'm gone
excuse me you seem to be a very good knitter oh thank you nobody ever said that to me before I enjoy it
what are you making I'm not sure I don't really know nothing in particular it's just that
knitting is so reassuring somehow nothing bad can happen while you knit can it trouble is I
always seem to forget to decide what to make before I start but it feels nice and warm and I
love the color couldn't you make socks it's a very nice sock color socks yes it's very very
cold in here oh yes that's a very good idea listen if I knitted each one of you a pair of warm
socks would you really put them on of course that will be nice I'm almost freezing to death in here
it's so very very cold is it really that cold yes my teeth are chattering so I could hardly talk
honestly oh dear oh dear what should I do maybe some steaming hot black currant juice would help
to warm us up a little possibly although it might already be too late
my cousin would be very angry with me if he knew but I think but you think why I think I'll
let you out so that we can all be nice and warm indoors really don't cry now baby there's a good
boy don't cry honey that's enough baby oh woman mama you need to show much more immersion it's
right to be more motherly and more loving listen dear this is a very happy baby how am I doing
woman papa you're just perfect for the part sniffing your performance was excellent
maybe I should add a part with some lines in it
look at these I think they might be ready by now I hope they're tasty they don't always come out
very well you're so kind we've had so much already but they smell really delicious they sure do
thank you so much now I feel warm again how about some more black currant juice or maybe one of these
freshly baked cookies it's very kind of you but no thank you I couldn't eat another thing I'm so
full up me too oh dear the party is over then I'm afraid so it's really sad but I have to
lock you up again but at least I know you're warm in there we're really sorry too but you don't
need to worry because actually we're not going back to jail oh aren't you we've got other plans
we're going to the theater to see my parents play and I suppose I should say hello to my Aunt Emma
who works there oh what shall I do my cousin will be very cross with me but you see we're innocent
we didn't do anything wrong you didn't I swear it do I look like someone who pulls up signs in a
park we just burned some flats and left by the flood but your cousin wouldn't believe it he
jumped to conclusions wrongful arrest that's all it was oh dear why didn't you tell me that it
once oh people shouldn't go to jail when they haven't done anything wrong so we can go to the
theaters that okay of course better leave right away my cousin will be very disappointed but I
guess I can't be helped wait for me I think I'd better come along and explain to that cousin of
mind that his three prisoners are innocent of the charge against them
all right all right bring it in that's right momma stop there okay sniff moment mama what have
you got there a baby's crib I want to use this in the play if that's all right with you
moment papa moment papa I just read your script and I think you have a big problem who is going
to pay the parts of moment and snorkemaiden in this play of yours I don't know yet we don't have
any more children and sniff can't take the part are you utterly mad we only have a few hours
before the curtain goes up and you don't even have actors for all the part what kind of director is
that maybe one of us could stand behind something and sort of read their line we did kill us
idea let's hope the credits are brown hold on tight all of you
listen kids you can be as noisy as you like out here but once we're at the
end or you have to be quiet you want to stand
the audience is waiting for us come
so
ladies and gentlemen thank you so much for giving up your valuable time in order to come to our show
tonight the world premiere of the lost children this is a brand new company the players never
been performed before ladies and gentlemen sit back and enjoy the superb acting what's that a
baby's cradle it's for you sniff for me we sincerely hope you'll be thrilled by the
originality of the plot and so now dear friends let's get started let's get started
come on come on come on
there's a good boy don't cry honey please don't cry
oh woman snork maiden my darling children you've been lost for a whole month and we haven't
heard a word from either of you oh he's forgotten all about me I'd give the whole world to be
rid of this most terrible agonizing despair oh make your husband try not to fret so I'm sure
they'll be back before very long little children come and free me from this plight your mother worries
all day through the babies awake go night come home come home my children to with all our hearts we're
missing you
louder sniff
but what's wrong with you sniff this rocket's making me sick oh dear in right in the middle of
movement poppers play oh mama let us set forth and find our loved ones we cannot leave our baby
here oh anyone would love to have him sweet little thing for how long pray do you think we
would be gone for as long as it takes I can no longer stand being this frightfully upset about my
children oh baby yeah
hurry up sniff I've seen two is about to start help me somebody I get out of here
when do they put the princess on we still have very far to go I'm afraid so hurry
I am hurrying it's for bitten it's for bitten it's for bitten why are you writing on that
yeah my cousin won't give up I'm sure so I better write this five thousand times it's for bitten it's
for bitten it's for bitten a full two weeks has passed oh what shall we do I dear children have
disappeared from the face of the earth oh what happened dear apple of my heart I think I
sprayed my hands really badly oh it hurts if you were in trouble apart from the wolves we're all
alone I'll put you out why was this happen in my theater I've been squeezed in here to make me look
smaller hell I'm trying to we can't have the land on stage without his behind we have to face
the worst and spend the night right here in the wilderness dear husband will it be all right
fairly in these unallowed woods I feel quite queasy sweet wife I too can smell those frightful beasts
howling for a blood may not just smell them dear now do you think that I can hear them now
I can hear the howling of those hungry beasts paint is the roar but I can make it out to lion
oh sniff what's up where are you going dear oh listen I have to go and stop that stupid lion who's
roaming around the countryside watching our every move hey don't worry I'll be right back my dear
was he supposed to say that hey what are you doing here you're supposed to be on stage
it's not my father stuck in his crib woman mama stuck on stage roll lion
that lion sounds very close my husband must be in great danger all right under that stage both of you
papa I can't get this thing off I feel sick
oh what are you doing woman papa you can do it with a cradle on sniff no I can't stop it please don't
do it woman papa don't laugh at me out there don't worry nobody knows it's you hiding in there come
on now all right
a lion a lion is this to be my most timely end
don't you dare laugh at me
oh
is that lion gonna eat moving mama
why do you do what should I do woman papa I'm scared
let's run off across the stage dear we were supposed to run off together
the situation has changed I'll have to come to your rescue some other time here
wow
oh please don't want to leave please oh now
everyone take that for me see
help me please someone come quickly before I get killed oh coming moving mama
oh
oh it's only snap little my I'm so glad you're all right
Shirley weren't worried about me moving mama well just a little maybe but you're such a lucky girl
I knew you'd manage mama mama I don't believe it mama it's me moment and it's me snorling in
mama mama move it snorkemaiden is it really you come here and let me see you
we've come back mama I was dying to see you oh it's wonderful to have you back
isn't that my face and Emma oh you look so grown up
and Emma so sorry to have missed your show but I have so much to tell you
hi everybody that was a great performance snorkeman I'm so glad to see you glad you say it moving
hey
those are my prisoners they've escaped from jail catch them
no cousin I let them out because they swear they're innocent they didn't pull up a single one of
those signs that's right I was the one who did that deliberately and I helped him very well
you're both under arrest
we were these pretzel children dear cousin it's forbidden it's forbidden
five thousand times that's what you wanted and are you sure there are five thousand oh yes quite
sure I've counted them one two three four now that we are all together again I would really like
to go back to movement valley what shall we do with all these little pests snuffed in
well little my someone might like to foster them you can leave them in my car sir
you always am odd yes now I have some acting experience I think I would like to start an acting
school exactly what this theater needs what a good idea do you think I would be too old to attend
perhaps character parts like in my play all is arranged for the best so now we can go home
it is moment papa I think it's high time quiet please I've lost my cap now I'll have to start again
right from the beginning moving papa do you think we should thank the audience for their
patience because they're still watching us you know oh you're right ladies and gentlemen
that's all for tonight I hope you have enjoyed the performance I think it was very kind of you
to stay to the very end sometimes I could almost believe the truth is strange and the fiction
well it is isn't it women papa no not really we writers are not better
all right more play what a very good idea women papa I think you're as good with plays as you
are with memoirs are you too right I'll start on the sequel as soon as we're all back home
there it is I lovely home at least I got a proper wash I've never seen it so clean what about
oh redecorated probably yeah let's go the movement family spent the whole of the following week
making their house cozy and comfortable and soon each carpet each cup and saucer and every
piece of furniture was back in its proper place once again
caring and giving the movements they're always happy and goes at play the
moments are having fun day after day the move is the move is