Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you are your TV, there are the movements, there are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements.
La-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la
Snort Maiden is running as if the groke is chasing her. I don't think I've ever seen her run so fast. I wonder what's the matter? Perhaps something terrible has happened.
Now come down and tell us what's wrong. My brother's on the cliff and then he's about to jump off. What snort? Are you sure? He says nothing will prevent him doing it. Oh, police, you must stop him, moment. Did you say that you wanted me to help you with something snort Maiden? Yes, I want you to stop snort jumping off the cell side of the cliff. Oh dear, I never thought he was the type. He says it's a test flight.
Oh. Now what? A test flight, did you say? Snort Maiden, do you mean that he's finally finished building his flying ship? No, only the blueprint. At least I think that's all. He doesn't tell me. Well, that's a start. He built a small model of the flying ship's wings and they don't look strong enough to carry anyone. And now he's going to try them out himself to see if they'll work. And I know they won't. They'll break, you know. Now wait a minute, Snort Maiden. Slow down and let me think.
He's made the wings from the blueprint of the flying ship. Well, his plans are always very accurate. Oh, Papa, you've got to stop him. The cell side, Papa. Yes, I know the highest and steepest one of all. Oh, moment, Papa, there must be something we can do. Yes, I'm sure there is. Right. Hurry, everybody. There's no time to lose. Come on. Oh, thank you, moment, Papa.
…No! Go!
A snork? Wait! Wait! Please! Stop snork, don't do it! Why have you brought everybody
here, snork maiden? They've come to beg you not to do it. You're too young and brilliant
for such a tragic end. Thank the bubble we were in time. As a matter of fact, you weren't.
Oh, really? It looks very dangerous to me, snork. Well, it's not at all moving, Papa. I made these wings
myself. They're perfectly balanced. Well, yes, I'm sure they are. The blueprints are detailed and precise. They're quite safe.
Tell me, snork. Why did you stop on the edge like that after running down the slope?
I was measuring the right length from my approach run. Don't do it, snork. I don't want to lose my only brother.
Don't make such a fuss, snork maiden. Do you really think it's safe? Of course it is. You don't see birds falling out of the sky, do you?
Well, at least do your test flight just above the ground so that if something happens to go wrong, you'll hurt yourself.
I've already done that from the roof of our house and it worked beautifully. Did you see him? No, I didn't see anything.
Of course you didn't. Do you think I let a wimpy little sister watch me? What's that supposed to mean, snork?
Just that I don't want you sticking your big nose into my affairs all the time. I don't like it, and there's nothing to do with you.
Yours is just as big and I don't want to lose you. Don't go on about losing me. Why not?
Come on now, you two. Stop it.
Hey! Oops! That was close. Snork maiden, I don't think your brother is going to be stopped.
Oh dear, oh dear. You're very brave, snork.
Hmm, right. Here we go. This time it'll be a perfect takeoff.
It's a long way. Oh look, isn't that snuffkin down there?
Where? Where is he? Where is snuffkin?
You can't see him from there, Sniff. You'll have to come here.
Is it really snuffkin? Yes, I'm sure it is. Snuffkin!
Yeah! Baby, here you...
No, I don't think so.
All right, here goes! Good luck, snork!
All right.
He's flying!
It's the snork!
Look at him flying.
It's all right, snork maiden. Your brother's doing fine. Come and see.
He's done it! He's done it!
Wow, I know he could do it. Well, so did I, to be honest.
Huh? Yeah, snork!
Hello!
Hi! How are you doing?
It's great that this test flight is a great success.
Okay, just as I thought he can't fly and wave at the same time.
Interesting. That was mean, stinky.
If I could get him to wave with both arms, you'd probably fall.
Look, we don't want you here, stinky. Why don't you just go away?
I can find lots to do with that machine.
If you won't go away, I will.
Well, go on then, Snuffkin. What do I care what you do?
Hmm, that would be perfect for robberies.
The wind seems to be taking him out to sea.
Why doesn't he turn around and come back?
Turning in that thing might not be so easy.
What? Do you mean he can't?
Well, don't worry, snork maiden. Of course he can.
Oh, what's this I can't turn on!
Oh!
Oh, he's hit a tree.
Come on, hurry!
Oh!
Is he dead?
No, he's been knocked out.
He looks dead to me anyway. Where are they? What's happened to the wings?
In the tree.
Ah, he won't want them anymore, so now I can have them.
Now, let me see.
So, did the test flight go all right?
Will someone tell me what happened?
Well, it was fine until the very end.
I'm sure that you only need a bit more practice.
Flying isn't the easiest thing to master, you know.
I expect so. Let's hope you don't run out of bandages, though.
Excuse me, snork.
Hmm?
Are you going to use the wings anymore?
I might not. Why?
Oh, well, I'll have them if you don't want them.
I want to fly in the sky, too.
It looks the most exciting thing I've ever seen.
Oh, please let me have them.
Well, it's not as simple as that moment.
They need testing before the design is done.
They need testing before the design is complete.
But I could do that snork. I know I could do it. Please let me have them.
Well, I suppose I could do with some help.
There's a lot to do, fetching and carrying mostly.
You haven't said if I can have the wings or not yet, snork.
Yes, you can, but on one condition.
Anything.
Well, now the blueprints are finished and the wings are more or less right.
I'll need somewhere to build the ship and somewhere to store all the materials so they'll be dry and at hand.
Yes, you will snork. I can see that.
It doesn't have to be much, just a roof will do or and walls.
So that people can't spy on me and steal my ideas.
I can do the building myself, but I'll need some help and when it's finished, you can have the wings.
Great. I'd love to help you. I'd have done that anyway, but now that I can have the wings, I'll work twice as hard.
You won't regret it, snork. I promise you you won't.
Splendid, woman. That settled them.
Perhaps we can get more help. I'm sure that'll be easy. How about it, snuffkin?
Yes, of course.
Will you help us do sniff?
Yes, but I want something too.
I'll let you borrow the wings.
No, I'm far too heavy. I only break them.
Don't worry, sniff. I'm sure I'll think of something you can have.
Oh, as long as it's something nice. Oh, I do love helping people.
You're all heart-sniff. We know that for sure.
I'm sure you'll need some expert help with the shed, snork.
Surely this must be deep enough, Papa?
Oh, no. Lee Moment's always built for posterity. Besides, I like pouring cement.
Okay, Papa.
I've given your present a lot of fortune, all.
Huh?
And I think I'll give you one of my invaluable books on machinery.
Oh? Don't you want it?
Well, if there was something else, I'm not much of a reader.
What about my invaluable fountain pen?
Invaluable fountain pen?
What about my invaluable...
Do you have anything that's not invaluable, snork?
Well, what about a gold coin?
Well, that sounds great. A real gold coin?
Oh, boy, yes, that's a deal.
You are digging a very deep hole.
Oh, why don't you stop and have some sandwiches?
Should we do that, Papa? Go on.
Yes, I think we can stop now.
Sniff and your brother are in the woods.
Yes, I know. I heard them.
Hi, snork maiden.
Oh, no.
Wait a minute. I want to ask you something.
What is it?
Tell me, snork maiden, is it true that your brother gave those wings to a woman?
Yes, it is. He's helping snork to build the shed his payment.
I thought they'd been broken up. They hit that tree very hard.
Well, my brother's repairing them.
Will you let me pass? I've got to take his lunch to him.
And will he be able to repair them?
He can repair anything.
Mmm.
Gosh, what a lot of wood you've got.
Well, the shed has to be a lot bigger than my flying ship.
Moving and moving Papa are digging holes. They sure are deep.
Everybody's being very kind, very kind indeed.
Mama's cooking and Snuffkin's gone to get nails.
There are some other things I need him to get as well.
Will you write them down?
Of course I will, snork. Oh, you're such a planner.
Well, I'm afraid all famous inventors have to be.
Whether it was Snork's planning or the fact that everyone in Moomin Valley helped in some way or other,
the hangar or boat house was finished in record time.
I'm going to take a look.
Here.
Moomin's here.
Come in, Moomin!
Thank you for all your help.
You did so much that these wings are hardly paymented enough.
But if you're happy with them,
Oh no, it was great fun building the shed.
I changed the design a bit, so it's easier to take off and land,
and turning shouldn't be a problem anymore.
You must remember to give yourself plenty of time though, woman.
Thank you, Snork. I can't wait to try them out.
I'm so excited. I don't think I'll sleep tonight.
Are you trying them out tomorrow?
As soon as I can. You will be careful.
You must practice a lot just above the ground to get used to wearing them
before you try to go too high.
I don't want anything to happen to you.
Well, practice, I promise.
Where are you going to practice tomorrow?
I haven't decided.
I'll find somewhere when I come out tomorrow,
perhaps on that small hill near the cliff.
But that can't be too dangerous.
I'll see you there.
Hey!
Hi, Moments! Where have you put the wings?
On the table outside.
You must have gone past them if you came in through the veranda door.
No, I didn't. They're not there.
What?
Oh no, you're right. They're gone.
Oh dear, I thought it was my friend.
What's happened to them?
Somebody stole them.
What's the matter with you, too? Is something wrong?
Yes, somebody stole and Moments wings.
Well, perhaps they haven't been stolen.
Of course they have, and I bet I know who did it, too.
Come on!
Where are we going? Do you know where they are?
It's stinky.
Oh, yeah. Well, it certainly didn't take you long.
Just a minute, stinky. Those are my wings.
See? I knew it was him.
Stop! You horrible creature!
I certainly will back.
If you give them back, stinky.
I'll let you try them out later.
I promise.
No way, boom, in their mind now.
I'm going to be a high-flier.
Look out, moving!
Oh, stop!
There we go!
You're pathetic.
The wings are mine.
I'll become a master criminal now.
All rotten seabing.
You shouldn't have left them outside, Moments.
Yeah, but who'd think let each steal them?
Where his friends? Well, almost.
I didn't think even stinky would do something like that.
Well, he did, didn't he?
Now, don't worry, Moments.
We'll find him and get them back. I know it.
Look, Moments. Now he's going towards the sea.
Oh, no, turn around.
But stinky didn't know how to maneuver the wings.
It was taken further and further out.
Turn around, we'll get turned back.
Until?
Oh!
You're at least he's having a bath for once.
The wings will be badly damaged.
Never mind. Snark will build another pair.
I sure hope so.
Oh!
They love the laughter and they love the living, the moments.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the moments.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the moments.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the moments.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.