Here they are for one and all. The movements are about to come. Come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you are your TV. They are the movements. They are the movements.
So come with me. Give me your hand. I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird. Sing that song ever. There were the movements.
There were the movements. There were the movements. There were the movements.
There were the movements. There were the movements.
For a whole week, snorkemaiden had been curled up on the sofa, reading fairy tales.
It's a lovely day and at last, movement is persuaded to come out for a walk in the lonely mountains.
Oh, it's beautiful up here. Aren't you glad you came now? This is much better than fairy tales, isn't it snorkemaiden?
Oh, look, movement. It's Adelvice. No, it isn't. That doesn't grow here at all.
I'm sure it is. I know what it looks like. I'm sorry, but it's not.
Oh, it's just like in Heidi. No, it's not. It's just a daisy. Oh, come on. I want to pick it.
Oh, no, it's too dangerous. I know then. You can do it. You're my boyfriend, aren't you, movement?
Well, I suppose we could climb down there, but I promise you it's not Adelvice. That only grows in the Alps and there are hundreds of miles away.
I know it's Adelvice. Be careful. They don't care about danger in fairy tales. That's why they call them fairy tales, silly.
Fairy Princess, please accept this, my humble offering.
Thank you, Brave Knight. You are right, movement. This isn't Adelvice. See, I told you...
It's gonna be hard to get down from here, you know? Can't we go back the way we came?
Well, I think it'll be easier to try to get to that path. If you say so...
It's nearer anyway, and better than going up. I'm surprised you're such a good climber.
Oh, Royalty is good at practically everything.
It's not made of. It's not made of.
It's not made of.
Let me see six petals. What was that, a giant snowball? It can't be, it isn't winter.
Well, nothing of interest to me. Now, where was I?
We start hemulating. Has Snorkmaiden just gone past you?
Snorkmaiden, no, I've seen going past. It's a very large snowball.
That was Snorkmaiden.
But she's not made of snow?
Stop! Snorkmaiden, stop!
Snorkmaiden, snorkmaiden!
Oh, I'll praise the boobah. She's still breathing. She's just knocked herself out.
Oh, Mum and what's happened to her?
She's unconscious.
What are you trying to do?
I want to get her home to Mama.
Oh, difficult. She should lose a bit of weight.
Perhaps she'd come around if we splashed cold water on her face.
Oh, there's nothing to fetch it in.
Ah, if you cut some bark off a tree trunk, you could make a small container.
What a good idea. If you stay here, I'll go and do that.
Wake up, Snorkmaiden.
Oh, that's cold.
Has she come around yet, Mr. Hemulet?
No.
Okay.
Oh, good. It's working.
How are you feeling, Snorkmaiden?
Are you all right, Snorkmaiden?
Oh, where am I?
We're still up in Lonely Mountains.
Who am I?
Why Royal Highness the Princess of Lonely Mountains?
What? A Princess?
Oh, yes, of course.
And who are you?
I am the Prince of Lonely Mountains.
Oh, yeah.
With that ridiculous shape?
No, a gesture, perhaps.
You want?
You there. Do not laugh.
I think the poor girl must have lost her memory.
Of course not. She's just pretending.
When does not whisper with royalty present, do you hear?
So sorry, Royal Highness.
A poor crafters cabin.
This is your castle, ma'am.
Royalty doesn't live in shacks.
Snorkmaiden, stop calling us that.
It's very rude.
Oh, forgive me.
A royal castle is elsewhere.
Is it not?
What?
That must be hunting lodge.
No, of course, that's what it is.
Good, we accept that.
Are you two going to tell me what you're so busy looking at?
Send a maid to my room, my good man.
A maid?
My good man.
Papa, have you seen Snorkmaiden?
Yes, up there.
Mama, please would you go on have a word with Snorkmaiden?
Have you been quarreling?
Oh, no.
It's just that she fell and banged her head.
And now she thinks she's a royal princess.
What?
Ah, Nanette, come here, please.
Nanette?
I'm Boomin, Mama.
Oh, we're too weary for your foolish jokes, girl.
Oh, we are very tired indeed, Nanette.
Please bring our silk nighty with the hand embroidered swans and clowns.
Then you may go.
I wish you, Mama.
All right, I'm sure.
But she seems convinced she's a princess.
Sounds as if it's dangerous, doesn't it, Mama?
Oh, I don't think so.
I was only joking when I called her a princess.
I'm very glad you didn't call her an opera singer.
Is Snorkmaiden asleep now?
Oh, yes, in a night gown with crowns and swans embroidered on it.
And another thing, Boomin, she wants a canopy put up immediately.
What's that?
Oh, a fancy cover over the bed that's draped in silks, envelopes, and tassels.
Oh, she was very upset because there wasn't one there already.
It might be necessary.
Her memory could have come back by the time she wakes up.
Why don't we wait and see?
She might be fine after a rest.
I sure hope so.
But what do we do if it hasn't come back?
Let's think about that if it happens.
We might not have to build that canopy.
Let me try it.
Try what?
To get Snorkmaiden's memory back, what else?
Oh, how?
Well, I think that if she sees me, she'll remember me
and then she'll remember everything else too.
Don't be silly little Mai.
If she doesn't remember me, why should you remember you, eh?
Simple, because I'm unforgettable.
There is that, I suppose.
She's still fast asleep.
Well, I'm glad we made the canopy anyway.
It looks really great, doesn't it?
Oh, oh, look.
She's opening her eyes.
Are you awake?
Get up, Snorkmaiden.
Come on.
Let's go down to the beach.
And who is that person?
Come on.
You remember me.
I warn you if you know you'll be sorry.
Oh, quite amusing.
Ah, so you remember me now.
Of course we do.
There you are, I told you.
Who am I then?
Well, you're another court jester.
Of course.
Ah, don't be little Mai.
A court jester.
Oh, very funny.
She's a better clown than the other one.
You can perform it our wedding.
You are a wedding.
I'm stinky.
What are you doing here?
Moment asked me to come over to Moment House and propose to some princess.
Moments lost his marbles as well then.
I think he wanted stinky as a contrast.
You what?
You mean to tell me you're both my rivals for the hands of the royal princess?
Well, it's not very original.
But in order to win the princess and have her kingdom stinky, you'll need to saw three riddles.
Hey, that's great! What's this kingdom like?
All right, sooner number one, you may now enter.
Oh, that's me.
Oh, hi, princess. How are you doing?
Jester, is this man a suitor?
He is.
I fear he does not treat us with respect.
Forgive him, your highness.
He is from a foreign land and does not know the ways of your kingdom.
Well, all right, very well.
Here is the first riddle. Are you ready?
Fire away!
Now then, listen, what is it that is yellow, has four legs and sings?
Oh, dear. And unusual, canary?
With four legs, you nincomboop.
I don't know any birds with four legs, but I do.
I don't know.
With four legs, you nincomboop.
I don't know any birds with four legs.
Who said it was a bird?
All right, then, what's the answer, snark baby?
He shows no respect.
Throw him into a dungeon and give him no food.
Your highness, he is temporarily out of his mind after the long journey here.
Hang on, I'm not out of my mind.
How do I pee?
How for what's the answer? That's what I want to know.
Silence, it does not concern you.
We believe you to be of lowly birth.
Sorry about this, napkin.
Don't worry.
Hmm, no, sir Gellad, but not bad.
I am honored to be here, your royal highness.
He'll do.
An easy riddle to start.
Here it is.
First, what is the number of which we think?
Take your time.
Two.
For a faux-gallant night, that is correct.
Now listen, what is the word upon our mind?
Love.
That's amazing.
Truly, the suitor has brains as well as looks.
Question three.
There are two numbers on our mind.
What do they add up to?
Answer carefully for it.
Could unlock your princess's heart.
21.
Oh, was that right, too?
Oh no, it was 22.
My heart is heavy.
For chance we should have said it was correct.
He was rather cute.
Was he not just her?
It's your turn now, stinky.
Well, I suppose that even half of Snortiles would be something.
Think she'll ever get her memory back?
Of course she will.
This is not our idea of a suitor.
His heart is aching for you, your royal highness.
Ah, let it ache.
Oh, all right.
I'll give him a chance.
Here is a question number one.
What is the number we are thinking of?
Well of all our stupid questions.
We haven't all day.
Oh, well of...
Four.
Indeed not.
It is 3,598,765.
Begone out.
Hey, Snortiles, that's up there.
It's not fair right there, ma'am.
Go home.
Give me another one I want after.
Oh, what a rude suitor.
We are no longer in the mood for royal marriage, Jester.
At least not today.
A wise decision.
A princess of the lonely mountains.
They will be prostrate with grief,
but bid the other suitors to go home.
Do not let them beg.
We would not like that.
Very well, your royal highness.
Do it kindly.
We wish them no pain at all.
From this day on, we shall devote ourselves to good works
and to the well-being of our people.
Oh.
You, I didn't want to marry you anyway.
Wonder what Snort maintenance up to now?
Upstairs thinking.
She says she'll devote her life to good works.
Works, what works?
I don't know, but she probably wants to be remembered
in the history books.
The princess who was adored by her subjects.
Oh, she's coming down.
Your royal highness, may I assist you?
Send the net to us.
She is on an errand, your highness.
Then have someone else make soup,
nourishing but not too rich.
Soup, highness?
Yes indeed.
And then we shall take it to our poor subjects ourselves.
What kind of soup?
We don't know.
We eat. We don't cook.
The poor will be happy with anything
brought by the princess herself.
Now hurry man, be quick about it.
Now she wants some soup.
This will be ample.
The poor do not eat much.
It would only make the meal.
I don't know anyone poor around here, your majesty.
Nonsense.
Do what, do what.
Greetings jester.
What now?
We're taking soup to the poor.
Made with our own regal fingers.
Do you know where they are jester?
Your fingers?
Oh, I know.
Good, wonderful.
Take us to them now.
They will be so grateful.
You back princess.
That house there.
Oh yes.
It's nice to know that the poor and my kingdom are so well off.
Oh you, please come over here.
Hmm?
Who are you?
I'm the princess of Lonely Mountain.
Princess?
Oh!
What moment you're all highness?
Do not keep us waiting.
We have a lot to do.
I'm coming.
Forgive me you're all highness.
I had no idea you were.
My mind smart maiden.
That common name again, we are princess.
Little sticks.
You're not right in the head coming here bothering your elders
and betters like this.
Others?
Oh!
Are you the queen men?
Hmm?
I am Mrs. Philly jog.
Now what do you want?
You're just fulfilling our royal duty bringing soup to the poor.
Giving cheer to those less fortunate that ourselves.
Here my good woman.
Now if you just pour.
Oh, there you call me poor.
You who doesn't have a stitch of clothing to your name.
Oh, the rich aroma of the soup must have overcome you Mrs. Philly jog.
Ah!
Eat it yourself your majesty.
Oh!
This is how I treason.
Send for the guard.
Take her to the tower.
Oh!
We cannot see.
I'm afraid that serves you right, Snork maiden.
Snork maiden!
Don't use that common name.
Help us.
We cannot see.
Please don't steal.
Your royal highness.
Oh, hold a moment.
Oh, oh, oh.
I think it's stuck moment.
Use the hand.
Ah!
Stop!
You heard it right.
I'll get it on.
Out of the way.
Ah, wait a minute.
You can't break that soup, Turin.
It's a family heirloom.
And you mustn't hit Snork maiden on the head.
You might hurt her.
Stop fooling around and get this thing off, will you?
All right.
Oh, poor smart maiden.
You didn't have to get up that hard.
Difficult to judge it with a broom.
I've never hit anyone wearing a soup, Turin, before.
Oh, you will write your royal highness.
Oh, forgive us, your royal highness.
Sprinkle some cold water over her face.
No, she'd hate that, mama.
Snork maiden.
Ah, it's no good, woman.
I don't think she'll wake up today.
I'm going to be late.
Oh, good, woman.
I don't think she'll wake up to anything, but your royal highness.
Your highness.
Hang on.
Snork maiden.
Oh, I'm so glad your royal highness is with us again.
I hope your royal highness is not badly hurt.
Where am I?
In moment, Valley, of course, stupid.
Where do you think?
That's weird.
I thought, woman, and I had gone for a walk in the lonely mountains.
Didn't we, woman?
Huh?
Do you remember who I am, Snork maiden?
Woman, what are you talking about?
Of course I do.
And you don't think you're a princess anymore?
Princess?
Have you gone crazy or something?
What princess?
What do you mean, woman?
Hooray!
She's back to normal.
Snork maiden's back to normal.
Yes, it's nice to have you back again.
Yes, it's wonderful.
Welcome home.
What is?
What's wonderful?
Have you all gone loopy or something?
Never mind, Snork maiden.
You bumped your head, that's all.
And so Snork maiden's brief spell as a royal princess came to an end.
Except that she was the only one who didn't remember it.
But everyone else in woman valley breathed a sigh of relief.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.