here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the movements they are the movements so come with me give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just like a bird sing that song ever there with the
movements there was a movement there was a movement there was a movement
Ba ba Ba Ba Ba Ba Ba Ba threat
With all the planets in outer space, there must be other forms of life different
that on earth. We don't know what they look like because no one from here has ever seen them.
However, we do know that they don't look like this because this is sniffed one of
women's friends.
So, it looks as though the rumor was right.
What rumor was that?
That we were about to be invaded by aliens from outer space.
Oh, dear, do you mean that thing that was chasing me might have been one of them?
Well, yes.
I thought they were just after me.
I wouldn't have thought you'd have been that important to them sniff,
but I suppose you never know, knew you.
It says here in this book that aliens from outer space are very civilized and peace-loving and would never want to invade us.
It seemed as though they're quite happy where they are.
I do, it's not a very scientific book.
Well, it was definitely attacking me, Mom and Papa, I know it was.
Well, it might have been a civilization from another planet sniff.
They were just hungry.
Huh? Well, the inspector told me that he thought we were being invaded by aliens, and he shouldn't know.
I'm sure he's exaggerating.
I wonder what they look like.
Why don't you come and help me in the garden?
You never know, we might see one.
Mama, wait for me!
Mama, what's that?
Well, I would say it's not a vegetable, that's for sure.
It looks like a flying saucer.
I wonder if there are any aliens in it.
They might be heard, Mama.
Let's have a look.
I think there's something there.
This looks odd. I wonder what it is.
It's a bit like a radio, isn't it?
Oh yeah, an alien radio.
Do you think there's anyone in there moving?
Anybody there?
It seems to have been deserted.
There's a funny noise coming from it.
Well, it doesn't look to me like it could fly again.
It could be repaired.
You'd need to know about flying saucers.
Papa could do it?
I don't think flying saucers should make that sort of noise.
Do you, woman?
I don't think so.
But I don't know very much about them.
It does seem a bit odd.
As if they've said it to be blown up so that no one would be able to steal it.
Because they want to keep the design a secret.
Do you think it will?
Oh!
I'm not sure, Mama.
But let's get away in case it does explode.
That's why it's empty.
It landed in the Asparagus patch.
I'll take the radio with me.
It won't be too long now, Mama.
No, it won't.
It won't be long.
It's vanished.
Less my soul.
Papa's book said they could be a very advanced life form.
There's nothing to show.
It was ever here.
Except the hole in the ground.
And this radio thing.
Hmm.
Is it a radio, Papa?
I don't know.
It looks a bit like one.
Let's try pressing one of these buttons.
The red one first, I think.
Oh!
Papa, where have you gone?
I'm right here.
I wonder what happens if I press this one.
Well, I'm sorry, but I'm afraid I can't see you either, dear.
What?
Oh, I see.
So if you press the red button, you become invisible.
What a fascinating machine.
Papa, I think I'd rather see you, dear.
Well, of course you would.
Well, let's try the yellow one.
Can you see me now?
No, Papa.
Oh, that's hard.
Do you want me to try, Papa?
Please, Mama.
Oh, Papa.
That's a very dangerous machine.
I don't want to disappear ever again.
It's not a nice experience.
No, dear. I didn't like you vanishing like that.
Well, we must put it somewhere safe, Mama,
where the children can't find it.
Yes, dear.
Oh, Papa.
That's a very dangerous machine.
I don't want to disappear ever again.
It's not a nice experience.
No, dear. I didn't like you vanishing like that.
Even forgotten.
Mumon.
Snortmaiden, what an earth's the matter.
We found a strange creature.
Strange creature.
I think it's an alien.
Does it look like a jellyfish?
No, not at all.
Little mice keeping an eye on it.
C'mon!
Where are you going, Mumon, Papa?
Going me out.
What do you mean?
Moving, Mum and Papa.
Going me? Oh, no, Especial.
Moving, Mum, I'll hang on.
I've got a few questions for you.
Really, Inspector?
I was told that a flying saucer
had landed in your garden,
but all I can see is a big hole.
Where is it?
What have you done with the saucer?
Nothing.
Well, where is it?
It's not there now.
It was there, but then it just vanished.
Darnished?
Yes, that's right.
When you say vanished, you mean it flew away again?
No, it just went, woof, gone.
Moments are it, too.
That's very odd.
Yes, it was.
Did you see any aliens on board by any chance?
No.
Are you telling me the truth?
Of course.
Why should I lie to you?
Well, I can't.
Think of any reason.
I'm sorry, but it's upsetting aliens
invading Moment Valley.
Yes, it is.
Can we go now?
Certainly.
Where are you all going, by the way?
Oh, only to the beach to collect shells.
See you, Inspector.
Collecting shells, indeed, while I'm hunting for aliens.
Ah, over here!
Ah, Mom!
Hey.
Oh, Aunt Lady, where are you now?
Where are you now?
Is that an alien?
It certainly is, but not like it says in the book.
Have you tried talking to it?
Yes, but it wouldn't answer.
Let me try.
Are you from outer space?
G-so, what aå•.
Why are you acting like a dacha-dacha-dacha-dali?
No-din.
Yes, it's not going to happen to me a little bit.
Looks like an alien child to me more like a lamp poor thing. He must be hungry. Let's take him home
Yeah, well, we don't want the inspector to see him
I'm sorry we can't understand you, but I'm sure you'll like me up even if you don't speak English
Just try it and see
I think he's missing his home
Wherever in the universe that might be I wonder where his parents are he can't have come on his own
He seems far too little for that
Well, I don't know
But he's obviously missing them and he seems very unhappy
Do you think the inspector would really arrest him moving papa?
Possibly, he would think it is duty
Well, that would be horrible of him
I know
Oh, it's inspector
Oh dear, he mustn't find him here
And he's got stinky with him
Oh, stinky? Well, that means trouble
Quick, he can hide in the kitchen
We gotta do something!
And quickly
I know what to do
What mama? We'll use the machine
Oh yeah
We'll just keep him out of sight
Now with him, this one is right
Oh dear
I think they're here
Oh, moving papa, I heard there was an alien here with what?
What's happening?
What's happened to me?
Oh dear, yes, how very, very strange
You look like a great big goldworm
An inspector in shining armor, you mean little my?
That's just what I thought
You'll never need a lamp to be seen, inspector
I like it, criminals will be afraid of me
I can't wait to get back to the station and show the constables
Handy for reading in bed, too
Well, duty calls, bye
D-D-D-D-D- im-d-D-D-D-D-D D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D-D
What are you doing?
I didn't know that the machine was still working
Or you can speak English
Of course I can
It's just that I need my language converted to help me translate
And if you hadn't taken it from my ship and hidden it
I would have been able to talk sooner
That's a good way to learn, isn't it?
Where are you going?
To see that nice, shiny man
But he'll arrest you!
He came here looking for you, but he forgot about it when the machine started him glowing
No, don't go there. Hey, why?
What is it?
What?
Oh, you're so bright and beautiful, Inspector.
Oh, you think so?
Everyone shimmers like that, everyone.
Well, that must be very nice for them.
I want to pose you, please.
I'm sorry, I'm too busy, but it was nice talking to you.
You see, the aliens have invaded Moomin Valley and I must find them.
Oh, I just remembered.
I was tipped off that there was one of them in Moomin House.
The inspector's coming back.
What about the alien?
He's running after him.
Has he been handcuffed, Moomin?
I don't think so.
Open up in the name of the law, Moomin Papa.
Well, certainly for you, Inspector. Come on in. You're very welcome.
Moomin Papa, I have information from a reliable source, well, sort of reliable.
That you have been harping a fugitive.
I'm sorry.
In other words, I believe you have been hiding an alien here.
Oh, Inspector, I don't think hiding is the right word. That suggests we are trying to keep something from you.
Well, Mama.
Would we do that, Inspector?
That stinky is tricked me again.
Isn't it lucky he didn't find you?
I want a nice inspector.
Look, how many times must I tell you? He'll lock you up in an nasty cell.
I like him. I want to see him.
No, don't.
Perhaps if we press the yellow button, he'll stop shining.
A good idea, Papa. Be quick, Mama.
The yellow button.
You girls.
You don't want him now that he stopped shining. Do you, little fella?
No.
Let's go home, then.
Well, Mama, come and look. We've saved the alien.
Well, Mama, the inspector's not glowing anymore. Isn't that something?
Mama?
Mama, where are you?
I'm here.
Hey, what? Where are you, Mama?
Well, Mama.
Right here.
Mama? Oh, no. What's happened to you?
I don't know. Probably that machine again.
Oh, so it shrinks you as well as making you invisible, does it? Well, well.
Oh, dear. I need an apron.
Papa, can you get a handkerchief from my handbag?
You really are quite small.
That you look very cute, of course, Mama.
Would you like to stay like that for a while?
No, I would not. Push another button quickly before anyone sees me.
Go on now. Hurry up, Papa.
Yeah. Oh, dear.
What's up?
The machine's gone.
Hey, you! Take me back!
Hey!
Papa!
Don't worry, Mama. I'll get it back.
Hey!
Oh, thank you.
Look at that way.
Stop him, Mama. Stop him. He stole the machine.
We'll get him, Papa.
Hey, sniff!
Don't let steam keep getting away.
Right.
Leave it to me.
Please let me pass, sniff. I'll give you a gold stopper.
A gold stopper?
I mean, free. No, no. Five.
No. Give me the machine, Stinky.
Where is it, moment? What's happened to the machine?
It's at the bottom of the river, Papa.
Oh, poor Mama. Poor Mama.
What's wrong with her?
Well, she needs the machine to get back to normal.
Normal?
Well, at least this is a chance to do some really fine embroidery.
Don't worry, Mama. I promise we'll look after you.
It's all right, Moomin. I'll manage.
I'll have to get some smaller pots and pans, though,
and we'll have to have smaller helpings.
But that might not be a bad idea.
Oh.
Here, here, my parents come for me.
Mama, Papa.
It's like the one we saw in the garden.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
My parents were still thank you for looking after me.
They're telling you off, aren't they?
Yes, because I took a flying saucer.
You ask your parents to make Mama a normal size again.
Yes, of course.
Fiddle grassy, grassy girl.
Oh, well, that's more like it.
Oh, no. Oh, dear.
Oh, no. Stop. It's too much.
Oh, well, I'm sorry.
But could you try again, please?
I know.
The more of Mama there is a better one.
She's getting very large.
Very large indeed.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, oh, oh.
So, Mum and Valley hadn't really been invaded at all.
And the movements and the friends that found out where aliens really looked like.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.