Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come.
Come on and sit down here with me, they're for you on your TV, they are the movements,
they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever, there were the movements, there were
the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements.
Fall has come to movement valley and the memory of sunshine filled ours fades as the days
become shorter and the nights longer.
The wind blows away the falling leaves and the blue skies of summer are now grey and
cloudy, winter is just around the corner.
Snork maiden!
Where are you going?
Oh I'm just taking my brother, his lunch little my, he must have nearly finished the flying
ship by now.
Oh no, not even snork works that quickly.
Well have you seen it?
No I haven't, he won't even let me come into his workshop.
Is he afraid it'll disappear if someone sees it?
He hasn't said why but I suppose all great inventors have to be very careful, someone
might want to steal their ideas.
The woman told me he's dying to have a look at it.
Hey woman, open the door, I've got my hands full, come on quickly.
Look what I've got, it's a regular player.
Oh.
Do you think you can get it working dear?
Oh yes of course mom.
Why do people always give me things that are broken, it'd be nice to have something that
worked for a change.
Movement probably will get it working for you.
My auntie said that the record was alright though it stands music, she's had it for ages
but I've never heard it.
Oh that's nice, it's years since I danced but it seems like only yesterday.
Do you remember what fun it was Papa?
Dancing.
Oh yeah, I see.
Have you fixed it Papa?
Huh?
I can hear music.
Doesn't sound like snuffkin.
Right, have you got the idea now?
Yes I think so.
Me too.
Come on, let's see you then.
What?
Did I do it?
Oh wow.
Look at Papa woman, he's a great dancer.
Well then, can you dance snuff?
I've never tried.
Right, well try now.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Yep.
Hi, yeah.
Hi, hi.
Hey, hey.
Hi, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Oh that was fun.
Oh, dancing never used to wear me out like this.
You've got no sense of rhythm at all, Snuff.
It's still dance though, can't I?
Oh, are you ready, Papa?
I think I'll have to sit this one out, Mama.
All right.
You all right?
No, thank you.
I'll dance on my own.
Well then, why don't you dance with me and dance, Smith?
Ah.
Hmm.
Oh.
Oh, it looks like it's here for the day.
Oh, what horrible weather, snuffkin.
Yes.
They're having fun.
Well, Smith brought this old record player over and we've been dancing.
I haven't done it for years and years.
Well, aren't you coming in?
I can smell winter in the air, Moomin, Papa.
Huh?
Oh, yes.
Yeah, all right.
Snuffkin, why?
Snuffkin, come and dance with me.
No, thanks.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
Oh, you.
Hmm, what's the matter with this?
I'm afraid it's broken.
Just when we were having so much fun.
Will you be able to fix it again, dear?
No, even I can't mend it now.
Oh, please, try, Papa.
Will you?
Hmm, snuffkin, do you know anything about record players?
No, I'm afraid not.
Oh, dear.
But what?
I'll play my harmonic if you want to continue to dance.
And then you can fiddle around with the machine.
How would that be?
Oh, yes, please.
That'd be great, snuffkin.
Thanks.
Now then, what would be a good tune to dance to?
Let's see.
Oh, no.
Now what's this?
I give up.
Me?
You're thinking about going away again, aren't you, Snuffkin?
Hmm.
I know that you go south every year when winter comes, but I'll still miss you, though,
and I wish you could stay here in Moomin Valley.
I know, Moomin.
Where are they?
How do you find them, I think?
I wonder where they're going.
I don't know.
A deserted island, I expect.
Probably the best place for them.
When are you leaving, Snuffkin?
Oh, I haven't decided yet.
So, you'll be here for a bit longer then.
Do you know where you're going?
No.
It must be fun traveling.
Yes, most of the time.
It's the best way of meeting new people and still being on your own.
I wish we could do that, but even when we hibernate and go to sleep, we're never really alone.
I guess I'd hibernate too if I had to stay up here in Moomin.
During all the freezing winter snows.
Do you think I could go south with Snuffkin, Papa?
Not really, it's the moment way to hibernate.
It's a family custom passed down through the years by our ancestors.
But Papa, I don't want to go to sleep for months on end.
I want to travel south with Snuffkin.
Oh, Moomin.
You promise you'll be back on the first day of spring.
Oh, Mama!
Does that mean I can really go?
I can't wait to tell Snuffkin.
I can, can't I?
Well, if you really want to, I don't suppose we'll stop you.
We'll be Papa.
Now, my parents didn't mind when I traveled around in my youth.
So, yes, all right, Moomin.
Oh, thank you, Papa.
Mama, thank you, Mama.
That's great, but what will Snuffkin say?
Well, it's a good idea.
And I got to say it'd be fun to have you a long Moomin.
So, I can come with you Snuffkin?
No.
What?
I'm sorry, but I've got to go on my own.
Don't be disappointed, Moomin.
I told you I travel alone.
I need to.
After spending the rest of the year here, just as I need to be here,
after spending the winter alone.
And the joy of returning to Moomin Valley is something I wouldn't miss.
Which Snuffkin, I thought.
The time will soon pass, and you'll be asleep through most of it.
You won't notice I'm not here.
I'll see you next spring, Moomin.
I'll be back on the first day as usual.
I promise, as soon as the weather warms.
And when the flowers start to grow, nothing will keep me from Moomin Valley.
Ah, I'm sorry I didn't work out for you, Moomin.
Oh, it's all right.
Oh, come on, Moomin.
You'll have to tie them a bit tighter than that.
It'll be a cold winter, so we'll need lots of wood
to keep us going till spring comes.
I know.
Now you want to stay warm, don't you?
When I grow up, I'll go south on my own, too.
Yes, of course you will.
Ah, ah, ah.
Is Moomin home?
Yes.
How is he?
Is he still down in the dumps?
I'm afraid so, grandma's cheer you up, recipe didn't work.
Ah, I think he's being silly just because Snuffkin's going away.
I suppose he is.
But don't worry, mama.
He won't be miserable much longer, because I've got a surprise for him.
Are you there, Moomin?
A moment, don't cry.
Boys don't cry, I suppose.
Of course they do.
Well, I'm not crying so, there.
All right, but I do think you should get up now.
Oh, and why should I?
I have a surprise for you.
I don't want any surprises.
Come on, I'm going to go and see Snuffkin his workshop.
But you know he won't let us in.
I've tried before.
Oh, yes, he will today.
I promise.
What?
You mean Snorkel shows his flying ship at last?
Yes, he said.
Has he really finished it then?
No, not yet.
There's still a lot of work to do on him.
Then I wonder why he's letting us see it.
He's always refused before.
What's made him change his mind?
But I asked him this time.
I said I wanted to show it to you.
It just needed a woman's touch.
What did you say to him?
First, he said absolutely not.
But when I told him how ill you were in that,
you probably wouldn't be with us much longer.
He gave in and said we could see it.
Just you and me have claimed not that it'll snorke maiden.
Oh, good.
Because sometimes some people are very depressed
and just lying bad.
They've done something bad.
Oh, stop it snorke maiden.
Don't say things like that.
I'm only trying to cheer you up.
So remember, don't tell us all.
No one else must know anything about it.
Okay.
Let's go.
No.
Oh, little Mai.
Little Mai.
Trouble.
Big Trouble.
We must fool her.
Yes, but how?
What can we do?
I know what we'll do.
What?
Quick, Moomin.
You just agree with everything I say snorke maiden.
Oh.
I thought you were in bad Moomin.
No, we're going to see snorke.
Yes.
Really?
Yes, he needs to clear a runway
for when the flying ship is finished.
We're going to help him do it.
That's all.
Yes.
Are you really, Moomin?
You got out of bad to do that.
I'm afraid I find it very strange that snorke is asked to go along
and help him cut down bushes and dig up roots and things.
You might have noticed I'm not a complete fool.
But it's true, little Mai.
Oh, yes.
Well, at least you could have invented a better lie.
You must think I'm pretty stupid to believe a pathetic story like that.
But it's the truth.
And we need your help.
Yeah.
Don't bother, don't bother.
I don't want to hear anymore.
I think it's very sad that you have to pretend.
You're trying to hide something from me
and I'm not interested in what sort of sneaky underhanded thing it is.
But little Mai.
No, but, and anyway, I'm a little too busy at the moment
to take any notice of what's going on.
Goodbye.
Come on.
Phew, that was close.
Yeah.
Ha, think, thank you.
Keep a secret from me, do they?
Are you alone?
Of course we are.
I promised, didn't I?
Come in, then.
Wow.
It's nearly ready, isn't it?
Oh, no, there's a lot more to do.
The machine isn't half finished yet.
And as you can see, there's a lot to do on the ship itself
but I'm getting there slowly.
I never thought it would be so fantastic, smork.
Well, I suppose you could say the design wasn't a complete failure.
I'm quite sure it'll fly beautifully.
Oh, thank you.
Do you really think it will, woman?
I can see it now.
High up in the air, dodging in and out of the clouds,
way up above the world.
Well, I'm glad to see that you're so perceptive and quite right.
Oh, how very thoughtful of me.
Shouldn't you sit down and rest?
Do you know your illness?
It doesn't help to get too excited.
Ha, I shouldn't worry, smork.
There's nothing wrong with him.
Oh, little my, how did you get in here?
Throw that door.
But I always keep it.
Oh, oh, oh, no.
I must have forgotten to lock it.
And it's a bit late to do it now, isn't it?
But don't worry.
If I wanted to get in, I'd get in locks or no locks.
Oh, you lied to us, little my.
Of course, but so did you.
Telling me that stupid story.
Now we're even, right?
Now, listen, little my.
Don't ever tell anybody what you see over here.
All right.
This invention contains so many outstanding new features
it is difficult to know where to begin.
But let me start with the most exciting part
of the whole construction.
It could go as a dream or rather the concept of a dream
thrilling, beautiful, impossible, dangerous.
Can you take the ship down, movement?
I'd like you to land at that side of the lake.
Oh, why do you want to get off?
Aren't you having fun flying about up here?
I want to be on my own.
Oh, please stay here.
I'll let you steer.
I'll be there.
Oh, please stay here.
I'll let you steer if you want.
No, really, movement, please.
Bye now.
No!
Snuff me!
Oh, oh, oh.
So long then, movement, my friend.
I'll see you again next year.
The first day of spring.
Bye!
Goodbye, then, Snuffkin.
Goodbye, then, Snuffkin!
Off for the winter, Asian Nafkin?
Yes, goodbye, Mr. Hemmielin.
We'll be seeing you in the spring.
Yes, when the snows are gone.
Oh, to be young and follow the sun wherever it goes.
And so the snow fell and winter came to Moomin Valley.
And in Moomin's heart, Snuffkin and the spring seemed a long, long way away.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They loved the laughter and they loved the living, the movements.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.