Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you on your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a movement land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing that song ever.
There were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements, there were the movements.
There were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements.
Woman Valley is enjoying another still peaceful summer's day.
However, this lazy lifestyle, no matter how pleasant it might be, does not suit everyone.
Oh, yes.
Would you like a cup of coffee, dear?
Yes, I think I need one, Mama.
Oh dear, is it your memoirs?
I'm stuck.
Ah, can I help?
How can I create in this?
In what?
In this sleepy atmosphere, and I've also come to a boring part.
When was that?
The time I wrote poems.
Were they any good?
No.
Well, miss that bit out then.
I can't.
I must put it down for posterity, it is my duty.
But how can I get inspiration here in this place where nothing ever happens, nothing ever happens at all?
Oh, I think this means another adventure.
Yes, Mama, but I need it to be big, exciting, and frightening.
Mama, what's the matter?
Are you all right?
Your father says that because nothing ever happens here, he can't write.
So I'm looking for an adventure for him.
Can you think of anything?
He wants it to be big, exciting, and frightening.
Does he want something really exciting?
Yes, dear, I'm afraid so.
I think I could manage that.
That looks like the footprint of a huge monster.
Oh, it's a good feeling giving others a bit of excitement.
Just a couple more.
I'm praise the booboo I don't have to do modest work very often.
Phew, that was harder than I thought.
Oi, sleepy heads.
Wake up, everybody!
Mom and Papa, quickly get up!
Mom and Mama, a monster!
You've been visited by a monster!
Wake up before you eat and alive!
Come on, hurry, hurry!
My, what huge tracks.
Ah, that should keep them guessing for a while.
Hmm, it could be a monster from the depths of the ocean.
Something's not right here.
Don't you think it's a bit odd that it came directly to Moome House?
Yeah.
Well, look at the footsteps. They go in a straight line.
Someone must have told it to go to Moome House.
And they're only going one way.
Look, there are tiny footsteps going back to the sea.
Oh, Mama, my monster must still be here then.
Oh, well, not necessarily.
Retracing one's own footsteps is the sign of an advanced intelligence.
Stepping back exactly the way you came.
The tough question is, why would the monster do that?
One is led to believe that it wants us to think it's still here.
Well, in fact, it has gone back to wherever it came from.
Fiddle battle, as my dear mother would say.
But why would it want us to think that, Papa?
It's a spy.
Oh, it's a spy.
Something it shouldn't.
It'd hardly be a good spy if we knew they have to sneak in and out.
I think it's still here. I can feel it. You know what I mean?
Perhaps tonight.
Tonight? What about tonight?
That's when they'll attack. It's gone back to give its report.
How do you know that, Papa?
Well, obviously, that's why it still wants us to believe it's here.
Mama, Mama!
Yes, what is it, Moome?
Something terrible is going to happen.
A monster is going to attack us tonight.
And Papa's excited about it.
Oh, good. That's nice for him.
Hurry, everyone.
I expect the monster will be here soon.
Now hold it still.
This is going to be a good barricade, don't you think?
We'd better make sure it's big enough.
It's hardly any fun at all playing tricks on them. They're so gullible.
If we catch the monster, we can sell it to a zoo.
I'll handle the sale, of course.
I'd rather tame it and keep it as a pet.
We could ride on it to go pig-nicking.
Alright, now for the moat. Here we go.
Hope the well's got enough water in it.
It'll be able to swim in this, Papa.
Yes, it'll remind you to the sea and keep it calm.
This is fresh water, Papa. We'd better put some salt in it.
Good idea, Moome.
We'll plant some seaweed and put some rocks in too,
and then it'll feel really at home.
I wonder when it'll come.
I don't know, but I can feel in my bones it'll be tonight.
And we keep watching till it comes?
Of course we will, constantly.
What if it doesn't come till tomorrow night or the night after that?
It might be a long wait, so we'll take it in turns and remember everybody.
The safe way is to keep it calm.
I don't know, but I can feel in my bones it'll be tonight.
And we keep watching till it comes?
We'll take it in turns and remember everybody.
The safety of Moome in Valley relies upon our vigilance.
We must be ready.
Look at what those fools have done.
It was worth all the trouble.
Look, they put down food as bait.
Moome and Papa must be worn out.
Well, I'll take the food anyway.
Carefully, does it?
Don't want to wake up the guard.
This is great.
I've managed to play a really good trick on the stupid moments,
and they've given me a slap-up meal as well.
The monster's here.
Shut the gate.
There's the rope.
Quickly!
No, the house!
Wake up everybody to ours!
No, it's only me!
Make room, I'll get it!
Oh, where is it?
There's no monster only me!
Please, it's me, it's me Stinky!
Stinky?
Well, it sounds like Stinky.
Be careful everybody, it's a baby monster.
Another monster, please help me!
I made the footprints!
You did?
He's obviously lying.
He's too small.
Watch him or he'll go get his daddy.
No, please, I beg you!
Ah, Moome and Papa?
Oh, hello, Snuffkin.
Why don't you let Stinky go?
It really is him, you know.
It is?
Yes, it was Stinky, and he really did make those footprints.
How do you know that Snuffkin?
I was fishing off the shore last night when I saw him digging the holes.
The little rascal was at it for hours and hours.
The
Why don't you come inside Stinky?
This is great.
It was very good of you to make the footprints.
Papa hasn't had so much fun at ages.
I'm glad it was hard work and I lost all my hair too.
Well, mischief isn't always easy, you know.
You can say that again!
This is delicious!
Papa, are you all right?
Yes, thank you, Moome.
Mama.
Yes, dear?
Shh, I've got something important to tell you.
What is it, Papa?
A secret in my mind is made up.
Of course, dear.
I'm going to run away on an adventure trip.
That's nice for you.
It's a trip without a destination full of mystery,
hazards and hardships, and you're coming to, Mama.
Oh, splendid.
Shall we take all the children or just Moome?
No, no children.
That would be the same as here, only somewhere else.
We'll run away.
Run away, Moome and Papa?
I'll be an adventurer again, just as I was in my last youth.
And with you by my side, we'll have adventure, romance.
All we desire, the sun, the stars.
But what about Moonman? He'll be frantic.
Whoa, then it's time he learned to stand on his own feet.
Fan for himself. Become a man.
We can't protect him forever, you know.
He's big enough to be left by himself.
I'm on, Mama.
Oh, just a moment, Papa.
Oh, you can't take anything more with us.
No, I know, but I forgot to write down where the sugar is.
If they can't find it, they'll just have to do without.
But then they won't be able to make cakes and the tea will taste awful.
Oh, and they'll never find this cinnamon on them. Where shall I leave it?
Goodness, Mama, cinnamon, I ask you when the unknown is calling to us.
I should have gone on my own, indeed, I should.
But then what good is an adventure when you can't say who?
That was a close shave to someone afterwards.
Is there anything wrong, Papa?
No, everything is fine, but we must leave before dawn.
All right.
We have a long way to go.
How far and where? It's very dark, you know.
Yes, isn't it? We'll just follow our feet and they say this way.
Oh, God.
Good morning, Mama.
Mama, where are you?
What's the matter, Moomin?
My parents are missing.
Are you sure? Of course, I'm sure.
That's a bit of a problem. I'm getting hungry.
I need my breakfast. I have to start the day with a good meal.
I'm starving. Me too.
Don't worry, Moomin. I'm sure that Moomin, Mama and Moomin, Papa will be back home very soon.
But where could they have gone to, Snuffkin?
No idea. Have they left a note?
Have you had your breakfast yet, Moomin?
No, nothing. It's not the shame without Mama.
Cheer up, Moomin.
You can have this fish.
And I'll come up to Moomin house and cook it especially for you, if you like.
Thanks, Snuffkin. But there are two cooks there already.
Little Mayan's sniff, a bull trying to cook.
A bit of fish, a bit of fat.
This is great. There's lots of delicious things I want to try out.
Where are we, Papa?
No idea, Mama. Too dark to see anything at all.
We've been gone for hours. I think it should have been light by now.
Oh, dear, we have to face it. I'm afraid we're lost. I'm sorry, Mama, but there it is.
What do you mean?
Well, in the dark, we must have wandered into some caves.
Who knows how many different tunnels we took. It could be weeks before we find our way.
Little Mayan's burning.
Mind your own business. I might like burnt food. It's very nutritious. Watch your own cooking.
It couldn't be any worse than the last lot you made for us.
Ha! I wonder where Moomin is. He likes my food. I'll get him to try it.
He can try mine first. Now that I practice, it'll be perfect.
Moomin, I've got something for you.
Mama!
Papa!
What was that?
Moomin, Papa! Wake up!
Moomin, Papa!
Ooh!
It tastes brackish. We must be quite near the sea.
That's a big one.
Gotcha.
Moomin, Moomin, where are you so far from home?
Mama, at last. Look, I've got a big fish. Come and help me quickly.
Don't let it get away.
I've never seen such a big fish movement.
Just wait till Papa sees it.
Oh, yes. Moomin, Papa. This looks familiar. It's Moomin Valley, isn't it?
Of course it is, just outside the cave.
Oh dear. I'm afraid that your father will be a bit disappointed.
Where is he then?
Well, he's gone, looking for adventure.
Adventure? Where?
I don't really know. Somewhere.
I could have gone with him.
When's he coming home?
I'm afraid I don't know that either.
You know Papa tonight, tomorrow night.
Next Christmas?
Your guess is as good as mine, Moomin.
Wow. I bet he's having a great adventure right now.
Hey, Mama.
Oh, oh.
Oh, you...
Mama?
Hello, where are you?
Oh, the cave dwellers must have her.
Oh, Mama.
Mama.
Mama, oh.
Can you hear me?
Oh.
Goodness, the sea.
Oh, this looks like...
Oh, it gets...
Oh, dear.
Terry, me, I don't...
Oh, well, oh, my...
Oh, you see?
It might have been...
Oh, yeah, of course.
Oh, look, look, it's Papa.
Papa's back, everyone.
Uh-huh.
Hi, Papa.
Oh, well, I'm back.
So pleased to see you again.
Thank you, Mama.
Papa, how was your adventure?
Unexpected, yes, that's what I'd say.
Unexpected, any food.
Oh, yes, you can try mine.
First, Moomin, Papa.
Oh, mine's the best.
Try mine, Papa.
Oh, that's good.
I'm starving.
Tell us about your adventure.
I love you.
Were you an mortal danger?
Did you eat any rams?
Yeah, I am supposed to.
I think Papa wants to talk about his adventure yet.
Maybe later.
And that was the end of Mama and Papa's adventure.
They didn't get far, but then you don't have to sometimes
for things to happen.
Or at least for you to think they're happening.
They love the laughter,
and they love the living, the romance.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.
They love the laughter,
and they love the living, the movements.
Believe in sharing and caring and giving the movements.
They're always happy and always at play.
The movements are having fun day after day.
The movements.