here they are for one and all the movements are about to come on and sit down here with
me here for you on your TV they are the movements they are the movements so come with me give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just like a bird sing that song ever there were the movements
there were the movements there were the movements there were the movements
the seeds that movement and his friends had found in a box that had been cast up on the beach
had grown into a tropical forest it was beautiful but also dangerous with man-eating plants kept a bay by snuffkin playing as harmonica but for how long
oh dear snuffkin don't stop playing your harmonica whatever you do they'll only get angry and attack us all over again
if I don't stop soon I might never want to play again
well perhaps the music has made them more friendly be careful mr. himmelon oh don't worry
mr. himmelon look out
I don't think the quickly snuffkin play again
oh
papa we must make sure the trap door won't open again
oh yes what's this about a trap door in the kitchen they almost got him before in the tag mama we reached her just in time
oh
I feel sorry for them it can't be helped snuffkin if we let them out will be eaten alive
it makes me feel very uncomfortable having man-eating plants under the floor
always keep a kettle of boiling water handy in case they break through
the children are playing Tarzan they might as well seeing as they've got a jungle to play in
still planting those seeds might have been a terrible mistake
well mama I'm very glad that you did just think what I would have missed and movement valley suddenly being full of tropical plants
is wonderful I'm not fond of traveling as you know and you've brought the plants to me
the trees make it much cooler but those man-eaters who I could do without them
you're just like Tarzan Tarzan loves James
oh what bliss
stinky's over there stinky Tarzan teach old baddie lesson
oh
pretty stupid moment playing Tarzan without wild animals
animals don't come from seeds no but you need them to have a real jungle I can get you some if you want
really I'll do anything for my friends that's very kind of you not too wild though no lions or tigers or anything
maybe it maybe chimpanzee I know exactly what you need
cheese bread
what are you doing mama well I don't like the thought of all those man-eaters still in the
cellar so your father and I are going to sleep in the bathhouse
we'll sleep outdoors too we've just built ourselves a hut
snorkemaiden and little Mai too well yes there's plenty of room
all right so that only leaves Mr. Himmelon sleeping in the house
and he still busy checking all the different plants
mama is everything ready oh yes dear
oh I'm already yes we are Mr. Himmelon see you later
stinky said he could get some wild animals papa
where ever from I don't know I wouldn't trust him he'll probably put a head jog in your sleeping bag
there it is the hut oh very well built
oh
I tell you it's a wonderful place you love it a real tropical jungle are you sure it's quite nice here
of course there you are oh
how lovely it is to run free
darling let's be the first to get to Moomin Valley
soon I'll have the largest collection in the botanic world and I will be famous and people will come from all over
now what have we here go away I'm not a zoologist
look Moomin those must be the monkey stinky promise
well that's a surprise not like him at all I just don't trust him what sweet things
just like in Tarzan what was that I don't know
that sounds like some really wild animal a lion or a tiger I'm frightened Moomin
very odd just like home isn't it even if it isn't very big perhaps we could live here
let's go hunting first ice mill humans oh be careful darling you're very out of practice
I must warn them oh see anything not a thing people should have been imagination
Moomin keep quiet little more I've just seen some tigers they're coming to get you tigers
let's get back to the house quick there's no time they're nearly here we'll go to the bathhouse
shall we eat him up you know that Hamilins upset your tummy dear rest I wonder where the movements are
just more animals that's all
what's the matter Moomin little Maya seen two tigers and they're looking for
tigers after us that rotten stinky probably told him we're good to eat or something maybe we are they'll be here
in a minute right Moomin you go and find the biggest stone you can and bring it back with you
okay
this way
up
a little less one yes that's perfect right get into the bathhouse and it quickly now
here they come
are you really going to eat them dearest of course my love you see I think they're hiding in that little house
up there they being very quiet if they are they're just too scared to move that's all
why's that stone there
oh
my darling it worth Papa well of course Moomin
my husband is drowning oh I'm so sorry Papa we must help he was just about to try
to eat his mama I'm sure he won't do it again I suppose so Moomin
I love I never thought I'd see the day Moomin's rescuing a tiger
here you are dear tie this tightly around him and we'll lift him out thank you
Mama
hmm oh darling are you all right my love what happened did we eat them no you were
drowning and they rescued you who now embarrassing well they're in that cabin behind you
if you still feel hungry but it was rather good of them to save you no my appetite's
completely gone welcome back here then and we'll go I'll just jump over
oh what's the matter I can't remember how to jump we've been stuck in that zoo for too long
we'll try and swim across dearest okay hmm
we got everyone the tigers are leaving I'm glad you didn't grow I knew they wouldn't be
mean enough to eat us after saving you shall we jump in and swim back as well it's not far
oh yes I'll go first I want to go first done little mine be careful Moomin look over there
crocodiles oh hurry up Moomin swim around the back and come up the ladder
how can there be crocodiles in the sea I thought they only lived in fresh water how are we
going to get back to the shore now we'll have to wait for a boat to come past no I'm afraid we'll
have to think of something else Mama we could be waiting for a week or so for that to happen
a whole week but we'll starve all they'll find is our bones bleached white in the sun don't worry
little my papa will think of something you'll see good morning
snuff again what are we leave I was going to go sea fishing but I changed my mind I didn't fancy
landing a sea monster help someone help help anybody that's mr. hemielin oh the tigers must be
after him quickly
I never made you so cross I just told you not to eat my plants
and please someone anyone help let me in
that fella's always been clumsy we can't really help him no
oh you're all right him you're all dear I think so what about him what do you do when a rhino
gets stuck in your brand oh this is a new one on me so I'm loose I can't think of any other way
you have to be very careful though I think you're right
I think you think you think you think yeah look where you're going it was you who brought all the
animals in wasn't it yes you're right that's what you wanted it's a jungle now I did a good
job oh really well they're not wild animals at all they're quite friendly friendly
hmm
see what I mean they make very good pets cute aren't they
ah snake I'll stick where are you
why do you want the rhino and the tigers have become pets of the movement family you're not
gonna let that happen to you well are you it's not I'll bring snorkemaiden and movement here
tonight there's no need to eat all of them just bite off their tails all right okay
you'll be really amazed like I was it's big enough for both of you to sit on how lovely a giant
water lily I wonder if the seeds came from that box you all found oh I can't wait to see it
looking at the size of the jungle there must have been an awful lot of seeds in that box I suppose
the wind could have blown them anywhere where's the giant water lily let's see now
over there how wonderful you see I wish you learned to trust me I'm a very honest guy
it's so soft and pink and beautiful how romantic to be on a boat made from a flower this is
unbelievable our old box seems to have grown into a tropical swamp it's a lot nicer hey stinky stinky
oh I can't see him anywhere I wonder how far we'll float it's getting dark moment
oh
got you we must get away I don't know yet look there's the sea but the crooked
miles over there's not made of a boat well it's the only way we'll get away from this monster
oh
keep going snorkemaid we're almost there wait
moment and snorkemaid kept swimming as fast as they could they had a head start on the snake but
now he was catching up even though movements are very good swimmers unfortunately for them so are snakes
they're always happy and always at play the movements are having fun day after day the
movements the movements they love the laughter and they love the living the movements
we're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements they're always happy and goes at play the
movements are having fun day after day the movements the movements