here they are for one and all the moments are about to come on and sit down here with
me there for you on your TV they are the moments they are the moments so come with me give me your hand
I'll take you up to a moment land you can fly just like a bird sing that song ever there with the
moment there was a moments there was the moments there was the moments
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la
la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la. It's spring again in
Mumen Valley and after their long winter hibernation, everyone is awake and enjoying the sunshine
in the flowers.
Everyone that is except for mumen was in bed with a terrible cold.
Oh dear mumen, that's a nasty cough.
My throat is very sore.
This will help soothe it.
It's one of grandma's best potions.
It's hard.
Never mind, nice tasting medicines don't always work as well.
I wanted to go out, it's spring.
I know dear, but you'd catch pneumonia or something.
Oh mama, does anyone know why snuff can't come back here?
No, perhaps spring came earlier this year and he wasn't ready.
Snuff can not always come back to mumen valley on the very first day of spring,
but not this year.
Snuff kill.
I'm mumen papa, is mumen any better?
No, I'm afraid not, he's still got a nasty cough.
Can I go up and see him?
No, you'd better not, you might catch it.
Papa's right, sniff, and you know how poorly you get when you're ill.
It's best not to take the risk.
I should think he'll be up and about before very long.
Yes, it's better to be safe than sorry.
Woman shouldn't have gone out in the winter, should he mama?
No, but he couldn't go back to sleep.
Snow would have that effect on anyone.
Not you, little Mai was out in the cold with him and look at her, she seems healthy enough.
I'll take these flowers to mumen later.
Little Mai's too small to catch a cold.
This is boring.
I can't believe that mumen's sick.
And Snuff gets not back either.
I sure wonder what's happened to him.
I bet you mumen gets better as soon as Snuff can arrive in mumen valley.
He's never been this late coming back before.
Perhaps he's got fed up with you guys.
Impossible, he's very fond of me.
He's told me so lots of times.
He likes mumen too, of course.
He might have been captured by a highway man.
Let's go and look for him.
The highway man?
First Snuff can silly.
He's got to come back so mumen will get better.
We must find him.
But where do we look Snork Maiden?
In the south.
It's a big place.
He could be anywhere.
Well, I don't care how big it is.
I'm going anyway.
You're being silly.
No, I'm not.
I don't think your brother will like it.
In fact, I know he won't.
Have you gone completely bananas?
No, I haven't.
And you'll just have to make your own muffins.
There's more to food than muffins.
I was speaking figuratively.
Anyway, I'm going to your brother
and nothing you can do or say will stop me.
It's for mumen.
That's a sort of hairbrain scheme
that could only have been dreamed up by you.
What good will it do?
You don't even know where he is.
It is not.
Mumen is pining for Snuffkin.
Rubbish.
Men don't pine for their friends.
If he isn't back yet, then he isn't coming.
And if he isn't going to come,
what's the point of looking for him?
You won't find him anyway.
He will come when he knows that Mumen is sick.
Black males just like a sister.
Something done for love could never be black male.
Oh no, you're not going and that's fine.
Look, why don't you and little Mai go by yourselves?
Oh, well, I didn't really make a definite decision.
I just sort of said that I might come along
that if Snort Maiden isn't going,
there doesn't seem any point.
Does there?
And I'm not going because I think it's stupid and hairbrain too.
Snuffkin will come back soon.
Not Snort Maiden.
What do you say to that?
How is Mumen feeling any better?
He's asleep now, but the cough doesn't seem so bad.
And is temperature still quite high?
Already.
Snort Maiden Moan.
Snort Maiden.
And my pleas to see you, Moomin.
You look like you needed a lift.
This magic cloud must be one of those we got from the Hobgoblins top hat.
That's right. I hid one of them away.
What a good idea, Moomin. You are clever.
Well, it was so much fun to last time, wasn't it?
Hi, Moomin! Hi! Hi!
Oh, look, Snuffkin. I didn't know they were here, too.
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
Snuffkin!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Moomin!
Snuffkin!
Oh, oh!
Oh! Oh!
Moomin!
Snuffkin!
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
That was just a dream.
Snuffkin!
Oh!
You look blousy, Moomin.
Oh, thanks, stinky. You'd better keep away.
There's no need bugs and things like that. Stay away from me.
They're probably frightened of someone so healthy.
Mama isn't letting anyone in here. It's very dull.
You followed a bed or something? Yes, I did.
I know. You were dreaming, weren't you?
Unfortunately, yes.
I know how you feel.
I have that dream a lot.
Oh.
You stand on a windowsill getting ready to break the glass
and inside there's diamonds.
And then, Moomin, you fall.
It's not the same dream at all, stinky.
Snuffkin hasn't come back yet.
Have you heard anything from him? He's very late.
Ah, Snuffkin.
You know something, don't you?
All I know is that he went away as usual last autumn
and hasn't come back yet.
And then...
Yes, what?
Snork Maiden wanted to go looking for him
because he thinks that if Snuffkin comes back,
he won't be sick anymore, but snork with a letter.
Snork Maiden?
Hey, Snork Maiden!
Snork Maiden!
You're not serious, are you?
I feel perfectly all right.
You look like that's warmed up if you ask me.
Thanks a lot.
Now, stinky, tell me which way does Snuffkin normally travel south?
Hey, are you going looking for him?
Yes, it's not really spring in Moomin Valley if he's not around.
It's just not right somehow.
Okay, you're all as mad as each other.
But you'll help me?
I've got to try and find him, stinky.
Yes, all right, but don't tell your parents I helped you.
Don't worry, I want to say a thing.
Sorry, stinky. Are you okay?
No, I'm fine.
Here's your lunch, Moomin. How are you feeling?
Moomin?
Papa, come here quickly.
Mmm.
Oh, Papa, Moomin's gone. He's not in his bed.
Not in his bed? Are you sure, Mama?
Of course I am. His room is empty and there's no sign of him.
Perhaps he's in one of the other rooms.
Don't worry, Mama, I'll find him.
Yo, Moomin.
Moomin.
Hi, Moomin, Papa.
Oh, little Mai.
What's wrong? You look worried.
A moment's gone up somewhere.
I expect you must have gone to look for Snuffkin.
Snuffkin?
Well, you know how crazy Moomin is about him.
Bit stupid if you ask me.
But he's not well, he's got a fever.
You're sure this is the right way?
Of course I'm sure.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Bye.
Are you sure this is the right way?
Of course I'm sure. I live in this forest, don't I?
Why don't we miss each other somewhere?
Well, if you think you might, don't go then. It's up to you.
But I've got to...
H-h-h-h-h-h-h!
Mumin!
Oh, snorke me, son!
Uh-huh.
Where are you taking him, Stinky? You can see he's not well.
I'm not taking him. He insisted on going. I came to look after him.
Is that really right, Mumin?
Yes, I wanted to find snuffkins, so he'd come back.
Well, I was going to find him for you. Little mind's sniff were coming too,
but they chickened out, so I came on my own.
What did Snorke say about that?
I bet he wasn't happy.
Oh, he made a big fuss, and I just let him.
So you just walked out and came on your own?
Brothers, always think they can tell you what to do.
Well, I just ignored him. Did you tell your parents where you were?
Ah, no.
Did you put him up to this stinky? It's just a sort of thing you do.
No, I did not.
That's true, Snark Maiden.
Well, I don't know how you did it stinky, but I know you,
and I know you're to blame, and I don't think I won't find out.
That's not fair, Snark Maiden. It was nothing to do with me at all.
Oh, you're right, Snark Maiden.
He didn't want to show me the way, but I made him.
I'm taking you home.
Oh, but Snark Maiden, look.
No, buts, you're sick, and you should be in bed,
and your parents must be very worried.
Ah, look.
Moomin!
Oh, it's Papa. It isn't that Snark behind him.
Oh, yes, it is.
Oh, oh, it's time I wasn't here.
I'm glad you hadn't gone too far, Moomin.
I might never have found you.
I'm very sorry, Papa.
Ah!
I have a feeling you're behind this stinky.
Come on quickly, I'll win it.
Why doesn't anyone believe me?
It was Moomin's idea. I swear it was.
It was, Papa. I wanted to find Snark Maiden.
Are you all right, Moomin?
Snark Maiden!
Ah, here we go again.
Snark Maiden, what are you doing here?
I thought I told you not to go on this silly jump.
Well, I didn't say I wouldn't. Did I?
Listen to me, Snark.
Ah, you're looking guilty, stinky.
How did you persuade her to disobey me?
See, I told you.
You stay nice and warm in bed, and I'll mix them
of grandma's potion with honey for you.
You'll have to be better soon,
because I have a feeling snuffkins on his way.
My wish snuffkin would hurry up,
then we could all get back to normal at last.
My sentiment's exactly.
So where is Snuffkin?
Well, he's on his way back to Moomin Valley.
But he's had a very long walk,
and is getting very tired now.
Poor Snuffkin, he's had a terrible cold as well,
and is feeling rather weak.
Hello, I know you don't I?
Oh?
Yes, you're snuffkin.
Oh!
Isn't that water still a little cold for that?
You'd better come by the fire and keep warm,
or you'll catch cold.
This is nice!
Just think, I'll be the one that's set by Snuffkin's fire,
and he told me to keep warm and not catch cold.
Hmm, that's no big thing, little fella.
It's a pretty chilly night out here.
Oh, it is!
I've heard so many stories about you from everybody,
and each year I try to watch as you go past,
but I've never been brave enough to talk to you before.
Stories from everybody.
I don't know if I like that.
In fact, I'm sure I don't.
What's your name, little fella?
Oh, well, I haven't got one.
I'm so small that nobody's ever asked me before.
I've always wanted to have a name, you know?
And it was you who asked me,
and I've actually met you and sat next to it.
You're countifying!
Oh, it's so wonderful!
You don't know how happy it makes me meeting you like this!
Aw, come on, you do go on a bit old, fella.
You just get warm now.
Do you think, Snuffkin?
Oh, I don't know whether I should ask you.
I don't want to offend you.
Oh, well, why not?
Yes, I will.
Perhaps you'd be kind enough to it.
I mean, would it be too much trouble for you
to think of a name for me?
There.
I've said it now.
Well, choosing a name is important.
I'd have to think carefully about that.
But it will be easy for you.
Now, everything!
Now, listen to me.
You can't look up to people too much if you want to be yourself.
It's not right.
But Snuffkin, you're so clever.
You can do anything, anything at all.
I know you can.
I've always wanted to be free like you to do whatever I feel.
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm talking too much.
I want to listen to you too.
All about your travels for a start.
I know you're on your way to the Moon Valley to see all your friends.
The hedgehog told me the Moon stayed out for most of the winter.
Just waiting for you to come back.
Now, isn't that wonderful?
What?
I'd love to have someone that missed me so much
they were miserable until I came back.
You don't know how lucky you are that you're so special.
Well, perhaps I'm not going there.
I might have somewhere else to visit instead.
Oh, moment, I'll be very sad if you don't go back.
Yes, but you've got to have time to be on your own as well.
Of course you have, and I've taken up too much of yours now.
Wait, I think I'll be off.
Okay, thanks.
Goodbye, Snuffkin.
Good night, little fella.
Hey, wait a minute.
What about your name?
You remembered.
Well, what do you think of TD Wu, my friend?
Yes, TD Wu.
It's nice and happy to start with, and then a little sadness.
TD Wu.
дом?
T-T Wu.
T-T Wu, T-T Wu.
Oh, that's great! It's a wonderful name, Titi Woo!
Titi Woo, I'm glad you like it. It's the first time I've ever given anyone a name.
Yeah! I think I'll be able to house and then I can put up a real name plate that says Titi Woo!
Ah, good idea, Titi Woo. About what I said before.
Huh?
You know, not going back to Moomin Valley? Well, I am. I've missed Moomin and all my friends.
Oh, I didn't take that seriously. You just got upset at something I said. I'm afraid that happens a lot. I guess I talked too much.
Maybe you do.
Oh, I'll be going back to Moomin Valley a bit behind schedule. And this year's spring came along early too.
But I suppose it's better late than never, as they say.
Moomin will be happy. Say hello to everyone from Titi Woo!
I will. And I'll tell them how it came about.
That's where you keep your harmonica, isn't it, Snuffkin? It's really famous, you know?
I didn't realize that.
Do you know? I've never ever heard any music.
Really? What would you like me to play?
Anything. Oh, I know. What about Moomin's favorite?
Oh, that's Snuffkin!
Oh, God!
Don't move!
Snuffkin!
Now at last, spring really has come to Moomin Valley.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the Moomin's.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moomin's.
They're always happy and always at play.
The Moomin's are having fun day after day, the Moomin's.
They love the laughter and they love the living, the Moomin's.
Believing in sharing and caring and giving the Moomin's.
They're always happy and always at play.
The Moomin's are having fun day after day, the Moomin's.
The Moomin's.