Here they are for one and all, the movements are about to come, come on and sit down here with me.
Here for you are your TV, they are the movements, they are the movements.
So come with me, give me your hand, I'll take you up to a moment land.
You can fly just like a bird, sing the best song ever, there were the movements, there were the movements,
there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements, there were the movements.
The snow was getting thicker on the ground and it was high time for the movements to start hibernating.
What are you doing now man, Alicia? What are you doing with these pine needles? That's what we always eat before we hibernate nobody knows why.
So you're going to start hibernating? Yes tonight. Oh that's soon? Yes.
I'm so glad I've come to see you today instead of leaving until tomorrow then.
I must say you came on just the right day, Alicia. We usually have a small party the night we start hibernating and you've arrived just in time.
Oh you mean I can stay for that woman, Mama?
And by the way Alicia is a matter of interest, is the witch, sorry your grandmother I mean, know that you're here?
No I'm afraid I didn't tell her, better for grownups not to know too much.
Oh do you say you're right?
I'm afraid she's not very happy for me to come here to move in valley.
Why ever not my dear?
I guess she's afraid that if I start coming here to play I shall lose interest in studying hard at my witchcraft.
Oh but you've got a very long time to go before you're a witch?
It takes anything between five to seven years nowadays.
Are you really sure that's what you want to be Alicia?
Study something out. But I want to be a witch.
Perhaps you don't know but witches aren't terribly popular.
Yes I do but I won't be like that, I'll be popular.
Hey, stop here.
You're off to the moments?
Yes.
I thought you'd gone south already, last winter you'd gone before the snow started.
Not this year I promised Moomin.
Promise?
I promised not to leave Moomin Valley until he went into hibernation.
Everybody seems to be here and somebody knew.
Who's that?
Have a guess.
Very well then, it's Alicia that's my guess.
How did you know?
What? I'm right?
Yes you are but I think you peaked and saw her earlier on.
I did it. I just named somebody I thought couldn't be here.
Clever huh?
Well she just happened to stop by. She's with Papa who's showing her around the house.
Is the witch here too?
No she didn't tell the witch she was coming here.
Just as well thank goodness.
Ah it's you snuffkin. I finally came over. I told you I would.
Hi.
Remember our friend here? He's called Sniff.
Hi, how do you do Sniff?
Well you aren't going to use your magic to cast any spells and stuff are you?
No.
Actually they didn't eat just pine needles for dinner that evening.
They had lots of other nice things too. All cooked by Moomin Mama.
Snuffkin I'd like to say how story I am.
Why?
I persuaded you to stay on here instead of going south as you'd planned.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
But the snow is quite deep.
Don't worry I'm used to deep snow.
I'm just worried Alicia will find it hard to get home in this.
Well she could spell the night here but of course tomorrow will be asleep for the winter so...
Huh?
Hmm? Someones is a door.
I'll see who it is.
Oh hello. How are you?
Hello indeed my young man. My granddaughter is here isn't she?
Who is it then Moomin?
Oh my dear.
You must be Moomin Papa.
Now you listen to me Moomin Papa.
I don't want my granddaughter playing with your children under any circumstances.
Do I make myself quite clear?
But Alicia likes playing with us.
Grandma!
We're leaving. Can't I stand a little longer?
Hello you're most welcome to stay and have dinner with us.
Don't you know I'm a witch? I can't eat that sort of baby food.
Alicia quite likes the food.
The pine needles look okay. The rest is yucky. Come Alicia.
Please let me stay grandma.
Not young lady. I've told you before which is never mixed with people like this.
And that goes for novice which is as well.
Never.
With their knives they're really all grandma.
And I told you that's the trouble.
They are disgustingly sicknessly good.
You will hear a lot more about this when we get home.
Come on now.
It's really cold out here and there's a lot more snow on the way.
All right I'm coming grandma.
Coming.
Oh thank you.
Mum and Papa.
Yeah?
We understand each other now don't we?
I'm sure you understand me.
Never mind about that.
You and your whole family are never to speak to my granddaughter again.
Is that understood?
But grandma.
Mind what I say over a vengeance of touch will come upon you.
Or even the revenge of a serious.
If you think cheap threats like that impress Mum and Papa.
You're making a grave mistake.
And Papa is a highly educated gentleman.
But I am a witch with three diplomas.
Maybe so.
But tell me how can three diplomas help you to get home with all this snow.
Ha! Child's play to an accredited witch.
Come, Alicia.
I've ever seen one of these before, a little pep square.
Is that really a witch's broom?
Well, never.
Let's go and see.
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
I'm ready.
Hold on, Ditalisia.
Okay.
Can you both ride on that broom?
It looks pretty scrappy to me.
Could fall to pieces any minute.
Do drive slowly in this weather.
Oh, please don't fall off, Alicia.
But terrible chatterboxes you all are.
Please keep quiet out of you.
Are you ready, girl?
Yeah?
Bet they'll never be able to take off.
Huh?
Oh...
What is it, Grandma?
Nothing.
Oh!
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just what I thought, they're too heavy.
Listen, I could take Alicia's place, I'm not too heavy.
Don't worry, I'm happy to walk home, Grandma.
Don't be so ridiculous, child.
You can't walk home in all this snow.
You'll never make it.
Only I had some skis.
Come on, climb aboard.
I'll try another spell.
Grandma, are you worried because all those people are watching you?
Shut up!
I help you say the magic spell.
Oh!
They're doing it!
What?
Oh!
Where'd we go?
She may have three diplomas, but I don't think she's very good, Mom.
I wish they'd sing to the ground so I could fly that broom.
Guess they're all right now, Mum and Papa.
Let's go back to our dinner.
Oh!
I forgot to thank them for asking me to stand at dinner!
Thank them indeed!
I don't think you're cut out to be a witch!
Oh, but Grandma, I don't want to be one!
Well, I'm quite happy to help, but the path will certainly be a difficult one.
Oh!
With Alessia and the witch gone home to the Valley of the Witches, Snuffkin departed for his trip south, and the Moomins went into hibernation.
They certainly would have slept till the beginning of the spring as usual, but this year.
Quite unexpectedly, something happened.
Oh!
Spring here already?
There's someone at the window!
Oh!
It's frozen shut!
Hey!
Why did you wake me up?
Well, you shouldn't be asleep!
Didn't you know Christmas is coming?
It's tomorrow, so there's not a minute to be lost!
Christmas is coming tomorrow?
But who on earth is that?
Why?
Who is Christmas?
This isn't a joke moment!
I'm not in the least ready!
I've lost my mittens and Christmas is coming and I haven't got a fertry yet!
A fertry, I really must get a fertry!
How very odd!
Why a fertry?
Hey!
Why?
Oh, what's that, Moomins?
Well, Christmas is almost coming and we don't have a fertry yet!
Christmas?
Hmm.
Did you say Christmas is coming?
Yes, and before that, one must have a fertry!
What's this about a fertry?
Well, you need one to protect ourselves against this Christmas person, Moomins Mama.
I am not really quite clear on that point.
But there's something awful that has to be kept away, right?
I better go get a fertry!
Ha!
About time you Moomins got up?
How are you going to see?
Pretty good fertry, Dad!
Well, thank you, Gavsie, but could you tell me something?
What is one supposed to do with it?
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Oh, really, Moomins Papa!
The way you can joke with such a straight face!
Joke?
Eh?
Love to stay, but I haven't even finished cooking yet!
I wasn't joking.
No one believed me either!
Would you like a little more, young man?
No, thank you very much. I'm really nice and warm again now.
I saw Moomins Papa and Moomins bring up a big tree!
But what is one supposed to do with it?
Don't you know?
No!
Why are you decorated as beautifully as you can?
Really?
Christmas is coming, so I better be off!
Everyone's talking of Christmas!
By now, I've got a long way to go!
Take care, dear!
Hello!
Bye-bye!
Good-bye!
Who was that?
I don't know!
He was in a hurry to get somewhere before Christmas!
So I gave him some tea!
That was nice!
And he told us what to do with the fir tree!
What did he say?
To decorate it beautifully!
Decorate it, but why should we do that, Mama?
I guess we must decorate the tree to make sure we keep Christmas happy!
Yes, you're right!
We'd better start doing it right away!
Yes, I'm sure there's another moment to lose!
No!
Mama!
Yes, dear!
They also say we have to cook lots of food for Christmas!
Goodness!
Well, at least he won't be eating us then!
Here!
Thank you, Snorkmaid!
Oh!
The ship means rather a lot to me!
It will look fantastic on the tree, Papa!
Yes, dear, I suppose you're right!
Oh!
Why don't we put this at the top?
This is Mama's!
Don't worry!
Mmm, that looks beautiful!
Listen, everybody!
I just heard that you need to get lots of presents for Christmas, too!
Really, Mama?
Yes, I do!
I just heard that you need to get lots of presents for Christmas, too!
Really, Mama?
I don't wonder what this Christmas will be like!
What if it's an awful greedy, beastly monster like the grove?
Don't worry, Snorkmaid!
We'll give him lots of presents and stuff him full of food!
Have you thought of any presents for Christmas yet?
I don't know what to give him!
Look, a seashell!
Oh, that's a beauty!
Oh, look, Mama, what I got for Christmas!
I'm going to give him a pretty lure for fishing!
I'm giving him this book!
Great presents!
I'm sure he'll be very happy with the moment family and not Thomas at all!
I think Christmas will come any moment now!
So do I!
Oh, dear!
I do hope he likes my pumpkin pie!
He will!
Imagine everyone in Moomin Valley being frightened!
Mmm!
Are you sleepy?
Yes, I am!
I can't stay this scared for much longer!
Better come before all the food freezes!
Oh!
He's coming!
I never thought Christmas could be that small!
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas! Is that what he is?
Well, it's just what you say!
All of my life I have dreamed of seeing all this up close, honestly!
I never really thought a Christmas tree could be this beautiful!
Brought my friends, too!
You're all very welcome!
Oh, thank you!
Hear that, everybody?
We're all very welcome!
Woo!
Man, let's get him!
There's some wonderful things here!
Yeah!
Oh, what a lot of food you've made!
Yes, all the food there is for Christmas!
And are those real presents?
Yeah!
All of my life, I've sort of wondered about those things called presents!
Papa, I don't think these creatures are Christmas!
Neither do I!
You look sleepy!
I am!
Must be well past midnight!
What is Christmas doing, Mama?
Aren't you sleepy, too, little ones?
Sleepy with a wonderful Christmas tree like this to look at!
Hey, Papa!
What is it?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Hmm, maybe.
Nobody can get really angry this late at night, surely!
We'll close the doors and perhaps we'll be safe inside!
I'm sure you're right!
Listen, my friends, we'd like to give you the tree and the food and the presents!
What?
All of this?
For us?
Yes, we want to sleep!
We're far more sleepy than scared!
Snort, Ma'am?
Oh, I see here yet!
No, but we decided to go back to hibernating!
Bye-bye!
I thought Christmas tree should have a star on top!
I don't think it makes any difference, you know?
A nice rose is just as good as a star!
Look at that!
And apparently it didn't make any difference at all!
Because the moon and family slept as peacefully as ever!
All through the night, without Christmas!
Coming!
Anywhere!
Hi!
And apparently it didn't make any difference at all!
Because the moon and family slept as peacefully as ever!
All through the night, without Christmas!
Coming anywhere near them!
So probably, he went someplace else!
They love the laughter and they love the living, the movements!
You're leaving and sharing and caring and giving the movements!
They're always happy and always at play!
The movements are having fun day after day!
The movements!